export const questions = {
  "LANGUAGE AND LITERATURE LEARNING MATERIALS DEVELOPMENT": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Which aspect of language learning materials is most crucial for fostering cultural awareness in students?",
      "answers": [
        "Including idiomatic expressions unique to the target culture",
        "Highlighting cultural contexts in which language is used",
        "Focusing on grammatical structures prevalent in the target language",
        "Providing extensive vocabulary lists with translations"
      ],
      "correct": "Highlighting cultural contexts in which language is used"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Which alternative reading material is most effective for promoting cultural awareness in the classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "A collection of folktales and legends from various cultures",
        "A standardized reading comprehension workbook",
        "A set of scientific journals and articles",
        "A textbook focused on historical grammar rules"
      ],
      "correct": "A collection of folktales and legends from various cultures"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Which approach to selecting reading materials best promotes critical thinking and analysis in students?",
      "answers": [
        "Using only textbooks with pre-defined reading lists and questions",
        "Assigning students to read only classic literature from a single culture",
        "Providing students with contemporary articles and essays on current social issues",
        "Focusing on literary texts that emphasize rote memorization and recitation"
      ],
      "correct": "Providing students with contemporary articles and essays on current social issues"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "How can a unit of material be evaluated for its ability to engage students?",
      "answers": [
        "By ensuring it includes only text-based explanations",
        "By emphasizing rote memorization of facts",
        "By using complex academic language",
        "By incorporating interactive and multimedia elements"
      ],
      "correct": "By incorporating interactive and multimedia elements"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "How can student involvement in materials development be integrated to enhance the relevance and engagement of educational materials?",
      "answers": [
        "By allowing students to choose topics without any guidance",
        "By providing pre-made materials without considering student interests",
        "By incorporating student feedback and preferences into the development process",
        "By focusing solely on standardized content and assessments"
      ],
      "correct": "By incorporating student feedback and preferences into the development process"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "What is the most significant advantage of using role-play activities in developing speaking skills?",
      "answers": [
        "They ensure perfect grammar usage in conversations",
        "They help students memorize scripted dialogues",
        "They provide a structured way to practice pronunciation",
        "They create realistic scenarios for practicing spontaneous speech"
      ],
      "correct": "They create realistic scenarios for practicing spontaneous speech"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "To help students develop critical thinking skills through reading, which alternative approach should a teacher take?",
      "answers": [
        "Assigning multiple-choice quizzes on the content of the texts",
        "Providing pre-written summaries of the texts before reading",
        "Asking students to write down all unfamiliar words and their meanings",
        "Encouraging students to participate in debates about the themes and arguments in the texts"
      ],
      "correct": "Encouraging students to participate in debates about the themes and arguments in the texts"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "In a multidimensional listening skills lesson, what type of activity can help students improve their ability to understand implied meaning?",
      "answers": [
        "Listening to a weather report and noting down temperatures",
        "Engaging in a role-play based on a conversation with implied subtext",
        "Watching a documentary and summarizing the key points",
        "Completing a worksheet on vocabulary words from the audio"
      ],
      "correct": "Engaging in a role-play based on a conversation with implied subtext"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which follow-up activity is most effective for developing students' ability to listen for the main idea in a multidimensional listening lesson?",
      "answers": [
        "Asking students to write down every detail they remember from the audio",
        "Conducting a dictation exercise using sentences from the audio",
        "Summarizing the audio in one or two sentences",
        "Creating a mind map of all the key terms mentioned in the audio"
      ],
      "correct": "Summarizing the audio in one or two sentences"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Teacher Pia wants to develop materials for speaking practice that align with students' daily experiences. Which activity would be most effective?",
      "answers": [
        "Reading and discussing classic literature passages",
        "Listening to news reports and summarizing them",
        "Role-playing common social interactions like ordering food at a restaurant",
        "Writing essays on current events"
      ],
      "correct": "Role-playing common social interactions like ordering food at a restaurant"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "What can be inferred as a significant advantage of using portfolio-based assessments in teaching writing?",
      "answers": [
        "Memorizing word lists and their definitions",
        "Completing a crossword puzzle with vocabulary words to apply lexical competence",
        "Participating in role-plays based on real-life scenarios using target vocabulary",
        "Matching vocabulary words with their synonyms in a worksheet, improving their testmanship"
      ],
      "correct": "Participating in role-plays based on real-life scenarios using target vocabulary"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "What role do authentic materials play in enhancing cultural awareness in language learners?",
      "answers": [
        "They provide real-world contexts that reflect the target culture's values and norms.",
        "They ensure learners achieve native-like pronunciation and behavior in real-life situations.",
        "They simplify the language to make it easier for beginners especially those with learning challenges.",
        "They focus exclusively on linguistic competence."
      ],
      "correct": "They provide real-world contexts that reflect the target culture's values and norms."
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "In the context of language learning, what is the significance of integrating sociocultural theory into instructional design?",
      "answers": [
        "It helps learners focus solely on grammatical accuracy.",
        "It encourages the use of technology in language classrooms and thereby making life at school convenient.",
        "It promotes individual learning without social interaction in preparation for real-world occupations.",
        "It emphasizes the importance of social interactions and cultural context in language acquisition."
      ],
      "correct": "It emphasizes the importance of social interactions and cultural context in language acquisition."
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which instructional approach is most suitable for fostering visual literacy in students?",
      "answers": [
        "Requiring students to memorize definitions of visual elements",
        "Conducting lectures on the history of visual media to ensure that students achieve a high level of digital literacy",
        "Engaging students in hands-on activities like analyzing visual media and creating visual projects",
        "Providing extensive reading materials on visual theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Engaging students in hands-on activities like analyzing visual media and creating visual projects"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "During a writing lesson, a teacher wants to encourage students to develop their creative writing skills using internet-based materials. Which activity would be most effective?",
      "answers": [
        "Having students write essays based on prompts from the textbook to help them structure their writing more systematically and cohesively",
        "Asking students to complete grammar exercises from an online workbook",
        "Encouraging students to participate in an online writing community where they can share and receive feedback on their work",
        "Assigning students to read academic articles and summarize them which leads to a better understanding and application of lessons learned"
      ],
      "correct": "Encouraging students to participate in an online writing community where they can share and receive feedback on their work"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "How can a teacher effectively integrate graphic novels into a reading curriculum to develop students' inferential reading skills?",
      "answers": [
        "Using graphic novels solely for leisure reading",
        "Providing students with graphic novels with random guided activities to ensure faster mastery of content",
        "Designing activities that ask students to interpret visual and textual elements in the graphic novels",
        "Focusing on the textual elements and paying no mind to the visual aspects to achieve balance of comprehension"
      ],
      "correct": "Designing activities that ask students to interpret visual and textual elements in the graphic novels"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Teacher Kat wants to create a vocabulary activity that emphasizes contextual learning. Which activity should she use?",
      "answers": [
        "Providing students with a list of vocabulary words to memorize and spell",
        "Organizing a role-play activity where students use the new vocabulary in realistic scenarios",
        "Asking students to write the vocabulary words in alphabetical order which encourages organized thinking",
        "Giving a matching exercise where students match vocabulary words to their definitions and thus stimulating happy hormones"
      ],
      "correct": "Organizing a role-play activity where students use the new vocabulary in realistic scenarios"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "Which approach best synthesizes the output hypothesis into the design of language learning materials?",
      "answers": [
        "Providing extensive listening and reading materials with speaking or writing activities constrained to a minute",
        "Focusing on receptive skills which are the basis of speaking and writing necessary for fluency",
        "Emphasizing error correction over language production",
        "Including tasks that require learners to produce language, such as speaking and writing activities"
      ],
      "correct": "Including tasks that require learners to produce language, such as speaking and writing activities"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "How can the issue of cultural relevance in materials development be addressed to create inclusive educational resources?",
      "answers": [
        "By using materials that reflect the dominant culture's perspectives and ideologies",
        "By integrating diverse cultural perspectives and examples into the materials",
        "By avoiding any cultural references to prevent controversy",
        "By focusing on academic content with limited consideration of cultural context"
      ],
      "correct": "By integrating diverse cultural perspectives and examples into the materials"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "What is the primary benefit of adapting materials using a learner-centered approach?",
      "answers": [
        "It allows teachers to cover more content in less time which addresses the burnout issue",
        "It reduces the need for ongoing assessment and feedback resulting in better quality of education",
        "It provides opportunities for students to take ownership of their learning",
        "It ensures that all students receive the same instructional content"
      ],
      "correct": "It provides opportunities for students to take ownership of their learning"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Which approach is most effective for ensuring that grammar teaching materials are relevant to learners' needs?",
      "answers": [
        "Using a standardized textbook for all learners",
        "Emphasizing formal written grammar exercises exclusively",
        "Including examples and exercises that relate to learners' everyday experiences",
        "Focusing on outdated grammatical structures no longer in common use"
      ],
      "correct": "Including examples and exercises that relate to learners' everyday experiences"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Which method is most effective for evaluating the long-term retention of vocabulary learned through input activities?",
      "answers": [
        "Immediate post-lesson quizzes on vocabulary",
        "Weekly vocabulary spelling tests",
        "Periodic assessments that require using vocabulary in various contexts",
        "Flashcard drills conducted daily"
      ],
      "correct": "Periodic assessments that require using vocabulary in various contexts"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "How can teachers use graphic novels to develop inferential reading skills in students?",
      "answers": [
        "Assigning graphic novels for independent reading without guided activities",
        "Using graphic novels to teach basic vocabulary and grammar rules",
        "Engaging students in activities that analyze both visual and textual elements to infer meaning",
        "Focusing solely on the textual narrative and ignoring the visual elements"
      ],
      "correct": "Engaging students in activities that analyze both visual and textual elements to infer meaning"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which activity is most effective for developing critical viewing skills in students?",
      "answers": [
        "Watching a popular movie and discussing its entertainment value",
        "Creating a storyboard for a short film to understand narrative techniques",
        "Viewing a music video and focusing on its artistic elements",
        "Analyzing news segments to identify bias and perspective"
      ],
      "correct": "Analyzing news segments to identify bias and perspective"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "Which method is most appropriate for evaluating the impact of teacher-centered adapted materials on student outcomes?",
      "answers": [
        "Conducting peer reviews of the adapted materials",
        "Surveying students about their enjoyment of the lessons",
        "Comparing the variety of instructional strategies used by different teachers",
        "Analyzing improvements in students' test scores and grades"
      ],
      "correct": "Analyzing improvements in students' test scores and grades"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Which of the following best illustrates the interdependence of receptive and expressive macro skills in language learning?",
      "answers": [
        "Asking students to read a textbook chapter on narrative techniques",
        "Having students watch a pre-recorded lecture on storytelling elements",
        "Providing a list of classic novels for students to read and summarize to augment cognitive processing",
        "Assigning students to create their own digital stories using multimedia tools"
      ],
      "correct": "Assigning students to create their own digital stories using multimedia tools"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "How can the principle of input hypothesis be synthesized into developing language learning materials?",
      "answers": [
        "By using only native language materials for explanations",
        "By providing comprehensible input that is slightly above the learners' current proficiency level",
        "By focusing solely on output activities without input",
        "By offering input that is too advanced and beyond learners' understanding"
      ],
      "correct": "By providing comprehensible input that is slightly above the learners' current proficiency level"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Which feature is essential for grammar teaching materials designed for beginner learners?",
      "answers": [
        "Complex sentence structures to challenge students",
        "In-depth analysis of grammatical nuances",
        "Clear explanations with plenty of simple examples",
        "Advanced exercises that require extensive grammatical knowledge"
      ],
      "correct": "Clear explanations with plenty of simple examples"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "During a listening lesson, a teacher plays an audio clip of a dialogue between two people discussing their weekend plans. Which follow-up activity is most effective for enhancing students' inferential listening skills?",
      "answers": [
        "Asking students to list all the activities mentioned in the dialogue",
        "Having students summarize the dialogue in their own words",
        "Conducting a multiple-choice quiz on specific details from the dialogue",
        "Engaging students in a discussion about the possible implications of the plans discussed"
      ],
      "correct": "Engaging students in a discussion about the possible implications of the plans discussed"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "Which element is most crucial for creating materials that promote cultural awareness through language learning?",
      "answers": [
        "Including phonetic transcriptions of local accents",
        "Providing context for cultural practices in language usage",
        "Listing common idiomatic expressions without explanations",
        "Focusing on the formal rules of grammar"
      ],
      "correct": "Providing context for cultural practices in language usage"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "How can the effectiveness of input activities for vocabulary learning be evaluated?",
      "answers": [
        "By counting the number of new words introduced in the lesson",
        "By measuring students' ability to recall isolated words in anticipation of a high-stakes exam",
        "By assessing students' ability to use new vocabulary in context during discussions",
        "By testing students on the exact definitions of new vocabulary words"
      ],
      "correct": "By assessing students' ability to use new vocabulary in context during discussions"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "How can the success of a learner-centered approach to material adaptation be best evaluated?",
      "answers": [
        "By observing the level of autonomy and self-direction demonstrated by students",
        "By measuring the students' scores on standardized tests and ranking students accordingly",
        "By assessing the teacher's ability to control the classroom",
        "By counting the number of instructional materials used by the teacher"
      ],
      "correct": "By observing the level of autonomy and self-direction demonstrated by students"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "Which approach is most effective for ensuring digital technology enhances learning in a material adaptation context?",
      "answers": [
        "Using digital tools for administrative purposes before allowing students to use them for fun",
        "Incorporating digital technology with minimal alignment with learning objectives",
        "Selecting digital tools based on the latest technological trends",
        "Integrating digital tools that align with and support curriculum goals and student needs"
      ],
      "correct": "Integrating digital tools that align with and support curriculum goals and student needs"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "How can the principle of learner engagement be applied in the evaluation of educational materials?",
      "answers": [
        "By assessing how effectively materials capture and maintain student interest and participation",
        "By ensuring materials are challenging enough so that students particularly in the upper half of the class are satisfied",
        "By measuring how well materials align with the teacher's preferences",
        "By evaluating materials based on their length and complexity"
      ],
      "correct": "By assessing how effectively materials capture and maintain student interest and participation"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "What type of evaluation is most appropriate for comparing the effectiveness of two different sets of educational materials?",
      "answers": [
        "Formative evaluation",
        "Summative evaluation",
        "Comparative evaluation",
        "Diagnostic evaluation"
      ],
      "correct": "Comparative evaluation"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "Which type of evaluation is best suited for gathering detailed feedback from students about their experiences with educational materials?",
      "answers": [
        "Summative evaluation",
        "Comparative evaluation",
        "Diagnostic evaluation",
        "Formative evaluation"
      ],
      "correct": "Formative evaluation"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "How does extensive reading of literature contribute to vocabulary development in language learners?",
      "answers": [
        "A set of instructional videos on grammar rules that include straight and squiggly lines",
        "A series of TED Talks by experts in various fields with fascinating visuals",
        "An audiobook of a classic novel",
        "A short film with abstract imagery and metaphorical content"
      ],
      "correct": "A short film with abstract imagery and metaphorical content"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "Which criterion should be prioritized when selecting materials to develop advanced speaking skills?",
      "answers": [
        "Complex and nuanced speaking tasks that require critical thinking",
        "Scripted dialogues focusing on basic vocabulary",
        "Simple conversational phrases for everyday use necessary for f luency and accuracy",
        "Worksheets on speaking etiquette"
      ],
      "correct": "Complex and nuanced speaking tasks that require critical thinking"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "A teacher wants to develop her students' vocabulary fluency through input activities. Which activity would be most effective?",
      "answers": [
        "Giving students a list of new words to memorize",
        "Using a story with rich vocabulary and context clues",
        "Asking students to write definitions of new vocabulary words",
        "Providing students with flashcards of isolated words and their meanings"
      ],
      "correct": "Using a story with rich vocabulary and context clues"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "Which output activity best encourages the use of new vocabulary in meaningful ways?",
      "answers": [
        "Copying sentences from the textbook that use the new vocabulary",
        "Engaging in a group discussion where students must use the new vocabulary words",
        "Filling in the blanks in sentences with the new vocabulary words",
        "Writing a list of synonyms for the new vocabulary words"
      ],
      "correct": "Engaging in a group discussion where students must use the new vocabulary words"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "When designing materials for cultural awareness, what is the most effective way to highlight the cultural significance of language use?",
      "answers": [
        "Emphasizing the correct use of formal and informal registers with different examples",
        "Providing historical overviews of language development",
        "Using case studies that explore language in various cultural contexts",
        "Including linguistic exercises that focus on syntax"
      ],
      "correct": "Using case studies that explore language in various cultural contexts"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "In assessing the effectiveness of cultural awareness materials, what criterion is most indicative of their success?",
      "answers": [
        "The number of vocabulary words learned as well as new collocations",
        "The accuracy of grammar exercises completed",
        "The learners' ability to navigate intercultural interactions",
        "The memorization of cultural facts and figures"
      ],
      "correct": "The learners' ability to navigate intercultural interactions"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "A teacher designs a lesson involving a podcast about environmental issues. How can the teacher ensure students develop critical listening skills?",
      "answers": [
        "Having students identify and discuss any biases or assumptions in the podcast",
        "Providing students with a detailed summary of the podcast before listening for proper previewing",
        "Asking students to memorize key facts presented in the podcast in preparation for a long quiz",
        "Playing the podcast multiple times to ensure understanding"
      ],
      "correct": "Having students identify and discuss any biases or assumptions in the podcast"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "During a classroom activity, students are asked to conduct a formal interview with a guest speaker. Which mode of communication is primarily being utilized in this scenario?",
      "answers": [
        "Historical documentaries showcasing past events",
        "Feature films with complex narratives",
        "Political advertisements from various campaigns",
        "Nature documentaries with educational content"
      ],
      "correct": "Political advertisements from various campaigns"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "Which assessment method best evaluates students' comprehensive listening skills in a multidimensional listening lesson?",
      "answers": [
        "Multiple-choice questions focusing on specific details",
        "Fill-in-the-blank exercises based on the audio content",
        "Short answer questions that require paraphrasing",
        "Reflective essays that analyze and interpret the listening material"
      ],
      "correct": "Reflective essays that analyze and interpret the listening material"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "What trend in materials for speaking skills emphasizes learner autonomy and self-directed learning?",
      "answers": [
        "Teacher-led classroom discussions and debates followed by students' choral reading",
        "Digital platforms with interactive speaking exercises and feedback",
        "Printed textbooks with scripted dialogues",
        "Audio CDs with repeated listening and speaking practice to automatize understanding"
      ],
      "correct": "Digital platforms with interactive speaking exercises and feedback"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "Which factor is most important when selecting textbook materials for developing writing skills?",
      "answers": [
        "The inclusion of advanced grammar exercises",
        "The presence of sample essays with diverse genres",
        "The availability of chapter summaries for quick review",
        "The provision of guided writing prompts and tasks"
      ],
      "correct": "The provision of guided writing prompts and tasks"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "Which material is most effective for developing critical thinking skills in reading?",
      "answers": [
        "Articles and essays on current social issues",
        "Illustrated storybooks for young readers",
        "Simplified texts with controlled vocabulary",
        "Classic novels from the 19th century"
      ],
      "correct": "Articles and essays on current social issues"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "Which output activity best supports the development of vocabulary fluency through active use?",
      "answers": [
        "Writing a summary of a text using key vocabulary words",
        "Matching vocabulary words to their definitions in a quiz",
        "Listening to a podcast and taking notes on new vocabulary",
        "Reading a passage silently and highlighting new words"
      ],
      "correct": "Writing a summary of a text using key vocabulary words"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "What is the main purpose of reading for professional development?",
      "answers": [
        "The inclusion of complex and advanced grammatical structures",
        "The provision of extensive lists of grammar rules and exceptions",
        "The focus on mechanical drills and rote memorization",
        "The use of interactive activities and real-life contexts"
      ],
      "correct": "The use of interactive activities and real-life contexts"
    }
  ],
  "TEACHING AND ASSESSMENT OF THE MACROSKILLS": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "In assessing reading comprehension, what is the primary goal of providing feedback based on metacognitive strategies?",
      "answers": [
        "To improve decoding skills",
        "To enhance vocabulary acquisition",
        "To develop students' ability to monitor and regulate their own understanding",
        "To encourage rote memorization of reading materials"
      ],
      "correct": "To develop students' ability to monitor and regulate their own understanding"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "What is the primary benefit of using multicultural literature in reading instruction?",
      "answers": [
        "Enhances decoding skills through diverse language exposure",
        "Fosters inclusivity and broadens students' cultural perspectives",
        "Increases standardized test scores across demographic groups",
        "Reduces the need for differentiated instruction in the classroom"
      ],
      "correct": "Fosters inclusivity and broadens students' cultural perspectives"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "What can be inferred about the role of differentiated instruction in writing lessons?",
      "answers": [
        "It creates a uniform learning experience for all students.",
        "It addresses the diverse needs and skill levels of students.",
        "It focuses exclusively on high-achieving students.",
        "It simplifies lesson planning by using a single approach."
      ],
      "correct": "It addresses the diverse needs and skill levels of students."
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "During a job interview, a candidate is asked to describe their previous work experience. What type of speaking format is being utilized?",
      "answers": [
        "Interactive speaking",
        "Transactional speaking",
        "Persuasive speaking",
        "Informal speaking"
      ],
      "correct": "Transactional speaking"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Which of the following best exemplifies the primary goal of Communicative Language Teaching (CLT)?",
      "answers": [
        "Mastery of grammar rules and structures for advanced level placement",
        "Ability to perform well on standardized tests",
        "Development of communicative competence in real-life contexts",
        "Focus on rote memorization of vocabulary"
      ],
      "correct": "Development of communicative competence in real-life contexts"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes a primary advantage of using Content-Based Instruction (CBI) in language teaching?",
      "answers": [
        "It focuses largely on grammar and vocabulary acquisition as dictated by reference books",
        "It provides real-world context and meaningful use of language",
        "It emphasizes lively conversation based on beautifully written scripts",
        "It relies exclusively on traditional lecture methods"
      ],
      "correct": "It provides real-world context and meaningful use of language"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "A student in a group discussion frequently interrupts others and dominates the conversation. What feedback should the teacher provide to promote better group dynamics?",
      "answers": [
        "\"Try to speak less so others have a chance to talk.\"",
        "\"Encourage your peers to interrupt you if they have something to add.\"",
        "\"Practice active listening and wait for others to finish before speaking.\"",
        "\"Focus on making stronger arguments to lead the discussion.\""
      ],
      "correct": "\"Practice active listening and wait for others to finish before speaking.\""
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Which strategy best illustrates the integration of receptive and expressive macro skills in a classroom activity?",
      "answers": [
        "Students watch a video and write an essay based on its content",
        "Students internalize grammar rules from a textbook before answering grammar quiz",
        "Students practice vocabulary drills extensively in preparation for spelling games",
        "Students engage in silent reading and then proceed to discussion a month after"
      ],
      "correct": "Students watch a video and write an essay based on its content"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the Bottom-Up approach to teaching reading?",
      "answers": [
        "Focusing on direct instruction of phonics, decoding, and word recognition",
        "Emphasizing students' background knowledge and context to derive meaning from text",
        "Using students' interests and experiences as the primary means to engage with texts",
        "Combining elements of both decoding and context-based understanding"
      ],
      "correct": "Focusing on direct instruction of phonics, decoding, and word recognition"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Which listening strategy involves focusing on key words and phrases to understand the main idea of a spoken text?",
      "answers": [
        "Selective listening",
        "Intensive listening",
        "Extensive listening",
        "Critical listening"
      ],
      "correct": "Selective listening"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "What can be inferred as a significant advantage of using portfolio based assessments in teaching writing?",
      "answers": [
        "They offer a comprehensive picture of students' progress and skills.",
        "They provide a limited view of students' writing development over time.",
        "They allow for the evaluation of students' final writing products only.",
        "They reduce the amount of feedback students receive."
      ],
      "correct": "They offer a comprehensive picture of students' progress and skills."
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "A writer is drafting their story and is unsure how to maintain a logical flow. Which strategy can they use to address this concern?",
      "answers": [
        "Using an outline to organize ideas and plot points",
        "Ignoring structure and focusing only on creativity",
        "Writing scenes in random order and rearranging later",
        "Concentrating solely on character development"
      ],
      "correct": "Using an outline to organize ideas and plot points"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Which sub-skill is essential for effective reading comprehension, particularly when synthesizing information from multiple sources?",
      "answers": [
        "Summarizing",
        "Decoding",
        "Annotating",
        "Inferring"
      ],
      "correct": "Summarizing"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which of the following best illustrates a key difference between the Bottom-Up and Top-Down approaches",
      "answers": [
        "Bottom-Up focuses on meaning-making first, while Top-Down focuses on phonics first.",
        "Top-Down relies on explicit phonics instruction, whereas Bottom Up emphasizes comprehension.",
        "Bottom-Up emphasizes word recognition and phonics, while Top Down uses prior knowledge and context for comprehension.",
        "Top-Down uses drills and repetition, while Bottom-Up focuses on holistic reading experiences, both aiming to achieve cognitive balance."
      ],
      "correct": "Bottom-Up emphasizes word recognition and phonics, while Top Down uses prior knowledge and context for comprehension."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "In Goodell's Reading Skills Ladder, which stage involves developing the ability to read fluently with expression and comprehension?",
      "answers": [
        "Fluency stage",
        "Interpretation stage",
        "Initial recognition stage",
        "Critical reading stage"
      ],
      "correct": "Fluency stage"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the role of non-verbal communication in active listening?",
      "answers": [
        "It enhances the listener's ability to understand the speaker's emotions",
        "It can be ignored if the listener is focusing on the speaker's words",
        "It is less important than verbal communication",
        "It should be minimal to avoid distracting the speaker"
      ],
      "correct": "It enhances the listener's ability to understand the speaker's emotions"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "What can be inferred as a primary benefit of providing formative feedback on students' writing during the drafting process?",
      "answers": [
        "It promotes students' engagement and ownership of their writing.",
        "It focuses entirely on grammatical accuracy and punctuation.",
        "It ensures students will have perfect final drafts.",
        "It simplifies the teacher's workload by providing generic comments."
      ],
      "correct": "It promotes students' engagement and ownership of their writing."
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "What is one benefit of using performance-based assessments in writing instruction?",
      "answers": [
        "They emphasize real-world application of writing skills.",
        "They focus on standardized testing metrics to meet international status.",
        "They require less time for teachers to assess.",
        "They limit students' creativity by enforcing strict guidelines."
      ],
      "correct": "They emphasize real-world application of writing skills."
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "What is one challenge of implementing performance-based assessments in writing?",
      "answers": [
        "They may require significant time and resources to administer.",
        "They are easy to standardize across different classrooms.",
        "They provide limited insights into students' writing abilities.",
        "They do not align with real-world writing tasks."
      ],
      "correct": "They may require significant time and resources to administer."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "During the pre-writing phase, a student struggles to generate ideas for their essay topic. Which strategy would be most effective in helping them overcome this issue?",
      "answers": [
        "Conducting a brainstorming session to list potential ideas",
        "Skipping pre-writing and starting with the first draf",
        "Writing the introduction first to see if ideas develop",
        "Focusing on grammar and punctuation from the beginning"
      ],
      "correct": "Conducting a brainstorming session to list potential ideas"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "A teacher uses video recordings of students' speeches as a resource for self-assessment. What is the main benefit of this approach?",
      "answers": [
        "It helps students memorize their speeches",
        "It allows students to visually and audibly evaluate their performance",
        "It encourages students to copy each other's speaking styles",
        "It simplifies the teacher's grading process"
      ],
      "correct": "It allows students to visually and audibly evaluate their performance"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Teacher Sara assigns students to watch TED Talks and prepare responses. What is the intended benefit of using TED Talks as a resource for speaking lessons?",
      "answers": [
        "They offer opportunities to practice reading aloud",
        "They provide examples of effective public speaking and diverse topics",
        "They ensure students use complex academic vocabulary",
        "They simplify the learning process by focusing on short clips"
      ],
      "correct": "They provide examples of effective public speaking and diverse topics"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "How does incorporating viewing as a macro skill benefit students' overall language proficiency?",
      "answers": [
        "It emphasizes the importance of listening skills over visual literacy",
        "It solely focuses on enhancing students' artistic abilities",
        "It helps students interpret and critically analyze visual information",
        "It replaces traditional reading and writing practices"
      ],
      "correct": "It helps students interpret and critically analyze visual information"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "What is the significance of teaching students to critically view advertisements and media messages?",
      "answers": [
        "It helps students learn to create visually appealing advertisements, encouraging them to be more innovative",
        "It limits students' exposure to diverse media formats",
        "It encourages students to accept all media messages as truth that must be always upheld",
        "It enables students to understand and analyze the persuasive techniques used"
      ],
      "correct": "It enables students to understand and analyze the persuasive techniques used"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "In the English K to 12 curriculum, how is speaking competency developed to prepare students for real-world communication?",
      "answers": [
        "By practicing scripted dialogues only",
        "By emphasizing public speaking and presentation skills in various contexts",
        "By focusing solely on pronunciation drills",
        "By limiting speaking activities to classroom discussions"
      ],
      "correct": "By emphasizing public speaking and presentation skills in various contexts"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Which of the following best illustrates the interdependence of receptive and expressive macro skills in language learning?",
      "answers": [
        "A student reads a text and then writes a summary of it",
        "A student memorizes a list of vocabulary words without context",
        "A student practices pronunciation drills in isolation",
        "A student listens to music without attempting to understand the lyrics"
      ],
      "correct": "A student reads a text and then writes a summary of it"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "A student has written a rough draft but notices some sentences are awkward. Which editing strategy can help improve sentence structure?",
      "answers": [
        "Adding more adjectives and adverbs to each sentence to evoke vivid imagery",
        "Removing all punctuation marks to simplify sentences",
        "Rewriting every sentence using passive voice for clearer understanding",
        "Breaking down long sentences into shorter, clearer ones"
      ],
      "correct": "Breaking down long sentences into shorter, clearer ones"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "In what way does viewing as a macro skill contribute to critical thinking development in students?",
      "answers": [
        "By encouraging active consumption of visual media and passive production of speech",
        "By promoting superficial observation of images",
        "By fostering analytical skills through the evaluation of visual content",
        "By focusing on the aesthetic aspects of visuals to develop deeper appreciation"
      ],
      "correct": "By fostering analytical skills through the evaluation of visual content"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "What is a key challenge in using automated feedback systems in assessing reading comprehension?",
      "answers": [
        "Inability to provide immediate feedback",
        "Lack of engagement from students",
        "Limited access to technology in classrooms",
        "Difficulty in assessing higher-order thinking skills"
      ],
      "correct": "Difficulty in assessing higher-order thinking skills"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "What is a primary goal of using literature circles in reading instruction?",
      "answers": [
        "To promote individual silent reading, enhancing their reflective skills",
        "To encourage competitive reading performance among advanced pupils",
        "To facilitate collaborative discussion and deeper comprehension",
        "To focus on teacher-led instruction slowly guiding low-level students"
      ],
      "correct": "To facilitate collaborative discussion and deeper comprehension"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "At which stage of Goodell's Reading Skills Ladder does a reader begin to develop inferential comprehension?",
      "answers": [
        "Decoding stage",
        "Initial recognition stage",
        "Interpretation stage",
        "Critical reading stage"
      ],
      "correct": "Interpretation stage"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "Which type of feedback is most effective for improving students' listening comprehension skills?",
      "answers": [
        "Summative feedback provided at the end of a listening exercise",
        "Delayed feedback given after all listening activities are completed",
        "Immediate formative feedback during the listening exercise",
        "Peer feedback based on group discussions"
      ],
      "correct": "Immediate formative feedback during the listening exercise"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "Which method is most effective for ensuring the reliability of observation-based assessments in listening?",
      "answers": [
        "Using a single observer to maintain consistency",
        "Relying on informal, unstructured observations",
        "Developing a detailed rubric with specific criteria",
        "Focusing solely on summative assessments"
      ],
      "correct": "Developing a detailed rubric with specific criteria"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "Which type of listening material is particularly effective for developing students' ability to understand different speech rates and intonations?",
      "answers": [
        "Textbook audio recordings",
        "Live lectures with consistent pacing",
        "Podcasts with varied speakers and topics",
        "Pre-recorded classroom dialogues"
      ],
      "correct": "Podcasts with varied speakers and topics"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Mr. Taba observes a student delivering a presentation and notices frequent pauses and filler words like \"um\" and \"uh.\" Which feedback strategy would be most effective in helping the student improve fluency?",
      "answers": [
        "Focusing on the content of the presentation first then correcting the structure",
        "Suggesting the student practice speaking without notes to dampen his/her confidence",
        "Recommending the student use more advanced vocabulary tom impress the audience",
        "Providing immediate feedback on reducing pauses and filler words"
      ],
      "correct": "Providing immediate feedback on reducing pauses and filler words"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "What quality should an effective English macro skills teacher possess to enhance students' listening skills in a diverse classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "Ability to lecture extensively without interruption",
        "Expertise in translating texts for students",
        "Proficiency in using varied and authentic listening materials",
        "Capability to minimize student discussions during lessons"
      ],
      "correct": "Proficiency in using varied and authentic listening materials"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "How does extensive reading of literature contribute to vocabulary development in language learners?",
      "answers": [
        "By exposing learners to a range of vocabulary in repeated contexts based on the principle of reinforcement",
        "By providing contextual clues that aid in understanding and retention of new words",
        "By focusing on technical terminology used in specific fields to gain genuine mastery of content",
        "By emphasizing rote memorization of vocabulary lists"
      ],
      "correct": "By providing contextual clues that aid in understanding and retention of new words"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "In what way does practicing writing skills help improve grammatical competence?",
      "answers": [
        "By allowing students to avoid complex sentence structures",
        "By providing opportunities for immediate oral feedback",
        "By enabling the application of grammar rules in varied contexts",
        "By limiting the use of creative expression"
      ],
      "correct": "By enabling the application of grammar rules in varied contexts"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "What role does listening to literary works (e.g., audiobooks) play in developing listening skills and grammatical knowledge?",
      "answers": [
        "It emphasizes the importance of silent reading over listening",
        "It focuses exclusively on visual learning methods",
        "It limits the exposure to conversational language",
        "It exposes listeners to varied sentence structures and grammatical forms"
      ],
      "correct": "It exposes listeners to varied sentence structures and grammatical forms"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "Which component of the speaking process involves the mental planning and organization of speech before verbalizing it?",
      "answers": [
        "Phonation",
        "Articulation",
        "Cognitive planning",
        "Resonance"
      ],
      "correct": "Cognitive planning"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "What teaching approach should an effective English macro skills teacher adopt to improve students' writing skills?",
      "answers": [
        "Emphasizing the importance of perfect grammar from the start to prevent major mistakes later",
        "Using a single writing format for all assignments to achieve uniformity and standardization",
        "Focusing on academic writing styles, enhancing their knowledge of colloquialisms",
        "Encouraging frequent writing practice and providing constructive feedback"
      ],
      "correct": "Encouraging frequent writing practice and providing constructive feedback"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "Which of the following best explains the role of visual literacy in enhancing students' communicative competence?",
      "answers": [
        "It focuses on memorizing visual elements without understanding context",
        "It limits students' engagement with multimedia content",
        "It emphasizes the use of visuals over verbal communication",
        "It enables students to decode and create meaning from visual texts"
      ],
      "correct": "It enables students to decode and create meaning from visual texts"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "In a group discussion, a student frequently uses gestures and facial expressions to emphasize their points. Which aspect of communication are they primarily utilizing?",
      "answers": [
        "Verbal communication",
        "Nonverbal communication",
        "Written communication",
        "Visual communication"
      ],
      "correct": "Nonverbal communication"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "During a classroom activity, students are asked to conduct a formal interview with a guest speaker. Which mode of communication is primarily being utilized in this scenario?",
      "answers": [
        "Nonverbal communication",
        "Written communication",
        "Interpersonal communication",
        "Mass communication"
      ],
      "correct": "Interpersonal communication"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "To develop students' ability to participate in formal discussions, a teacher wants to design a lesson that includes practice in structured debate. What is the best approach to achieve this?",
      "answers": [
        "Encouraging casual conversations during break time",
        "Showing students recorded debates without active participation",
        "Asking students to write persuasive essays",
        "Implementing a debate format with assigned roles and topics"
      ],
      "correct": "Implementing a debate format with assigned roles and topics"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "An author is writing a novel set in a futuristic world. What is the primary purpose of this type of writing?",
      "answers": [
        "To argue the benefits of advanced technology",
        "To inform readers about scientific facts and theories",
        "To provide step-by-step instructions on how to build futuristic gadgets",
        "To entertain readers with a captivating story and imaginative world"
      ],
      "correct": "To entertain readers with a captivating story and imaginative world"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "Leni is writing a research paper on the effects of climate change on coastal ecosystems. Which approach should they take to achieve the purpose of informative writing?",
      "answers": [
        "Sharing personal anecdotes about visiting the beach",
        "Using creative storytelling techniques to describe the ecosystems",
        "Persuading readers to take action against climate change",
        "Providing detailed, evidence-based information and analysis"
      ],
      "correct": "Providing detailed, evidence-based information and analysis"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "While proofreading their final draft, a student finds several spelling mistakes. Which tool or strategy is most effective for identifying and correcting these errors?",
      "answers": [
        "Reading the essay backward, one word at a time",
        "Using complex vocabulary to replace common words",
        "Ignoring the mistakes since they are minimal",
        "Changing the essay topic to avoid rewriting"
      ],
      "correct": "Reading the essay backward, one word at a time"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "What is the primary purpose of using reflective statements in active listening?",
      "answers": [
        "To change the subject of the conversation",
        "To challenge the speaker's viewpoint and thereby broadening understanding",
        "To give advice based on personal experiences and insights",
        "To paraphrase the speaker's message and confirm understanding"
      ],
      "correct": "To paraphrase the speaker's message and confirm understanding"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "What is the main purpose of reading for professional development?",
      "answers": [
        "To relax and relieve stress after a whole day of busy work",
        "To enjoy the aesthetic qualities of literary works, nourishing one's soul",
        "To engage with imaginative and creative narratives",
        "To acquire knowledge and skills relevant to one's career"
      ],
      "correct": "To acquire knowledge and skills relevant to one's career"
    }
  ],
  "CHILDREN AND ADOLESCENT LITERATURE": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "What role does family play in Little House on the Prairie, and how does it reflect the broader theme of perseverance?",
      "answers": [
        "The family's unity is depicted as a source of comfort that shields them from adversity.",
        "The family plays a central role in facing the difficulties of pioneer life, using love and resilience to overcome challenges.",
        "The Ingalls family faces challenges largely on their own, with little sense of communal support.",
        "The family is portrayed as a source of tension and conflict, hindering the characters' ability to persevere."
      ],
      "correct": "The family plays a central role in facing the difficulties of pioneer life, using love and resilience to overcome challenges."
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "In Number the Stars, how does Lois Lowry convey the importance of friendship in times of crisis?",
      "answers": [
        "Friendship is a secondary theme, with the story focusing more on historical events.",
        "The bond of friendship is critical, as it motivates Annemarie's acts of bravery to protect her Jewish friend.",
        "Friendship is portrayed as an obstacle, as it complicates the characters' ability to make difficult choices.",
        "Friendship is shown to be less important than family loyalty in t imes of crisis."
      ],
      "correct": "The bond of friendship is critical, as it motivates Annemarie's acts of bravery to protect her Jewish friend."
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Where is the main setting of \"Where the Wild Things Are,\" and how does it contribute to the story's themes?",
      "answers": [
        "A city park, showing the boy's isolation in a crowded environment.",
        "A small village, representing the boy's longing for community.",
        "A remote island, highlighting the boy's adventure and self discovery.",
        "An enchanted forest, symbolizing the boy's encounter with magical beings."
      ],
      "correct": "A remote island, highlighting the boy's adventure and self discovery."
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "How does the structure of Beowulf, particularly its use of both heroic and Christian elements, reflect the culture of its time?",
      "answers": [
        "It emphasizes the adventure that follows",
        "It indicates the end of the poem",
        "It creates a rhythmic pattern that aids memorability",
        "It signals a change in the characters' relationship"
      ],
      "correct": "It creates a rhythmic pattern that aids memorability"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Who are the main characters in \"Jabberwocky,\" and how do their actions drive the poem's narrative?",
      "answers": [
        "The Jabberwock, who is seeking revenge; and the father, who guides the son",
        "The Jubjub bird, who assists the hero; and the Bandersnatch, who challenges him",
        "The young hero, who slays the Jabberwock; and his father, who praises him",
        "The hero's mother, who warns him; and the Jabberwock, who befriends him"
      ],
      "correct": "The young hero, who slays the Jabberwock; and his father, who praises him"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "When choosing a multicultural book for an adolescent classroom, what should teachers prioritize to engage students effectively?",
      "answers": [
        "The ability of the book to portray universal themes of friendship and family which makes it more relatable to readers.",
        "The emphasis on moral lessons rather than on cultural storytelling.",
        "The inclusion of contemporary issues that reflect the experiences and struggles of the students' cultures.",
        "The historical accuracy of the book, regardless of the students' ability to relate to the content."
      ],
      "correct": "The inclusion of contemporary issues that reflect the experiences and struggles of the students' cultures."
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "How does censorship in children's literature affect their understanding of social issues?",
      "answers": [
        "It allows children to fully explore complex social issues in a controlled environment.",
        "It encourages children to develop a sense of curiosity by keeping certain issues hidden.",
        "It prevents exposure to controversial topics, limiting the development of critical thinking.",
        "It has little impact on children as they do not understand the content they read."
      ],
      "correct": "It prevents exposure to controversial topics, limiting the development of critical thinking."
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "In Anne of Green Gables, how does Anne's imagination influence her interactions with others in Avonlea?",
      "answers": [
        "It isolates her from the community as people find her fantasies ridiculous.",
        "It makes her a more competitive person, often leading to conflicts with peers and her close relatives.",
        "It enables her to form deep connections with others by offering creative solutions to everyday problems.",
        "It causes her to withdraw from social situations as she lives more in her imagined worlds."
      ],
      "correct": "It enables her to form deep connections with others by offering creative solutions to everyday problems."
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which literary device is most prominently used in \"Jabberwocky\" by Lewis Carroll to create a sense of mystery and confusion?",
      "answers": [
        "Alliteration",
        "Hyperbole",
        "Nonsense words",
        "Simile"
      ],
      "correct": "Nonsense words"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "How do the rhyme schemes in \"Mother Goose Nursery Rhymes\" contribute to their memorability?",
      "answers": [
        "By using irregular patterns that challenge the reader's expectations",
        "By incorporating complex and varied meters",
        "By employing simple, repetitive, and predictable patterns",
        "By avoiding any form of rhyming altogether"
      ],
      "correct": "By employing simple, repetitive, and predictable patterns"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "How can teachers use the variety of book formats (paperback, e books, audiobooks) to cater to the diverse needs of children with varying literacy abilities?",
      "answers": [
        "By offering only one format, ensuring consistency and ease of access for all students.",
        "By providing multiple formats to give students choices, helping them engage with texts in ways that suit their learning styles.",
        "By avoiding digital formats, as they may detract from the experience of reading printed books.",
        "By focusing solely on audiobooks to allow students to focus on listening rather than reading."
      ],
      "correct": "By providing multiple formats to give students choices, helping them engage with texts in ways that suit their learning styles."
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "In what way does storytelling enhance children's literacy development, particularly when they actively participate in the process?",
      "answers": [
        "It provides an opportunity to engage with a single fixed narrative without much variation.",
        "It allows children to experiment with language, structure, and expression while enhancing comprehension skills.",
        "It limits creative expression by encouraging children to follow a prescribed story structure and by instilling writing discipline.",
        "It focuses primarily on listening skills, with little benefit to language production or creative thinking."
      ],
      "correct": "It allows children to experiment with language, structure, and expression while enhancing comprehension skills."
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "What is the significance of Hidden Figures by M. L. Shetterly in showcasing the contribution of African-American women to the space race?",
      "answers": [
        "It challenges the notion that science and technology were predominantly shaped by men of European descent.",
        "It focuses solely on the political struggles of the 1960s, overlooking the technical achievements.",
        "It emphasizes the role of white men in the success of the American space program.",
        "It downplays the significance of race and gender in the careers of these women."
      ],
      "correct": "It challenges the notion that science and technology were predominantly shaped by men of European descent."
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "In I Am Malala, how does Malala's relationship with her father, Ziauddin Yousafzai, shape her activism?",
      "answers": [
        "Her father serves as a passive figure, offering little encouragement or support for her advocacy.",
        "Her father's dedication to education and his progressive views inspire her to become an outspoken advocate for girls' education.",
        "Malala's activism is independent of her father, and she advocates for girls' education without his influence.",
        "Her father discourages her activism, fearing for her safety and encouraging her to focus on traditional roles for women."
      ],
      "correct": "Her father's dedication to education and his progressive views inspire her to become an outspoken advocate for girls' education."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "In Peter Rabbit, which of the following best represents the moral outcome of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "Curiosity is the key to discovering new opportunities even though it might pose some serious consequences.",
        "Stealing is wrong but can be justified in specific situations.",
        "Mischief is acceptable as long as it is done for fun.",
        "Breaking the rules can lead to undesirable results, but there is always a chance for redemption."
      ],
      "correct": "Breaking the rules can lead to undesirable results, but there is always a chance for redemption."
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "How does Winnie the Pooh demonstrate the value of simplicity in life?",
      "answers": [
        "By showing that complex problems can always be solved with detailed plans and rigor.",
        "By illustrating that happiness often comes from appreciating small moments.",
        "By portraying that having a lot of material wealth leads to greater happiness in the long term.",
        "By showing that a rigid routine is essential for peace and joy."
      ],
      "correct": "By illustrating that happiness often comes from appreciating small moments."
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Which feature of \"Mother Goose Nursery Rhymes\" helps them maintain cultural relevance over time?",
      "answers": [
        "Their educational content",
        "The use of complex vocabulary",
        "Their use of traditional themes and values",
        "The inclusion of moral lessons and philosophical musings"
      ],
      "correct": "Their use of traditional themes and values"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "How does \"The Giving Tree\" utilize symbolism to convey its message?",
      "answers": [
        "The tree symbolizes selfishness.",
        "The boy symbolizes nature.",
        "The tree symbolizes selfless love.",
        "The boy symbolizes material wealth."
      ],
      "correct": "The tree symbolizes selfless love."
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "What makes The Cat in the Hat a popular choice for early readers?",
      "answers": [
        "It uses an advanced vocabulary to challenge young readers.",
        "The book's storyline is simple, with clear moral lessons about responsibility and behavior.",
        "Its playful language, rhythm, and repetition make it engaging for young children.",
        "It focuses on the development of complex character relationships and emotions."
      ],
      "correct": "Its playful language, rhythm, and repetition make it engaging for young children."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "What central theme is explored in Peter Rabbit?",
      "answers": [
        "The importance of obedience and following rules.",
        "The value of curiosity in overcoming adversity.",
        "The significance of family loyalty and togetherness.",
        "The danger of venturing into the unknown."
      ],
      "correct": "The importance of obedience and following rules."
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "How does Curious George challenge traditional fable structures? A. It introduces a more sophisticated moral lesson about responsibility.",
      "answers": [
        "It introduces a more sophisticated moral lesson about responsibility.",
        "The animal character exhibits less human-like traits compared to traditional fables.",
        "It places emphasis on problem-solving through accidental discoveries.",
        "It includes a distinct moral message about the consequences of mischief."
      ],
      "correct": "It places emphasis on problem-solving through accidental discoveries."
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "What does Anne Frank's diary reveal about the relationship between hope and despair in extreme circumstances?",
      "answers": [
        "Hope and despair are portrayed as opposites, with Anne rarely feeling both at once.",
        "The diary shows that in extreme circumstances, hope and despair coexist, with Anne often experiencing both emotions simultaneously.",
        "Anne becomes completely overwhelmed by despair and loses all hope by the end of the diary after witnessing the death of her entire family.",
        "Hope is the only emotion Anne experiences, as she believes the war will end soon, making her more resilient despite the tragedy around her."
      ],
      "correct": "The diary shows that in extreme circumstances, hope and despair coexist, with Anne often experiencing both emotions simultaneously."
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "How does Little House on the Prairie address the theme of adaptability in the face of change?",
      "answers": [
        "The family resists all changes and prefers to live according to old traditions.",
        "The Ingalls family learns to adapt to their new environment, embracing change while maintaining their core values.",
        "Adaptability is not an important theme; the focus is on the stability of traditional values for the community to survive.",
        "The family refuses to adapt to changes, which leads to their downfall and eventual separation of members from their land."
      ],
      "correct": "The Ingalls family learns to adapt to their new environment, embracing change while maintaining their core values."
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "How do the stories by L. Gatmaitan and other Palanca awardees contribute to the representation of Filipino values in modern literature?",
      "answers": [
        "They exclusively present traditional Filipino values without any consideration for contemporary issues.",
        "They reflect both the traditional and evolving values of Filipino society, engaging with modern concerns.",
        "They only focus on contemporary, urban experiences, neglecting rural traditions.",
        "They primarily showcase Filipino struggles in a way that removes the complexity of societal change."
      ],
      "correct": "They reflect both the traditional and evolving values of Filipino society, engaging with modern concerns."
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "In the context of multicultural literature, how do the themes in Akong Bugsay resonate with global issues of migration and identity?",
      "answers": [
        "The story provides a strictly local view, with little to no relevance to global themes.",
        "It explores the complexities of maintaining one's cultural identity amidst migration and external pressures.",
        "It primarily focuses on economic struggles without addressing cultural identity.",
        "The narrative is centered on individuals who completely assimilate to a new culture, losing their original identity."
      ],
      "correct": "It explores the complexities of maintaining one's cultural identity amidst migration and external pressures."
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "How does the portrayal of characters in movie or TV versions of classic fables differ from the original text?",
      "answers": [
        "Characters in movie and TV adaptations often have more depth, with their motivations explored in greater detail.",
        "Characters are typically simplified to fit a predefined moral narrative and are less nuanced.",
        "Movie and TV adaptations usually leave characters unchanged to preserve the original story's impact.",
        "Characters in adaptations focus only on providing comic relief rather than contributing to the moral of the story."
      ],
      "correct": "Characters in movie and TV adaptations often have more depth, with their motivations explored in greater detail."
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "What is the primary challenge when rewriting or deconstructing classical tales for contemporary children's literature?",
      "answers": [
        "It is difficult to balance modern values with the historical context and lessons of the original story.",
        "The process is largely unproductive, as it simply duplicates the original without offering anything new.",
        "It causes children to become confused about traditional stories and their meanings, leading to unresolved cognitive dilemma.",
        "It makes the stories overly complex and inaccessible for young readers."
      ],
      "correct": "It is difficult to balance modern values with the historical context and lessons of the original story."
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "How does the strategy of reading aloud to children support the development of literacy skills?",
      "answers": [
        "It limits vocabulary exposure by focusing on familiar, repetitive texts often leading to stunted understanding of various text types.",
        "It focuses primarily on visual literacy, with little emphasis on auditory processing or understanding.",
        "It only helps children become better at memorizing stories rather than developing critical thinking.",
        "It promotes word recognition, comprehension, and vocabulary growth by exposing children to complex language structures."
      ],
      "correct": "It promotes word recognition, comprehension, and vocabulary growth by exposing children to complex language structures."
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "How does Curious George illustrate the theme of curiosity?",
      "answers": [
        "By showing that curiosity always leads to danger.",
        "By demonstrating that curiosity can be controlled through self discipline.",
        "By portraying curiosity as a virtue that should be completely suppressed.",
        "By highlighting that curiosity can lead to learning, even through mistakes."
      ],
      "correct": "By highlighting that curiosity can lead to learning, even through mistakes."
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "In \"The Little Prince\" by Antoine de Saint-Exupery, what event marks the rising action of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "The prince's meeting with the rose",
        "The prince's meeting with the king",
        "The prince's decision to return to his asteroid",
        "The prince's journey to various asteroids"
      ],
      "correct": "The prince's journey to various asteroids"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "Who is the author of \"The Rainbow Fish\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Eric Carle",
        "Maurice Sendak",
        "Dr. Seuss",
        "Marcus Pfister"
      ],
      "correct": "Marcus Pfister"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "In \"The Ugly Duckling\" by Hans Christian Andersen, what is the setting of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "A bustling city littered with ducklings of all sorts and colors",
        "A quiet village surrounded by ponds and rivers where ducklings thrive",
        "A dense forest full of birds of all kinds including ducks, swans, and chickens",
        "A place where a duckling could grow into a swan"
      ],
      "correct": "A place where a duckling could grow into a swan"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "In \"The Three Little Pigs\" by James Orchard Halliwell, what is the point of view used in the story?",
      "answers": [
        "First-person point of view",
        "Second-person point of view",
        "Multiple points of view",
        "Third-person point of view"
      ],
      "correct": "Third-person point of view"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "In \"The Little Engine That Could\" by Watty Piper, what is the setting of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "A vibrant city where Industrial Revolution is welcome",
        "A denuded forest that will be made into a subdivision",
        "A hidden village built by mechanical engineers",
        "A place where a little engine could pull a train"
      ],
      "correct": "A place where a little engine could pull a train"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "In \"The Story of Ferdinand\" by Munro Leaf, what is the point of view used in the story?",
      "answers": [
        "First-person point of view",
        "Second-person point of view",
        "Multiple points of view",
        "Third-person point of view"
      ],
      "correct": "Third-person point of view"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "In \"Harold and the Purple Crayon\" by Crockett Johnson, what is the theme in the story?",
      "answers": [
        "Conflict between tradition and modernity",
        "Importance of color in one's existence",
        "The inherent goodness of humans",
        "Imagination as a tool for exploration"
      ],
      "correct": "Imagination as a tool for exploration"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "In \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\" by Roald Dahl, what does the chocolate river symbolize?",
      "answers": [
        "Turmoil",
        "Nirvana",
        "Danger",
        "Excess"
      ],
      "correct": "Excess"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "In what way does the use of language in the works of L. Gatmaitan, a Palanca awardee, contribute to the depiction of Filipino identity?",
      "answers": [
        "It reinforces colonial narratives that define the Filipino identity through external perspectives.",
        "It blends native and foreign linguistic elements to illustrate the hybridity of modern Filipino culture.",
        "It strictly uses native languages to avoid any influence of foreign cultures.",
        "It relies on historical language forms that are inaccessible to contemporary readers."
      ],
      "correct": "It blends native and foreign linguistic elements to illustrate the hybridity of modern Filipino culture."
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the tone of \"Jabberwocky\" by Lewis Carroll?",
      "answers": [
        "Somber and reflective",
        "Playful and surreal",
        "Serious and instructive",
        "Melancholic and dark"
      ],
      "correct": "Playful and surreal"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "When selecting multicultural literature for children, which of the following is the most important factor to ensure an authentic representation of diverse cultures?",
      "answers": [
        "The inclusion of exotic settings and characters from unfamiliar cultures.",
        "Accurate and respectful representation of cultural traditions, values, and experiences.",
        "The portrayal of diverse characters as heroes, even if it distorts cultural facts.",
        "The focus on visual elements such as illustrations to show cultural diversity."
      ],
      "correct": "Accurate and respectful representation of cultural traditions, values, and experiences."
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "What type of plot involves a character rising in wealth or status?",
      "answers": [
        "Overcoming the Monster",
        "The Quest",
        "Rags to Riches",
        "Voyage and Return"
      ],
      "correct": "Rags to Riches"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "Who is an example of a dynamic character in literature?",
      "answers": [
        "Ebenezer Scrooge from \"A Christmas Carol\"",
        "Sherlock Holmes from \"Sherlock Holmes\"",
        "Mr. Bennet from \"Pride and Prejudice\"",
        "Samwise Gamgee from \"The Lord of the Rings\""
      ],
      "correct": "Ebenezer Scrooge from \"A Christmas Carol\""
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "In \"1984\", Winston Smith struggles against the oppressive government of Oceania. What type of conflict is this?",
      "answers": [
        "Man vs. Man",
        "Man vs. Nature",
        "Man vs. Self",
        "Man vs. Society"
      ],
      "correct": "Man vs. Society"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "In \"A Sick Day for Amos McGee\" by Philip C. Stead, why do the animals visit Amos when he is sick?",
      "answers": [
        "They want to play with him because they haven't done so in weeks.",
        "They are bored at the zoo and want to do something adventurous.",
        "They want to take care of him as he takes care of them.",
        "They want to live with him and care for him."
      ],
      "correct": "They want to take care of him as he takes care of them."
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "In \"Who's in My Family?\" by Robie H. Harris, what is the main message of the book?",
      "answers": [
        "Families should always have a pet.",
        "Families should always eat dinner together.",
        "Families come in many different forms and that's perfectly normal.",
        "Families should always go to the zoo together."
      ],
      "correct": "Families come in many different forms and that's perfectly normal."
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "In \"The Kid and the Chameleon\" by Sheri Mabry, what does Tessy learn about making friends?",
      "answers": [
        "Friends should always have the same interests.",
        "Friends can have different interests and still enjoy spending time together.",
        "Friends should always do what she wants to do.",
        "Friends should always be the same species."
      ],
      "correct": "Friends can have different interests and still enjoy spending time together."
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "In \"A Worn Path\" by Eudora Welty, what is the main message of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "The power of love and sacrifice of a young but mature child",
        "The struggle for identity and self-discovery of a boy trapped in an old woman's body",
        "The strength and endurance of an elderly woman",
        "The effects of technology on society and the aftermath of Industrial Revolution"
      ],
      "correct": "The strength and endurance of an elderly woman"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "In \"The Red Badge of Courage\" by Stephen Crane, what is the main theme of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "The power of love and sacrifice",
        "The struggle for identity and self-discovery",
        "The effects of technology on society",
        "The meaning of courage in the face of war"
      ],
      "correct": "The meaning of courage in the face of war"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "In \"How Many Miles to Babylon?\" by Jennifer Johnston, what is the main theme of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "The vast expanse of land and its huge potential benefits for the people living in it",
        "The perfect harmony of nature and humans as the latter travel great distances",
        "The effects of personal conflicts and the temporary impact of wrong choice on young people's psyche",
        "The unlikely friendship between two boys from different social backgrounds"
      ],
      "correct": "The unlikely friendship between two boys from different social backgrounds"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "In \"Because of Winn-Dixie\" by Kate DiCamillo, what is the main lesson of the story?",
      "answers": [
        "The eternal struggle for individual goals versus societal expectations",
        "The endless yearning for motherland despite years of living in a foreign land",
        "The unreliability of memory in solving problems and uncovering the truth",
        "The power of friendship and the importance of forgiveness"
      ],
      "correct": "The power of friendship and the importance of forgiveness"
    }
  ],
  "MYTHOLOGY AND FOLKLORE": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "The \"body\" (line 3) is the body of _____ . And on the slope above the sea The hard-handed peasants go their round Turning the soil, blind to the body Ambitious and viable, whose pride Will leave no trace in the quenching tide.",
      "answers": [
        "Ulysses",
        "Achilles",
        "Icarus",
        "Priam"
      ],
      "correct": "Icarus"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "In the story of Odysseus, as they were sailing back to Ithaca after the Trojan war, they passed along a narrow straits and were tested by the monster Scylla and the giant whirlpool, Charybdis. These two women used to be beautiful maidens who earned the anger of Amphitrite. What was the cause of the anger?",
      "answers": [
        "Amphitrite was jealous of the two.",
        "Amphitrite was envious of the beauty of the two women.",
        "Amphitrite was worried about the condition of Odysseus.",
        "Amphitrite used her powers against the two."
      ],
      "correct": "Amphitrite was jealous of the two."
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Paul Bunyan and Bernardo Carpio are tales that depict a greatly exaggerated imaginative story or account of something or someone such as an extraordinary person doing extra ordinary things. What type of tales being described?",
      "answers": [
        "Realistic tales",
        "Folktale",
        "Humorous tales",
        "Tall tales"
      ],
      "correct": "Tall tales"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "What is the Greek name for Venus?",
      "answers": [
        "Aphrodite",
        "Thalassa",
        "Venus",
        "Thalea"
      ],
      "correct": "Aphrodite"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "For what act is Antigone sentenced to death?",
      "answers": [
        "She killed her own father.",
        "She refused to marry the king's son.",
        "She disobeyed her sister's command.",
        "She performed the burial rituals for her brother."
      ],
      "correct": "She performed the burial rituals for her brother."
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "He was a fearless warrior and king who one day saw the emptiness of his life and turned his back on it, becoming a wanderer and sadhu. He refused to return to the world that is why he is often alluded to as having refused the responsibility.",
      "answers": [
        "King Minos",
        "King Muchukunda",
        "King Rama",
        "Jason"
      ],
      "correct": "King Muchukunda"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Which mythical creature is depicted as a shape changer who could transform into a cat, a big dog, or a pig, and who liked to eat people?",
      "answers": [
        "Manananggal",
        "Aswang",
        "Tikbalang",
        "Kapre"
      ],
      "correct": "Aswang"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "When Pallas Athena appeared as an old woman and challenged Arachne to a weaving contest, the goddess proves that ____ .",
      "answers": [
        "changing identity is easy",
        "goddess has the power to appear",
        "physical appearance is deceiving",
        "goddess is just like mortal woman"
      ],
      "correct": "physical appearance is deceiving"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which of the descriptions below best describes the goddess Aphrodite?",
      "answers": [
        "Goddess of wisdom and war who was the patron god of Athens",
        "Goddess of love and beauty who was married to Hephaestus",
        "Goddess of agriculture whose symbol was the pig",
        "Goddess of family and marriage who was queen of the gods"
      ],
      "correct": "Goddess of love and beauty who was married to Hephaestus"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "He is considered as the Mesopotamian great hero and son of goddess Ninsun whose stories are told in Sumerian and Babylonian poems.",
      "answers": [
        "Gilgamesh",
        "Enkidu",
        "Enuma Elish",
        "Anu"
      ],
      "correct": "Gilgamesh"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "To punish himself for murdering his father and having sexual relations with his mother, what did Oedipus do?",
      "answers": [
        "He killed himself",
        "He gouged his eyes",
        "He castrated himself.",
        "He ordered his sons to murder him"
      ],
      "correct": "He gouged his eyes"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "It is considered as the river of forgetfulness found in the Underworld.",
      "answers": [
        "Acheron",
        "Lethe",
        "Styx",
        "Phlegethon"
      ],
      "correct": "Lethe"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "In Hindu mythology, he is traditionally depicted with four heads, four faces and four arms. He also symbolizes the supreme eternal deity whose essence pervades the entire universe.",
      "answers": [
        "Brahma",
        "Vishnu",
        "Shiva",
        "Sarasvat"
      ],
      "correct": "Brahma"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which of the following creatures from Japanese folklore is known for its ability to shape- shift and often appears as a beautiful woman?",
      "answers": [
        "Tengu",
        "Kappa",
        "Kitsune",
        "Oni"
      ],
      "correct": "Kitsune"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Who died at the end of Iliad?",
      "answers": [
        "Achilles",
        "Agamemnon",
        "Hector",
        "Menelaus"
      ],
      "correct": "Hector"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the hero who sailed in the long ship Argo to search for the golden fleece?",
      "answers": [
        "Achilles",
        "Jason",
        "Paris",
        "Ulysses"
      ],
      "correct": "Jason"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "What does the crossroads represent in Oedipus the King?",
      "answers": [
        "Oedipus' fate, where he made a life changing decision",
        "the beginning of Oedipus' journey",
        "the ability of Oedipus to finally see the truth",
        "an interaction with the supernatural"
      ],
      "correct": "Oedipus' fate, where he made a life changing decision"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "What is the moral of the fable below? Four bulls were such great friends that they always ate together. A Lion watched them for many days with longing eyes, but since they were never far apart from each other, he was afraid to attack them. At length he succeeded in making them jealous of one another, and their jealousy eventually turned into a mutual aversion. When they stayed away from each other, the Lion fell upon them singly, and killed them all.",
      "answers": [
        "Only by working together can the greatest good for all be achieved.",
        "The enemy of my enemy is my friend.",
        "The quarrel of friends are the opportunities of enemies.",
        "Never underestimate the viciousness of your enemy."
      ],
      "correct": "The quarrel of friends are the opportunities of enemies."
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "What information can be inferred from the passage? To the ancient Egyptians, their ruler was both god and king, a descendant of the sun god, Ra. His power was absolute, and no one could question his decisions or repeal his judgments. Because the ruler was a god, no one was allowed to address him directly or to talk about him. Instead people called him pharaoh, meaning, \"the Great House.\"",
      "answers": [
        "A god has no name.",
        "A name demystifies a god.",
        "Ra is both god and human.",
        "A god has no address."
      ],
      "correct": "A name demystifies a god."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Philosophical-religious belief in reincarnation is based on which mythical character?",
      "answers": [
        "Orpheus",
        "Paris",
        "Achilles",
        "Agamemnon"
      ],
      "correct": "Orpheus"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Modern Cosmology is a speculative science which examines the beginning of the universe. Modern cosmology includes the Big Bang Theory. In Greek mythology, the universe was said to have started with Chaos. Out of Chaos emerged Gea, the goddess who represents the earth, Tartarus, representing the land of the dead, and Eros who represented desire. What can be said about the early Greeks regarding their belief about creation?",
      "answers": [
        "The early Greeks understand the concept of creation.",
        "The early Greeks associated creation in weaving stories of mythology.",
        "The early Greeks understand the importance of understanding the logic of creation.",
        "The early Greeks believe that creation is a product of mythology."
      ],
      "correct": "The early Greeks understand the concept of creation."
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "What does the presence of these three divinities: Clotho, Lachesis, and Atropos in Greek myth symbolize?",
      "answers": [
        "Immortals play a great part in mortal's life",
        "Destiny cannot be controlled by anyone",
        "Power of immortals over mortals",
        "Mortal's fate depends on the gods"
      ],
      "correct": "Destiny cannot be controlled by anyone"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "The story of Cupid and Psyche depicts undying love and devotion. What was Psyche's mistake that according to Cupid was a betrayal?",
      "answers": [
        "Psyche got infatuated with Zeus.",
        "Psyche believed her sisters persuasion that her lover was an ugly beast and would kill her.",
        "Psyche disobeyed her husband when she enlightened his face in the middle of the night.",
        "Psyche left the house without her husband permission."
      ],
      "correct": "Psyche disobeyed her husband when she enlightened his face in the middle of the night."
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "In the Chinese myth of the Monkey King, what does the monkey's journey to retrieve the Buddhist scriptures symbolize?",
      "answers": [
        "The search for enlightenment",
        "The importance of education",
        "The dangers of greed and ambition",
        "The power of friendship and loyalty"
      ],
      "correct": "The search for enlightenment"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "A traditional or legendary story, usually concerning some being or hero or event, with or without a determinable basis of fact or a natural explanation, especially one that is concerned with deities or demigods and explains some practice, rite, or phenomenon of nature.",
      "answers": [
        "Legend",
        "Myth",
        "Fable",
        "Folktale"
      ],
      "correct": "Myth"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "What group of twelve elder gods came before the Roman gods?",
      "answers": [
        "Celtics",
        "Ogres",
        "Cyclops",
        "Titans"
      ],
      "correct": "Titans"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "In the Middle Ages and Renaissance, it was commonly described as symbol of purity and grace, which could only be captured by a virgin.",
      "answers": [
        "Troll",
        "Dragon",
        "Kappa",
        "Unicorns"
      ],
      "correct": "Unicorns"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "What powerful god lived in the Underworld rather than on Mount Olympus?",
      "answers": [
        "Hades",
        "Poseidon",
        "Zeus",
        "Apollo"
      ],
      "correct": "Hades"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the Tagalog myth Malakas and Maganda?",
      "answers": [
        "The creation of bodies of water",
        "The creation of the universe",
        "The great flood",
        "The creation of mankind"
      ],
      "correct": "The creation of mankind"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "What is the primary symbolism of the Trojan Horse in the Trojan War?",
      "answers": [
        "It symbolizes deceit and betrayal.",
        "It symbolizes the cunning and intelligence of the Trojan warriors.",
        "It represents the strength and power of the Greek's army.",
        "It represents a gift of peace and friendship between the Greeks and Trojans."
      ],
      "correct": "It symbolizes deceit and betrayal."
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "According to the epic poem Enuma Elish, this Mesopotamian god leads the new gods in a battle against the old gods. After defeating the gods of chaos and gaining power of a supreme god, he creates the sky and earth, as well as the first human beings.",
      "answers": [
        "Tiamat",
        "Kingu",
        "Marduk",
        "Nabu"
      ],
      "correct": "Marduk"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "This is the attribution of a human form, human characteristics, or human behavior to nonhuman things, e.g. deities in mythology and animals in children's stories.",
      "answers": [
        "Anthropomorphism",
        "Ethereal",
        "God-like",
        "Anthropocentrism"
      ],
      "correct": "Anthropomorphism"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "According to the myth of Demeter and Persephone, the \"death\" of the world in winter comes about because of _____ .",
      "answers": [
        "the grief of Demeter for her lost daughter Persephone.",
        "the grief of Persephone for her mother.",
        "the anger of Hades toward Demeter.",
        "the anger of Demeter toward Hades."
      ],
      "correct": "the grief of Demeter for her lost daughter Persephone."
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
      "answers": [
        "Tall tales are funny stories written about ordinary people. People read the stories for entertainment, and relaxation.",
        "Tall tales are stories about extraordinary characters compared to people in real life. They are usually funny and entertaining.",
        "Tall tales are stories about characters who lived in the 18th century. They are based on real people, and are read with groups of people.",
        "Tall tales are true stories about extraordinary events that took place in America during the 18th century."
      ],
      "correct": "Tall tales are stories about extraordinary characters compared to people in real life. They are usually funny and entertaining."
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of Philippine Tall tale?",
      "answers": [
        "Ang Matsing at ang Pagong",
        "Si Malakas at Maganda",
        "Biag ni Lam-ang",
        "Ang Alamat ng Pinya"
      ],
      "correct": "Ang Matsing at ang Pagong"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "What is the usual pattern in flood myths? (I. Signs II. Survivors III. Size IV. Cause)",
      "answers": [
        "I, II, III, and IV",
        "IV, III, II and I",
        "I, IV, III, and II",
        "IV, I, III, IV"
      ],
      "correct": "IV, III, II and I"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "Whose wily mind thought of the stratagem of the wooden horse that is often alluded to have caused the Trojans' defeat against the Greeks?",
      "answers": [
        "Achilles",
        "Aeneas",
        "Menealus",
        "Odysseus"
      ],
      "correct": "Odysseus"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "She is a woman with snakes as hair and turned into stone whoever looked at her.",
      "answers": [
        "Helen",
        "Medea",
        "Lavinia",
        "Medusa"
      ],
      "correct": "Medusa"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "Hera is symbolized by what animal?",
      "answers": [
        "frog",
        "peacock",
        "pig",
        "sparrow"
      ],
      "correct": "peacock"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "The mythological background of the Trojan war is said to be caused by Paris, the prince of Troy. Eris, the goddess of discord, brought to a party a golden apple with an inscription - for the fairest. Hera,Athena and Aphrodite all made a quick claim on the apple. Fearing that he may anger any of the goddess, Zeus decided to send the three women to Paris. Each of the three goddesses offered a bribe to Paris: Hera promised him unlimited political power; Athena assured him that he would always be victorious in battle and Aphrodite offered him the most beautiful woman in the world, as his wife. Being young and romantic, he gave the apple to Aphrodite. Who was this beautiful woman offered to Paris as bribe?",
      "answers": [
        "Penelope, queen of Ithaca",
        "Persephone, queen of the underworld",
        "Helen of Troy",
        "Hera, queen of Olympus"
      ],
      "correct": "Helen of Troy"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "Which is the subject in Mythic history portrayed in \"Musee des Beaux Arts\" painting?",
      "answers": [
        "Daedalus and Icarus",
        "Iliad and Odyssues",
        "Farewell of Hector and Andromache",
        "Encounter with Polyphemus"
      ],
      "correct": "Daedalus and Icarus"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "When Oedipus learns the incredible truth about his mother and father, he puts out his own eyes and leaves his city to wander and eventually dies. This shows _______________ .",
      "answers": [
        "fate's control over human's lives",
        "regret and repentance to a wrong decision",
        "physical manifestation of the limitation of man",
        "acceptance of wrongdoing and self-punishment"
      ],
      "correct": "acceptance of wrongdoing and self-punishment"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a description of a creation myth?",
      "answers": [
        "Describes how the universe, earth, and life began",
        "Explains the workings of the natural world",
        "Supports and validates local laws",
        "Guides people through the trials of living"
      ],
      "correct": "Explains the workings of the natural world"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "She was the mother of all titans with her union with the Heavens.",
      "answers": [
        "Rhea",
        "Gaea",
        "Hera",
        "Aphrodite"
      ],
      "correct": "Gaea"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "What is the main theme of the epic of Gilgamesh?",
      "answers": [
        "The meaning of life, identity and relationship, and mortality and immortality.",
        "Love and friendship, fate and free will, and honor",
        "Believing in one's sacred duty called dharma",
        "Hospitality, Loyalty, and Vengeance"
      ],
      "correct": "The meaning of life, identity and relationship, and mortality and immortality."
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "Birth, death and after life are constant stories in the mythologies of the world. What universal idea about life is reflected in using these motifs?",
      "answers": [
        "That life has a beginning and an end.",
        "That life is a never ending cycle.",
        "That life is impermanent.",
        "That life is lived only once."
      ],
      "correct": "That life has a beginning and an end."
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "It is a mythical fire bird from ancient Egypt which is portrayed as a bird that dies in fire and is reborn of it.",
      "answers": [
        "Griffin",
        "Phoenix",
        "Unicorn",
        "Banshee"
      ],
      "correct": "Phoenix"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "What is the story of \"The Carabao and the Shell?\"",
      "answers": [
        "A carabao and a shell compete in a race, with the carabao using its strength to overcome obstacles and win.",
        "A carabao and a shell make unlikely friends, learning valuable lessons about cooperation and friendship.",
        "A carabao discovers a magical shell that grants wishes, leading to a series of adventures and misadventures.",
        "A carabao and a shell engage in a battle of wits, with each trying to outsmart the other to prove their superiority."
      ],
      "correct": "A carabao and a shell engage in a battle of wits, with each trying to outsmart the other to prove their superiority."
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "He was the Greek titan who swallowed all his children in order to prevent the fulfillment of an oracle.",
      "answers": [
        "Zeus",
        "Hades",
        "Uranus",
        "Cronus"
      ],
      "correct": "Cronus"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "He is perhaps the most popular god among the Scandinavians during the Viking Age. He is portrayed as unrelentingly pursuing his foes and with his mountain-crashing thunderous hammer Mjolnir in hand.",
      "answers": [
        "Odin",
        "Frigg",
        "Thor",
        "Loki"
      ],
      "correct": "Thor"
    }
  ],
  "PRINCIPLES & METHODS IN SLE": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Koa is a high school student who is very conscious of her language, both written and spoken. She self-corrects her errors, strives for grammatical accuracy, and sometimes hesitates or adjusts her speech to ensure correctness. How would Stephen Krashen's Monitor Hypothesis categorize Lorena's language learning behavior?",
      "answers": [
        "Under-User",
        "Optimal-User",
        "Over-User",
        "Smart-Use"
      ],
      "correct": "Over-User"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "he also encourages students to engage in active listening to music, songs, or any dialogues taking place in the classroom. What description best captures Teacher Peter's methods?",
      "answers": [
        "Cognitive code approach",
        "Cognitive code approach",
        "Counseling-learning approach",
        "Task-based language teaching"
      ],
      "correct": "Counseling-learning approach"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Which is the correct order of reading skills in Goodell's Reading Skills ladder? (I. Finding the main idea II. Basic sight words III. Vocabulary building IV. Using contextual clues V. Using structural analysis VI. Using phonetic analysis)",
      "answers": [
        "II, V, IV, I, III, VI",
        "II, I, IV, III, V, VI",
        "II, VI, V, IV, III, I",
        "II, III, VI, IV, V, I"
      ],
      "correct": "II, VI, V, IV, III, I"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which theory, supported by ancient philosophers Plato and Pythagoras, posits that the origin of speech lies in humans' attempts to imitate the inherent qualities of objects in their surroundings, suggesting that early vocalizations were harmonious with the natural world?",
      "answers": [
        "Bow-Wow Theory",
        "Ding-Dong Theory",
        "La-La Theory",
        "Pooh-Pooh Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Ding-Dong Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "According to Danish linguist Otto Jespersen, which types of sounds are theorized to have contributed to the development of language?",
      "answers": [
        "Bow-Wow Theory",
        "Ding-Dong Theory",
        "La-La Theory",
        "Pooh-Pooh Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "La-La Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Substituting different sounds for the first sound of familiar songs just like the example below can help in developing _____ . Row, row, row your boat Gently down the stream Merrily merrily, merrily, merrily Life is but a dream Bow, bow, bow your boat Bently bown the beam Berrily, berrily, berrily, berrily Life is but a dream",
      "answers": [
        "Phonological Awareness",
        "Word Recognition",
        "Phonological Stress",
        "Emergent Word Reading Skills"
      ],
      "correct": "Phonological Awareness"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Which theory suggests that the beginnings of human language can be traced back to instinctive vocalizations driven by emotions like pain, surprise, fear, or joy - essentially, that our first words were similar to involuntary exclamations?",
      "answers": [
        "Bow-Wow Theory",
        "Ding-Dong Theory",
        "La-La Theory",
        "Pooh-Pooh Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Pooh-Pooh Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Which theory proposes that human language arose from the sounds people made while engaged in physical labor - the heavy breathing, grunts, groans, and snorts that accompanied activities requiring significant exertion?",
      "answers": [
        "Yo-He-Yo Theory",
        "Ding-Dong Theory",
        "La-La Theory",
        "Pooh-Pooh Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Yo-He-Yo Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which of these is one of Halliday's functions of speech?",
      "answers": [
        "Instrumental",
        "Social",
        "Action",
        "Personal"
      ],
      "correct": "Instrumental"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "This type of language is used to describe the kind of language a learner uses at a given time, that is, his version of a given language, which deviates in certain ways from the language of a mature speaker.",
      "answers": [
        "Dialect",
        "Native Language",
        "Holophrasticspeech",
        "Interlanguage"
      ],
      "correct": "Interlanguage"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "In the American series, The 100, Octavia made a united clan called WonKru that discourages people from discriminating against each other based on their former clans. Whilst attacking anyone who is spreading hatred and going against the collective goals of the majority, Octavia asks each of her followers a simple question; \"You are Wonkru, or You are the enemy of WonKru. Choose!\" What fallacy is in the situation above?",
      "answers": [
        "Ad Hominem",
        "Red Herring",
        "Straw Man Fallacy",
        "False Dichotomy"
      ],
      "correct": "False Dichotomy"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Noam Chomsky argues that babies acquire language",
      "answers": [
        "because humans are born with the ability to learn language",
        "when caregivers speak softly to infants",
        "by watching adults interact",
        "by repeated exposure to sounds that have meaning"
      ],
      "correct": "because humans are born with the ability to learn language"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "A Filipino family migrated to the US. After 5 years, the child's accent is typically Filipino. He did not learn the accent of the Americans. When his mother was asked why his son did not acquire the accent and facility to communicate in English, the mother responded, \"He didn't want to mingle with other children in the US. He was always at home.\" What explains this phenomenon?",
      "answers": [
        "Accommodation Theory",
        "Monitor Model",
        "Nativization Model",
        "Discourse"
      ],
      "correct": "Accommodation Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which approach to grammar refers to the structure of a language as it is actually used by speakers and writers?",
      "answers": [
        "Reference Grammar",
        "Pedagogical Grammar",
        "Descriptive Grammar",
        "Prescriptive Grammar"
      ],
      "correct": "Descriptive Grammar"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "In the discussion regarding the nature-nurture debate related to language acquisition, Chomsky underscores ______ .",
      "answers": [
        "the 'harmony and mutual dependence' of nature and nurture",
        "the fundamental antagonism of nature and nurture",
        "the importance of nature over nurture",
        "the importance of nurture over nature"
      ],
      "correct": "the importance of nature over nurture"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Educators who exhibit self-confidence, maintain appropriate boundaries with their students, possess strong acting skills, and embody a positive attitude foster an authoritative presence. This can lead students to have more faith in their teachers than in their parents. Which method of language teaching does this scenario reflect?",
      "answers": [
        "Community Language Learning",
        "Audio-Lingual Method",
        "Suggestopedia",
        "Grammar Translation Method"
      ],
      "correct": "Suggestopedia"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Every time young Haley says the word 'teddy,' she is given her favorite stuffed bear, which reinforces her understanding and continued use of the word for getting the toy. According to behaviorist theory, this is an example of:",
      "answers": [
        "Operant conditioning",
        "Information processing",
        "Conditioned stimulus",
        "Repetitive-style language learning"
      ],
      "correct": "Operant conditioning"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "Regardless of culture, children begin to learn language around the same time all over the world. At about what age is this?",
      "answers": [
        "between 6 and 8 months",
        "between 8 and 28 months",
        "between 2 and 4 years",
        "between 5 and 7 years"
      ],
      "correct": "between 8 and 28 months"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Susie and Jen, identical twins, appear to speak and understand their own \"secret language\"; however, upon listening to them, their mother is unable to discern any consistency in the words and grammar they use. When she asks the girls, they reply that they change it whenever they feel like it. What characteristic of language does their \"language\" violate?",
      "answers": [
        "The language code is conventional.",
        "Language is a representational tool.",
        "Language is socially shared.",
        "Language is a code that uses a system of arbitrary symbols."
      ],
      "correct": "The language code is conventional."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "There are two sub-stages within this period. The first occurs between birth and 8 months. Most of this stage involves the baby relating to its surroundings and only during the 5/6 - 8 month period does the baby begin using its vocals. From 8 months to 12 months the baby gains more and more control over not only its vocal communication but also physical communication as well, for example, body language and gestures.",
      "answers": [
        "Babbling",
        "Holophrastic/One-word stage",
        "Two-word stage",
        "Telegraphic Stage"
      ],
      "correct": "Babbling"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "This stage is characterized by one word sentences. In this stage, nouns make up around 50% of the infant's vocabulary while verbs and modifiers make up around 30% and questions and negatives make up the rest.",
      "answers": [
        "Babbling",
        "Holophrastic/One-word stage",
        "Two-word stage",
        "Telegraphic Stage"
      ],
      "correct": "Holophrastic/One-word stage"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "This stage is called so because it resembles a telegram, providing only the essential information needed for the sentence to be understandable. At this point, you'll notice many three- and four word sentences. During this stage, the child starts to recognize the connections between words and objects, which can lead to overgeneralization.",
      "answers": [
        "Babbling",
        "Holophrastic/One-word stage",
        "Two-word stage",
        "Telegraphic Stage"
      ],
      "correct": "Telegraphic Stage"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Considering the intricate nature of linguistic analysis, which theoretical perspective posits that language can be dissected into a hierarchical system of interconnected components, functioning as \"building blocks\" for the construction of meaning, where these fundamental units comprise phonemes (the smallest units of sound), morphemes (the minimal units of meaning), and tagmemes (syntactic units encompassing phrases, clauses, and sentences), and how does this perspective contrast with other approaches to language study?",
      "answers": [
        "structuralists",
        "transformationalists",
        "functionalists",
        "interactionalists"
      ],
      "correct": "structuralists"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which of the following is a view of an interactionalist?",
      "answers": [
        "Language is primarily vocal.",
        "Language is creative.",
        "Language emphasizes the meaning and functions rather than the structures",
        "Language is a vehicle for establishing interpersonal relationships."
      ],
      "correct": "Language is a vehicle for establishing interpersonal relationships."
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "Which theory on language teaching has given birth to the methods that are learner- centered, allowing learner to work in pairs or groups in information gap tasks and problem-solving activities where such communication strategies as information sharing, negotiation of meaning, and interaction are used.",
      "answers": [
        "Structuralism",
        "Behaviorism",
        "Cognitivism",
        "Functionalism"
      ],
      "correct": "Functionalism"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "All of the following are implications of Krashen's Monitor Model EXCEPT _____ .",
      "answers": [
        "Teachers should correct errors during the time they are committed as error correction is valuable.",
        "Teachers should not insist on learners conversing before they feel comfortable in doing so.",
        "Teachers should not expect learners to learn \"late structures\" such as third person singular early.",
        "Teachers consider grammatical teaching is of limited value."
      ],
      "correct": "Teachers should correct errors during the time they are committed as error correction is valuable."
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "This view emphasizes that native language comprises habits that a second language learner must overcome. This is accomplished by forging new habits through repetition of pattern drills with accompanying positive reinforcement.",
      "answers": [
        "Behaviorist learning theory",
        "Cognitive learning theory",
        "Functional learning theory",
        "Holistic learning theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Behaviorist learning theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Which type of activity is highlighted in the following examples? Puppets, board games, picture dictation, speed dating, interviews",
      "answers": [
        "Interactive",
        "Generative",
        "Communicative",
        "Conversation games"
      ],
      "correct": "Communicative"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Which language function is expressed in the following statements? \"Assessments in most schools are segmented. There must be a well-crafted assessment tool to determine learning. Assessment tools must be standardized\"",
      "answers": [
        "Valuing",
        "Accommodating",
        "Invigorating",
        "Evaluating"
      ],
      "correct": "Evaluating"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "How do cognitivists such as Chomsky perceive the commission of error by learners?",
      "answers": [
        "Errors are indicators of failure to learn; thus should be right away eliminated.",
        "Error fosters wrong speech habits and should be stamped out by repeated drills and exercises.",
        "Errors are welcome in that they indicate what has been learned and what needs yet to be learned.",
        "Contrastive analysis before language teaching minimizes error occurrence."
      ],
      "correct": "Errors are welcome in that they indicate what has been learned and what needs yet to be learned."
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "Which of the following language teaching methods is NOT learner-centered in approach?",
      "answers": [
        "Content-Based Instruction",
        "Cooperative learning",
        "Task-Based Language Teaching",
        "Grammar Translation Method"
      ],
      "correct": "Grammar Translation Method"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "When you teach students to use words instead of those with distasteful or offensive effect like the \"grim reaper\" for death or \" crossing over\" for dying, you are teaching a lesson on _______ .",
      "answers": [
        "Existentialism",
        "Euphemism",
        "Localization",
        "Contextualization"
      ],
      "correct": "Euphemism"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "What approach might the teacher use when instructing her students to avoid using their native language and encouraging them to independently discover grammar rules while consistently speaking the target language?",
      "answers": [
        "Communicative",
        "Immersion",
        "Direct",
        "Audio-lingual"
      ],
      "correct": "Immersion"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "Considering the inherent complexities of human language acquisition, and acknowledging the diverse range of linguistic structures observed across various cultures, how can the theoretical construct of \"Universal Grammar\" be best defined, taking into account its postulated role as an innate, biologically determined system of principles that underlies the human capacity for language, and how does this concept address both the commonalities and variations observed in the world's languages?",
      "answers": [
        "language used for communication by people who speak different first languages",
        "rules applicable to all human languages",
        "language with the same vocabulary, grammar, and pronunciation",
        "rules of grammar that distinguish one language from the others"
      ],
      "correct": "rules applicable to all human languages"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "At the border of the two countries, there is a port where f ishermen work. The fishermen do not speak the same language, so they communicate using one that has been invented but only for trade. This scenario most accurately describes which of the following types of language?",
      "answers": [
        "a dialect",
        "a creole",
        "a pidgin",
        "a regionalism"
      ],
      "correct": "a pidgin"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "The multifaceted dynamics of acculturation and identity negotiation in second language acquisition, if a second language learner undergoes the process of \"assimilation,\" what does this imply regarding their relationship with both their original cultural group and the target language community, specifically in terms of the adoption or rejection of cultural values, behavioral norms, and social identities, and how does this process differ from other forms of acculturation, such as integration, marginalization, or separation?",
      "answers": [
        "maintains its own lifestyle and values and rejects those of the target language group",
        "adapts to the life style and values of the target language group but maintains its own life style and values for intragroup use.",
        "gives up his own lifestyle and values and adopts those of the target language group",
        "maximizes the use of his first language and the target language"
      ],
      "correct": "gives up his own lifestyle and values and adopts those of the target language group"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "The following are the areas of knowledge and skills of communicative competence EXCEPT _____",
      "answers": [
        "grammatical competence",
        "sociolinguistic competence",
        "discourse competence",
        "language competence"
      ],
      "correct": "language competence"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "Which is TRUE among the options below as you refer to the two given statements? He may leave tomorrow if he finishes his term paper. He will leave tomorrow if he finishes his term paper (I. The sentence may denote permission or possibility. II. The sentence with will simply describes a future event.III. The two sentences convey the same meaning. IV. Action in sentence 1 is conditional as stressed by the word \"if\")",
      "answers": [
        "II and IV",
        "I and III",
        "II, III",
        "I and II"
      ],
      "correct": "I and II"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "Content-Based Instruction (CBI) is based on the common underlying principle that successful language learning occurs when students are presented with target language material in a meaningful, contextualized form, with the primary focus on _____ .",
      "answers": [
        "understanding the lessons",
        "acquiring information and knowledge",
        "making connections between what they learn at school and what they learn outside the school",
        "making meaning from what they learn"
      ],
      "correct": "acquiring information and knowledge"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "It is a vocabulary strategy that involves the process of breaking up a word into its meaningful components: the root words, affixes, and suffixes.",
      "answers": [
        "contextual clues",
        "structural analysis",
        "summarizing",
        "groupings"
      ],
      "correct": "structural analysis"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "Teacher Beta employs an approach to learning the English language characterized by direct contact with the native speaker of the target language, which approach is it?",
      "answers": [
        "Immersion",
        "Transition",
        "Grammar Translation",
        "Audio-Aural"
      ],
      "correct": "Immersion"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "What method of language instruction stems from the behaviorist perspective that language learning involves developing a collection of correct language habits? This approach aims for communicative use of the target language, emphasizing overlearning to enable automatic usage.",
      "answers": [
        "Direct Method",
        "Communicative Approach",
        "Suggestopedia",
        "Audio-Lingual Method"
      ],
      "correct": "Audio-Lingual Method"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "Grammar may be taught in two main ways - by experience with discourse that entails the varieties of word forms and sentence construction, or by analyzing dummy sentences and diagramming parts. Plentiful discursive experience is what really teaches grammar, for it exercises judgment and provides language intake, whereas formal grammar study has been proved irrelevant. Politics more than pedagogy retards the changing of the curriculum to fit this truth.",
      "answers": [
        "using language in a wide variety of situations improves grammar",
        "good judgment can be improved by studying the rules of formal grammar",
        "analyzing and diagramming provide exercise in logical thinking",
        "formal study of grammar improves writing ability"
      ],
      "correct": "using language in a wide variety of situations improves grammar"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "Which among the following shows the first step of DRTA in the classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "Students read the first part of the selection based on the pre selected stopping point by the teacher.",
        "Students look at the cover of the book and tell what the story is all about.",
        "Students scan the text and find evidence that will help them make and prove their predictions.",
        "The students tell the teacher about the subject matter they want to read in the class."
      ],
      "correct": "Students look at the cover of the book and tell what the story is all about."
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "Which approach to grammar refers to the structure of a language as it is actually used by speakers and writers?",
      "answers": [
        "Reference Grammar",
        "Pedagogical Grammar",
        "Descriptive Grammar",
        "Prescriptive Grammar"
      ],
      "correct": "Descriptive Grammar"
    }
  ],
  "LANGUAGE, CULTURE, AND SOCIETY": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Where do most linguistic borrowings in modern English come from?",
      "answers": [
        "Latin and Greek",
        "Chinese and Japanese",
        "Arabic and Hebrew",
        "Swedish and Norwegian"
      ],
      "correct": "Latin and Greek"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "In the Kanzi experiment, what method was primarily used to communicate with the bonobo?",
      "answers": [
        "Spoken words, with Kanzi's response measured in vocalizations.",
        "Visual symbols, using a lexigram-based system.",
        "Written language, where Kanzi was taught to write human words.",
        "Gestural language, with Kanzi responding to human hand signs."
      ],
      "correct": "Visual symbols, using a lexigram-based system."
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "How does Hockett's cultural transmission explain the way humans learn language?",
      "answers": [
        "It suggests that language is passed down genetically, and humans are born with a specific linguistic capacity.",
        "It argues that language is learned through cultural interaction and socialization, rather than being biologically innate.",
        "It highlights that language is fixed and cannot evolve over time within any given culture.",
        "It implies that language is primarily individualistic and learned in isolation from the community."
      ],
      "correct": "It argues that language is learned through cultural interaction and socialization, rather than being biologically innate."
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which of the following best characterizes the main difference between mythological and scientific explanations of natural phenomena?",
      "answers": [
        "Mythological explanations are rooted in empirical observation and repeatable experiments, while scientific explanations are based on divine will and human imagination.",
        "Mythological explanations use symbolic and supernatural forces to explain events, while scientific explanations focus on natural laws and observable phenomena.",
        "Mythological explanations prioritize technological innovation, while scientific explanations are concerned with moral and ethical lessons.",
        "Mythological explanations seek to explain modern scientific concepts, while scientific explanations often rely on ancient storytelling traditions."
      ],
      "correct": "Mythological explanations use symbolic and supernatural forces to explain events, while scientific explanations focus on natural laws and observable phenomena."
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "A linguist is analyzing how oral traditions shape storytelling in indigenous cultures. Which of the following aligns most closely with Ethnopoetics?",
      "answers": [
        "A written transcript of an indigenous story arranges dialogue and rhythm to reflect how it was originally performed",
        "A historian translates oral stories into formal prose, ensuring they f it academic standards of storytelling",
        "A researcher ignores performance techniques, focusing only on the literal meanings of the words in oral narratives",
        "A poet rewrites indigenous myths using modern literary conventions to make them more accessible to contemporary readers"
      ],
      "correct": "A written transcript of an indigenous story arranges dialogue and rhythm to reflect how it was originally performed"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "A cognitive scientist is investigating how early humans developed language using an evolutionary framework. Which of the following would be the best explanation based on Darwinian principles?",
      "answers": [
        "Language emerged suddenly as a result of a genetic mutation that rewired the human brain for speech",
        "Language evolved gradually through natural selection, improving survival and social cooperation over generations",
        "Early humans acquired language by imitating animal calls, which eventually became structured into words and grammar",
        "The first languages developed from divine intervention, providing humans with a fully formed system of communication"
      ],
      "correct": "Language evolved gradually through natural selection, improving survival and social cooperation over generations"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "During an archaeological excavation, a researcher uncovers inscriptions in an ancient European language. To determine if the language is derived from Proto-Indo-European (PIE), which of the following characteristics would be the most decisive evidence?",
      "answers": [
        "The presence of grammatical cases and a system of verb conjugation based on aspect",
        "The use of runic script and strong-weak verb distinctions in conjugation",
        "The presence of extensive loanwords from Latin and Celtic languages",
        "The use of compounding as the primary method of word formation"
      ],
      "correct": "The presence of grammatical cases and a system of verb conjugation based on aspect"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "When did the Great Vowel Shift occur, leading to significant changes in English pronunciation?",
      "answers": [
        "During the Old English period",
        "At the turn of the 21st century",
        "After World War II",
        "During the 15th to 17th centuries"
      ],
      "correct": "During the 15th to 17th centuries"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "How does the distinction between a language and a dialect often depend on sociopolitical factors?",
      "answers": [
        "Linguistic features alone determine the distinction",
        "Sociopolitical factors play no role",
        "Power and prestige influence the classification",
        "Only historical context is considered"
      ],
      "correct": "Power and prestige influence the classification"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Who is most likely to facilitate linguistic borrowing between cultures?",
      "answers": [
        "Monolingual individuals",
        "International travelers and traders",
        "Local artisans",
        "Politicians and diplomats"
      ],
      "correct": "International travelers and traders"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "What was a significant finding from the Gua experiment with a chimpanzee raised by humans?",
      "answers": [
        "Gua could learn to communicate through spoken and written English after extended training with expert zoologists.",
        "Gua was able to perform complex tasks but never learned to understand human language.",
        "Gua exhibited some ability to understand human words but failed to produce human-like vocalizations.",
        "Gua communicated exclusively through physical gestures and did not respond to vocal commands."
      ],
      "correct": "Gua exhibited some ability to understand human words but failed to produce human-like vocalizations."
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Why is the classification of a speech form as a language rather than a dialect significant?",
      "answers": [
        "It affects the speakers' social status",
        "It simplifies linguistic studies",
        "It reduces the number of dialects globally",
        "It promotes equal linguistic rights"
      ],
      "correct": "It affects the speakers' social status"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "A linguist is studying the structure of Filipino Sign Language (FSL). Which of the following best describes its status and characteristics?",
      "answers": [
        "FSL is a direct manual translation of spoken Filipino, following the same grammar and sentence structures",
        "FSL is an artificial system created to help Deaf Filipinos learn English through manually coded gestures",
        "FSL is a simplified version of American Sign Language (ASL), used primarily for educational purposes in the Philippines",
        "FSL is a distinct natural language with its own grammar, influenced by American and Spanish Sign Languages"
      ],
      "correct": "FSL is a distinct natural language with its own grammar, influenced by American and Spanish Sign Languages"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "What does the concept of \"animal consciousness\" tell us about the potential for non-human animals to engage in complex language?",
      "answers": [
        "It shows that only humans are capable of high-level symbolic language use, as animals lack consciousness.",
        "It demonstrates that animals' emotions and social behaviors can be translated into complex grammatical structures like humans.",
        "It proves that all animals can learn and use human language through appropriate training.",
        "It suggests that cognitive structures in non-human animals may support basic communication but are not capable of human-like language."
      ],
      "correct": "It suggests that cognitive structures in non-human animals may support basic communication but are not capable of human-like language."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "How does linguistic borrowing typically affect a language over t ime?",
      "answers": [
        "It eliminates native words.",
        "It enriches the vocabulary.",
        "It causes grammatical errors.",
        "It restricts language evolution."
      ],
      "correct": "It enriches the vocabulary."
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Where is Beki Language/Swardspeak most commonly used in the Philippines?",
      "answers": [
        "In rural farming communities",
        "In informal social gatherings",
        "In government offices",
        "In academic dissertations"
      ],
      "correct": "In informal social gatherings"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "How do sociolinguistic studies help in understanding language variation?",
      "answers": [
        "By analyzing historical and political texts",
        "By studying fictional literature",
        "By focusing solely on written language",
        "By examining everyday speech patterns"
      ],
      "correct": "By examining everyday speech patterns"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "How does linguistic borrowing usually influence a language over t ime?",
      "answers": [
        "It simplifies the grammar rules for low-level learners",
        "It eliminates native words",
        "It enriches the vocabulary with new terms",
        "It restricts language evolution"
      ],
      "correct": "It enriches the vocabulary with new terms"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Which of the following criticisms of Otto Jespersen's language origin theory is most commonly discussed in linguistic studies?",
      "answers": [
        "The bow-wow theory lacks evidence of how animal sounds evolved into complex human language.",
        "The theory suggests language originated only in social contexts without considering physical anatomy.",
        "It overly emphasizes the role of syntax in language formation, neglecting vocabulary.",
        "It assumes that language is entirely an arbitrary social construct, ignoring natural influences."
      ],
      "correct": "The bow-wow theory lacks evidence of how animal sounds evolved into complex human language."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "A philosophy student is studying Aristotle's contributions to language theory. Which of the following best represents his approach to linguistics?",
      "answers": [
        "He viewed language as a purely arbitrary system, independent of logic and reality",
        "He developed the first formal rules of prescriptive grammar based on Latin models",
        "He argued that all languages share a deep, innate grammatical structure",
        "He emphasized the relationship between language, logic, and categorization of meaning"
      ],
      "correct": "He emphasized the relationship between language, logic, and categorization of meaning"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Who plays a critical role in revitalizing endangered languages?",
      "answers": [
        "Government officials exclusively",
        "Community members and linguistic activists",
        "Monolingual speakers who take care of their own dialects",
        "International tourists interested in learning ethnic languages"
      ],
      "correct": "Community members and linguistic activists"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Where is Colehiala English most frequently used?",
      "answers": [
        "In academic papers and theses",
        "In business correspondence",
        "In conversations among students at exclusive schools",
        "In public service announcements"
      ],
      "correct": "In conversations among students at exclusive schools"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "How do borrowed words often adapt to the borrowing language's phonological system?",
      "answers": [
        "They retain their original sounds entirely.",
        "They are replaced by native synonyms that retain their core meanings.",
        "They maintain the original spelling but not the pronunciation.",
        "They adapt phonologically to fit the borrowing language."
      ],
      "correct": "They adapt phonologically to fit the borrowing language."
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Why is it important to use inclusive language in policy-making documents?",
      "answers": [
        "To simplify the language used",
        "To appeal to a specific demographic",
        "To avoid alienating any group",
        "To increase the length of the document"
      ],
      "correct": "To avoid alienating any group"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "How does Yaya English contribute to the understanding of sociolects in the Philippines?",
      "answers": [
        "It highlights the influence of formal education only.",
        "It focuses on language use in government settings.",
        "It examines the interaction between employers and domestic helpers.",
        "It disregards social hierarchy impacts on language."
      ],
      "correct": "It examines the interaction between employers and domestic helpers."
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Where is the impact of ethnic identity on language most apparent?",
      "answers": [
        "In written legal documents for pro-nationalist groups",
        "In personal and community interactions",
        "In national news broadcasts",
        "In scientific journals with rigorous processes"
      ],
      "correct": "In personal and community interactions"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "A Deaf rights advocate is explaining the importance of recognizing sign languages as official languages. Which argument best supports this recognition?",
      "answers": [
        "Sign languages are just visual representations of spoken languages and should not be treated as separate languages",
        "Recognizing sign languages as official languages ensures accessibility and legal rights for Deaf communities",
        "Sign languages are universal, so making one official would benefit all Deaf people globally",
        "Spoken language interpreters can fully replace the need for official recognition of sign languages"
      ],
      "correct": "Recognizing sign languages as official languages ensures accessibility and legal rights for Deaf communities"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "In the context of animal language transmission, what does the social learning of chimpanzee gestures reveal about the nature of human language acquisition?",
      "answers": [
        "It suggests that humans acquire language strictly through biological programming, not by learning from others.",
        "It implies that human language is entirely based on visual communication, without any use of vocal sounds.",
        "It shows that humans, like chimpanzees, learn language through imitation and social interactions, which play a critical role in language development.",
        "It indicates that chimpanzees possess a more advanced form of language than humans, as they can learn to communicate using visual symbols more effectively."
      ],
      "correct": "It shows that humans, like chimpanzees, learn language through imitation and social interactions, which play a critical role in language development."
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "How does Halliday's imaginative function contribute to creative uses of language in human culture?",
      "answers": [
        "It allows individuals to use language for explaining the world and conveying objective facts in a neutral tone.",
        "It is focused on expressing emotions and social roles, facilitating interaction in personal and professional relationships.",
        "It enables language to be used in the creation of stories, poetry, and other forms of artistic expression, allowing for creativity and playfulness.",
        "It primarily serves to solve problems and aid in practical communication, like giving instructions or directions."
      ],
      "correct": "It enables language to be used in the creation of stories, poetry, and other forms of artistic expression, allowing for creativity and playfulness."
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "What was the primary goal of the Viki experiment involving a chimpanzee in the 1950s?",
      "answers": [
        "To explore whether a chimpanzee could learn to speak human like words and sounds.",
        "To teach Viki to communicate using visual symbols like American Sign Language.",
        "To examine whether Viki could understand complex grammatical structures in human speech.",
        "To test the ability of a chimpanzee to learn human-like vocalization through mimicry."
      ],
      "correct": "To explore whether a chimpanzee could learn to speak human like words and sounds."
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "How does Otto Jespersen's \"ding-dong theory\" explain the origin of language?",
      "answers": [
        "Language originated from a divine source, with humans naturally understanding words' meanings.",
        "Language evolved from the deliberate invention of abstract words and symbols.",
        "Language emerged from a combination of gestures and vocalizations in early human communication.",
        "Humans created language by associating sounds with objects based on their inherent qualities."
      ],
      "correct": "Humans created language by associating sounds with objects based on their inherent qualities."
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "In a study of semiotics, a researcher observes that a symbol in a public sign indicates a prohibition. What best explains this type of symbol?",
      "answers": [
        "It uses a natural connection between the sign and its meaning to convey a message",
        "It resembles the action it represents, making it an iconic sign",
        "It is arbitrary, with its meaning defined by social conventions and context",
        "It requires external cues to be understood, acting as an index of behavior"
      ],
      "correct": "It is arbitrary, with its meaning defined by social conventions and context"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "A researcher is analyzing how language influences cultural perception. Which scenario best supports the Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis?",
      "answers": [
        "A bilingual speaker easily translates abstract concepts between languages without any shift in meaning",
        "An indigenous group with no past-tense verbs in their language struggles to conceptualize historical events in the same way as English speakers",
        "A scientist discovers that brain structure, rather than language, determines how people think and perceive the world",
        "A global trade language develops, allowing speakers from diverse cultures to communicate without changing their worldviews"
      ],
      "correct": "An indigenous group with no past-tense verbs in their language struggles to conceptualize historical events in the same way as English speakers"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "A linguistics student encounters an unfamiliar Germanic language. Which of the following features would most likely indicate that the language is not closely related to English within the West Germanic branch?",
      "answers": [
        "It lacks vowel shifts similar to those found in the English Great Vowel Shif",
        "It uses strong and weak verb conjugations like English and German",
        "It shares basic vocabulary words like \"water\" (Wasser in German, water in English)",
        "It has grammatical gender for nouns, similar to German and Dutch"
      ],
      "correct": "It lacks vowel shifts similar to those found in the English Great Vowel Shif"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Why is it important to acknowledge dialect diversity within a single social class?",
      "answers": [
        "To eliminate language barriers",
        "To discourage regional accents",
        "To impose a uniform dialect",
        "To appreciate linguistic richness"
      ],
      "correct": "To appreciate linguistic richness"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "Where is it most appropriate to use formal language during a meeting?",
      "answers": [
        "Among close friends discussing plans",
        "At a casual family gathering",
        "During a professional business meeting",
        "While chatting with neighbors"
      ],
      "correct": "During a professional business meeting"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "How has bilingual education affected language use in the Philippines?",
      "answers": [
        "It has led to the extinction of regional dialects.",
        "It has decreased the usage of English in academic settings.",
        "It has increased proficiency in both Filipino and English.",
        "It has discouraged the learning of foreign languages as argued by globalist."
      ],
      "correct": "It has increased proficiency in both Filipino and English."
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "Where are language variations most likely to be preserved?",
      "answers": [
        "In multicultural urban centers",
        "In monolingual countries",
        "In isolated rural communities",
        "In standardized educational systems"
      ],
      "correct": "In isolated rural communities"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "How does the syntax of Old English differ from Modern English?",
      "answers": [
        "Old English uses a strict Subject-Verb-Object structure.",
        "Old English avoids the use of auxiliary verbs.",
        "Old English frequently employs inflectional endings and flexible word order.",
        "Old English relies on passive voice constructions."
      ],
      "correct": "Old English frequently employs inflectional endings and flexible word order."
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "A scholar is researching the effects of the Norman Conquest on the English language. Which of the following would be the most noticeable linguistic impact of this historical event?",
      "answers": [
        "The introduction of thousands of French words, particularly in law, government, and cuisine",
        "A complete shift from Germanic syntax to a Romance language structure",
        "The replacement of English with Latin as the dominant spoken language in England",
        "The simplification of English grammar due to the direct influence of Old Norse"
      ],
      "correct": "The introduction of thousands of French words, particularly in law, government, and cuisine"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "A linguist is examining Sir William Jones' impact on historical linguistics. Which discovery is most closely associated with his work?",
      "answers": [
        "The concept of a \"universal grammar\" underlying all human languages",
        "The relationship between Sanskrit, Greek, and Latin, forming the basis for Indo-European studies",
        "The distinction between langue (language system) and parole (speech acts) in structural linguistics",
        "The argument that languages evolve through social and political power structures rather than cognitive mechanisms"
      ],
      "correct": "The relationship between Sanskrit, Greek, and Latin, forming the basis for Indo-European studies"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "How does the Biblical account of creation in Genesis differ from modern scientific explanations of the origin of the universe?",
      "answers": [
        "The Biblical account presents creation as a direct act of God, while modern science explains the origin through the Big Bang theory.",
        "The Biblical account emphasizes the evolution of species over billions of years, while science suggests a young Earth.",
        "The Biblical account is focused on the gradual formation of the universe, whereas science claims it was an instantaneous event.",
        "The Biblical account suggests that humans evolved from lower species, while science argues that humans were created in their current form."
      ],
      "correct": "The Biblical account presents creation as a direct act of God, while modern science explains the origin through the Big Bang theory."
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "How does the \"gestural theory\" of language origin differ from other vocal-based theories like \"bow-wow\" and \"ding-dong\"?",
      "answers": [
        "The gestural theory suggests that humans initially communicated through gestures, and vocalization came later.",
        "The gestural theory proposes that language originated as a form of complex sign language.",
        "The gestural theory emphasizes the importance of vocal sounds that mimic the environment, not gestures.",
        "The gestural theory focuses on the emotional expression of human sounds rather than communication."
      ],
      "correct": "The gestural theory suggests that humans initially communicated through gestures, and vocalization came later."
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "How does the concept of Theory of Mind in animals relate to the evolution of language in humans?",
      "answers": [
        "It suggests that animals' ability to use gestures and signals evolved independently from human language.",
        "It proposes that humans are the only species capable of understanding the emotions and intentions of others, which is essential for language.",
        "It supports the idea that animals with theory of mind are more likely to develop symbolic communication systems similar to humans.",
        "It argues that animals' cognitive abilities are primarily designed for physical survival rather than communication."
      ],
      "correct": "It supports the idea that animals with theory of mind are more likely to develop symbolic communication systems similar to humans."
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "A linguist is studying the shift from Middle English to Early Modern English. Which of the following phonological changes would most strongly indicate this transition?",
      "answers": [
        "The loss of inflectional endings on most nouns and adjectives",
        "The Great Vowel Shift, which drastically altered the pronunciation of long vowels",
        "The simplification of strong verb conjugations in favor of weak verbs",
        "The introduction of new Latin and Greek loanwords through Renaissance scholarship"
      ],
      "correct": "The Great Vowel Shift, which drastically altered the pronunciation of long vowels"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "Why is language shift often observed along socioeconomic lines?",
      "answers": [
        "Wealthier communities prefer minority languages",
        "Minority languages are seen as socially prestigious",
        "Dominant languages offer better economic opportunities",
        "Socioeconomic status has no impact on language preference"
      ],
      "correct": "Dominant languages offer better economic opportunities"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "When do ethnic identity markers in speech become most prominent?",
      "answers": [
        "During casual conversations",
        "In standardized tests",
        "In translated literary works",
        "During formal debates"
      ],
      "correct": "During casual conversations"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "How does a politician's speech typically influence public opinion?",
      "answers": [
        "By providing detailed facts and figures",
        "By evoking emotions and shared values",
        "By ignoring existing societal issues",
        "By promoting personal achievements only"
      ],
      "correct": "By evoking emotions and shared values"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "Where is the basilect variety of Philippine English most likely to be found?",
      "answers": [
        "In academic and professional settings",
        "Among rural communities and informal urban settings",
        "In government and legal documents",
        "On national television news broadcasts"
      ],
      "correct": "Among rural communities and informal urban settings"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "Why is Grimm's Law considered fundamental in understanding the evolution of Germanic languages, including English?",
      "answers": [
        "It explains the origin of vowel changes.",
        "It highlights changes in word order.",
        "It outlines the adoption of foreign loanwords.",
        "It describes consistent consonant shifts."
      ],
      "correct": "It describes consistent consonant shifts."
    }
  ],
  "LC | CJ| TET | RIEI": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Poststructuralism refers to:",
      "answers": [
        "The idea that meaning is fixed and stable within a text",
        "The belief that texts have a single, authoritative interpretation according to literary experts",
        "The notion that meaning is fluid and constructed through language",
        "The emphasis on the historical context of a text"
      ],
      "correct": "The notion that meaning is fluid and constructed through language"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes a key concept in Critical Theory?",
      "answers": [
        "The idea that literature should be critically analyzed independently of its social context",
        "The belief that texts have a single, authoritative interpretation",
        "The focus on the formal elements and literary techniques of a text",
        "The examination of power structures and ideologies within a text"
      ],
      "correct": "The examination of power structures and ideologies within a text"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "__________ is best known for his critical edition of the Greek New Testament and his work \"In Praise of Folly.\"",
      "answers": [
        "John Locke",
        "Voltaire",
        "Denis Diderot",
        "Desiderius Erasmus"
      ],
      "correct": "Desiderius Erasmus"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which Enlightenment philosopher's work laid the foundation for modern political theory by advocating for the separation of powers in government?",
      "answers": [
        "Montesquieu",
        "John Locke",
        "Voltaire",
        "Immanuel Kant"
      ],
      "correct": "Montesquieu"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "W.E.B. Dubois : Ethnic Studies ; Joseph Campbell : _______",
      "answers": [
        "Psychoanalytical Criticism",
        "Cultural Materialism",
        "Feminist Criticism",
        "Archetypal Criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Archetypal Criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Which activity is most likely to occur during a literary discussion? A. Analyzing the use of symbolism in a poem",
      "answers": [
        "Analyzing the use of symbolism in a poem",
        "Debating different interpretations of a character's actions",
        "Writing a critical essay on a novel's themes",
        "Conducting a close reading of a specific passage"
      ],
      "correct": "Debating different interpretations of a character's actions"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "The concept of the \"anxiety of influence\" is developed by whom?",
      "answers": [
        "Harold Bloom",
        "Roland Barthes",
        "Edward Said",
        "Henry Louis Gates Jr."
      ],
      "correct": "Harold Bloom"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the narrative technique used in James Joyce's \"Ulysses\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Stream-of-consciousness",
        "Third-person omniscient",
        "Epistolary",
        "Free indirect discourse"
      ],
      "correct": "Stream-of-consciousness"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which literary movement is known for its focus on the depiction of everyday life and social issues?",
      "answers": [
        "Surrealism",
        "Modernism",
        "Realism",
        "Romanticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Realism"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "What is the term for the line in a newspaper article that tells who wrote it?",
      "answers": [
        "Headline",
        "Byline",
        "Dateline",
        "Caption"
      ],
      "correct": "Byline"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "A reporter's regular routine for covering news sources refers to:",
      "answers": [
        "Lead",
        "Assignment",
        "Features",
        "Beat"
      ],
      "correct": "Beat"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Kevin, a campus journalist, has been asked to write an editorial about a recent event on campus. What is the main purpose of an editorial?",
      "answers": [
        "To present an objective report of the event",
        "To present the newspaper's opinion on the event",
        "To present a personal opinion on the event",
        "To present a summary of the event with engaging language"
      ],
      "correct": "To present the newspaper's opinion on the event"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Roy is a campus journalist and he has been asked to write an article that covers a recent event on campus. What type of news article should he write?",
      "answers": [
        "Feature Article",
        "Review",
        "Editorial",
        "News Article"
      ],
      "correct": "News Article"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "How does media ownership influence the content and perspective of news coverage?",
      "answers": [
        "It ensures that all news coverage is unbiased and objective",
        "It has no impact on the content and perspective of news coverage",
        "It can lead to the promotion of specific agendas and viewpoints",
        "It guarantees that all viewpoints are equally represented"
      ],
      "correct": "It can lead to the promotion of specific agendas and viewpoints"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "How should the editorial board handle conflicts of interest among its members?",
      "answers": [
        "Ignoring conflicts of interest to maintain harmony",
        "Allowing members with conflicts of interest to participate in related decisions",
        "Requiring members to disclose conflicts of interest and recuse themselves from related decisions",
        "Delegating conflict resolution to the faculty advisor"
      ],
      "correct": "Requiring members to disclose conflicts of interest and recuse themselves from related decisions"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "As a campus journalist, Carlos has been asked to cover a controversial event on campus. How should he approach this task according to the principles of campus journalism in the Philippines?",
      "answers": [
        "Write an article that supports your personal opinion on the issue",
        "Write an article that supports the majority opinion on campus",
        "Write an article that presents all sides of the issue objectively",
        "Refuse to cover the issue because it's controversial"
      ],
      "correct": "Write an article that presents all sides of the issue objectively"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "The law that protects and promotes the rights and campus journalists in the Philippines.",
      "answers": [
        "RA 7079",
        "RA 8190",
        "RA 7722",
        "RA 7836"
      ],
      "correct": "RA 7079"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "What was the first university to offer a course in journalism?",
      "answers": [
        "Harvard University",
        "University of Missouri",
        "Columbia University",
        "Yale University"
      ],
      "correct": "University of Missouri"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Which of the following translation approaches involves altering the source text so that it corresponds to the culture, style, grammar, semantics, and syntax of the target language?",
      "answers": [
        "Literal translation",
        "Dynamic equivalence",
        "Functional equivalence",
        "Adaptation"
      ],
      "correct": "Adaptation"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a principle of editing and translation?",
      "answers": [
        "Creativity",
        "Clarity",
        "Accuracy",
        "Consistency"
      ],
      "correct": "Creativity"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "What is the translation technique that involves translating each word separately without considering how the words are used together in a phrase or sentence?",
      "answers": [
        "Literal translation",
        "Dynamic equivalence",
        "Adaptation",
        "Compensation"
      ],
      "correct": "Literal translation"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Oral translation also pertains to:",
      "answers": [
        "Interpretation",
        "Calque",
        "Vocalization",
        "Phonemization"
      ],
      "correct": "Interpretation"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Domeng is translating a short story from Spanish to English for a class assignment. The story contains a reference to a popular Spanish TV show that is not well-known in the English-speaking world. How should he handle this cultural reference in your translation?",
      "answers": [
        "Modify it",
        "Preserve it",
        "Explain it",
        "Omit it"
      ],
      "correct": "Explain it"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "What is one of the benefits of using translation materials for bilingual classrooms?",
      "answers": [
        "They can adapt the linguistic and cultural needs of the students.",
        "They can enhance the language skills and intercultural competence of the students.",
        "They can measure the learning outcomes and evaluate the performance of the students",
        "They can motivate the interest and engagement of the students in the learning process."
      ],
      "correct": "They can enhance the language skills and intercultural competence of the students."
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "What is the term for the social phenomenon that occurs when a language or a culture dominates and influences other languages or cultures through translation?",
      "answers": [
        "Translation power",
        "Translation loss",
        "Translation gap",
        "Translation shif"
      ],
      "correct": "Translation power"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Which technique involves changing the perspective or point of view of a word or phrase from the source language to the target language, without altering its meaning?",
      "answers": [
        "Modulation",
        "Equivalence",
        "Adaptation",
        "Compensation"
      ],
      "correct": "Modulation"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "Which technique involves recreating elements of the source text that have been lost during translation in the target text in a similar way to make up for semantic losses?",
      "answers": [
        "Borrowing",
        "Calque",
        "Literal translation",
        "Compensation"
      ],
      "correct": "Compensation"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Which approach is often used in early intervention for language learning difficulties?",
      "answers": [
        "Rote memorization",
        "Multisensory techniques",
        "Standardized testing",
        "Group therapy sessions"
      ],
      "correct": "Multisensory techniques"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Ms. Reyes wants to enhance her students' writing skills by encouraging a deep understanding of language structures. Which strategy would best support her goal in a secondary English language classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "Conducting explicit instruction on the writing process stages",
        "Providing graphic organizers for planning writing tasks",
        "Modeling effective sentence structures through examples",
        "Focusing on the final product to motivate students"
      ],
      "correct": "Modeling effective sentence structures through examples"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "What is a common strategy in early intervention for language learning difficulties?",
      "answers": [
        "Ignoring signs of learning difficulties in young learners.",
        "Waiting until the end of the school year to address learning concerns.",
        "Identifying and addressing learning difficulties as early as possible.",
        "Excluding young learners from classroom activities."
      ],
      "correct": "Identifying and addressing learning difficulties as early as possible."
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "What is an example of integrating technology in a remedial program for a student with dyslexia?",
      "answers": [
        "Giving the student more online homework",
        "Using text-to-speech tools",
        "Requiring the student to participate in online forums",
        "Limiting the student's use of technology"
      ],
      "correct": "Using text-to-speech tools"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "Ana often has trouble expressing her thoughts during oral recitations, but she understands her lessons well. What learning difficulty might Ana be experiencing?",
      "answers": [
        "Expressive Language Disorder",
        "Dyscalculia",
        "Dyslexia",
        "Dyspraxia"
      ],
      "correct": "Expressive Language Disorder"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "Luisa, a student in your class, often struggles with writing tasks. She has difficulty with spelling, grammar, and putting her thoughts into writing. What learning difficulty might Luisa be experiencing?",
      "answers": [
        "Dyslexia",
        "Dysgraphia",
        "Dyscalculia",
        "Expressive Language Disorder"
      ],
      "correct": "Dysgraphia"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "What is the primary purpose of differentiated instruction in an inclusive classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "Promoting a one-size-fits-all approach to teaching.",
        "Providing identical learning experiences for all students.",
        "Tailoring instruction to meet the unique needs of each student.",
        "Excluding certain students from the learning process."
      ],
      "correct": "Tailoring instruction to meet the unique needs of each student."
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "What is 'mastery learning' in remedial instruction?",
      "answers": [
        "Learning multiple subjects at once",
        "Achieving a high level of understanding before moving on",
        "Mastering teaching techniques",
        "Learning at a rapid pace"
      ],
      "correct": "Achieving a high level of understanding before moving on"
    }
  ],
  "INSTRUCTION AND EARLY INTERVENTION": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Adrian often repeats the words his sister tells him especially when he's getting scolded. What is the likely problem of this student?",
      "answers": [
        "Dyslexia",
        "Reduplication",
        "Autism",
        "Echolalia"
      ],
      "correct": "Echolalia"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "What does 'early intervention' aim to do in the context of language learning difficulties?",
      "answers": [
        "Address difficulties as soon as they are identified",
        "Intervene in family matters to prevent potential school dropouts",
        "Start teaching languages at a young age",
        "Intervene in every aspect of a child's life"
      ],
      "correct": "Address difficulties as soon as they are identified"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "What is the primary goal of remedial instruction in language learning?",
      "answers": [
        "To accelerate learning",
        "To identify learning styles",
        "To diagnose disorders",
        "To enhance memory skills"
      ],
      "correct": "To accelerate learning"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "How does technology contribute to supporting diverse learners in an inclusive classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "Restricting access to tools and resources for specific students.",
        "Providing uniform tools and resources for all students.",
        "Offering tools and resources that cater to diverse learning needs.",
        "Fostering dependency and limiting independent learning."
      ],
      "correct": "Offering tools and resources that cater to diverse learning needs."
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Sara Terterdu finds it difficult to follow the orders given to her by Bingbing Cosmar. Which language learning difficulty does this refer to?",
      "answers": [
        "ASD",
        "ADHD",
        "APD",
        "Egocentrism"
      ],
      "correct": "APD"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "In a writing class where students have varying writing abilities, the teacher decides to employ a strategy that tailors instruction to meet the unique needs of each student. What instructional approach is the teacher likely using?",
      "answers": [
        "Individualized Instruction",
        "Feedback and Revision",
        "Process Writing",
        "Modeling"
      ],
      "correct": "Individualized Instruction"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Which of the following is not an ethical consideration in remedial instruction and early intervention?",
      "answers": [
        "Respect for diversity",
        "Confidentiality",
        "Professional conduct",
        "Favoritism"
      ],
      "correct": "Favoritism"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Anthony pouts his lips three times while in front of Maris Raquel. But Maris carries on with her small talk. What does this likely demonstrate?",
      "answers": [
        "Nonchalance",
        "NVLD",
        "LPD",
        "Cerebral Palsy"
      ],
      "correct": "NVLD"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Teacher Gee observes that a student with language learning difficulties is often hesitant to participate in class discussions. What ethical consideration should the teacher prioritize to address this situation?",
      "answers": [
        "Providing confidential information to classmates to encourage understanding.",
        "Promoting respectful and inclusive participation without singling out the student.",
        "Avoiding collaboration with special education teachers to maintain confidentiality.",
        "Advocating for a separate classroom for students with language learning difficulties."
      ],
      "correct": "Promoting respectful and inclusive participation without singling out the student."
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "In a writing class, the teacher decides to focus on teaching grammar rules, sentence structure, paragraph structure, and the use of descriptive language to improve students' writing skills. What instructional approach is the teacher employing?",
      "answers": [
        "Process Writing",
        "Modeling",
        "Use of Technology",
        "Explicit Instruction"
      ],
      "correct": "Explicit Instruction"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Which is not a common sign of language-learning difficulty in children?",
      "answers": [
        "Difficulty following directions",
        "Excessive talking",
        "Limited vocabulary",
        "Difficulty forming sentences"
      ],
      "correct": "Excessive talking"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Teacher K is planning to differentiate instruction in her remedial program. What might this involve?",
      "answers": [
        "Teaching the same content to all students",
        "Offering extension activities for ready students",
        "Ignoring the learning profiles of students",
        "Focusing only on the strongest students"
      ],
      "correct": "Offering extension activities for ready students"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Mr. Tan is working with a student who consistently struggles with completing writing tasks independently. The student often gets overwhelmed during the revising and editing stages. What approach would be most beneficial for the student in this situation?",
      "answers": [
        "Providing explicit instruction on grammar rules and sentence structure",
        "Encouraging the use of graphic organizers for brainstorming",
        "Modeling effective revising and editing strategies",
        "Focusing on the final product to motivate independent work"
      ],
      "correct": "Modeling effective revising and editing strategies"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Teacher M is implementing a remedial program and notices that a student is struggling to understand a concept despite several explanations. What strategy should the teacher try next?",
      "answers": [
        "Move on to the next concept",
        "Give the student additional homework",
        "Reteach the concept using a different learning modality",
        "Ask the student to teach the concept to the class 15.What is the benefit of slowing down the original lesson in a remedial program?"
      ],
      "correct": "Reteach the concept using a different learning modality"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "What is the benefit of slowing down the original lesson in a remedial program?",
      "answers": [
        "To fill up the class time",
        "To give students more time to absorb the material",
        "To make the lesson easier for the teacher",
        "To ensure that all students finish the lesson at the same time"
      ],
      "correct": "To give students more time to absorb the material"
    }
  ],
  "STRUCTURE OF ENGLISH": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "How does split negation differ from parallel negation in terms of sentence structure?",
      "answers": [
        "Split negation places both negation elements together.",
        "Parallel negation distributes negation across multiple clauses.",
        "Split negation separates the negation elements within the clause.",
        "Parallel negation is only found in interrogative sentences."
      ],
      "correct": "Split negation separates the negation elements within the clause."
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Where is coordination most commonly found in sentence structure?",
      "answers": [
        "Between a noun and an adjective",
        "Between the ass cheeks",
        "Inside prepositional phrases",
        "Between two main clauses"
      ],
      "correct": "Between two main clauses"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Which sentence correctly uses a dash?",
      "answers": [
        "I went to the store-but forgot my wallet.",
        "The meeting will be held on Tuesday - we'll discuss the new project.",
        "She was tired- so she decided to rest.",
        "I will see you later- at the park."
      ],
      "correct": "I went to the store-but forgot my wallet."
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences demonstrates the correct use of a gerund as a direct object?",
      "answers": [
        "She enjoys to read novels.",
        "He started reading the book.",
        "They will go swimming tomorrow.",
        "Swimming is what I like on weekends."
      ],
      "correct": "He started reading the book."
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Which of the following demonstrates an adjective modifying a noun in a specific position as per standard English rules?",
      "answers": [
        "He is a tall and strong athlete.",
        "He is an athlete tall and strong.",
        "He is tall and strong athlete.",
        "He is an athlete strong and tall."
      ],
      "correct": "He is a tall and strong athlete."
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Which of the following is in the objective case?",
      "answers": [
        "Their",
        "We",
        "Yours",
        "Me"
      ],
      "correct": "Me"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "When is parallel structure in negation most effectively used?",
      "answers": [
        "In contexts demanding clear, unambiguous negation",
        "In poetic and figurative language",
        "In legal documents to reduce readability",
        "In informal spoken language"
      ],
      "correct": "In contexts demanding clear, unambiguous negation"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Which punctuation is used to separate items in a list when the items contain commas?",
      "answers": [
        "Comma (,)",
        "Semicolon (;)",
        "Hyphen (-)",
        "Ass (  )(  )"
      ],
      "correct": "Semicolon (;)"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "In an English class, a student says, \"The team are winning.\" Is this sentence grammatically correct?",
      "answers": [
        "Yes, because 'team' is a collective noun and can take a plural verb.",
        "No, because 'team' is a singular noun and should take a singular verb.",
        "Yes, because 'team' is a collective noun and can take a plural verb if the individuals within the group are acting separately.",
        "No, because 'team'  is not eating my ass."
      ],
      "correct": "Yes, because 'team' is a collective noun and can take a plural verb if the individuals within the group are acting separately."
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Who is likely to analyze parallel structure in negation when studying syntax?",
      "answers": [
        "Syntaxists",
        "Syntaxocologists",
        "Syntaxers",
        "Syntacticians"
      ],
      "correct": "Syntacticians"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Why is it important to understand the structure of correlation in syntactic analysis?",
      "answers": [
        "To enhance word formation and its implications for sentence building",
        "To identify phonetic variations amidst the complexity of sentence structures",
        "To improve the understanding of sentence complexity and meaning",
        "To enforce language standardization"
      ],
      "correct": "To improve the understanding of sentence complexity and meaning"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Why is it important to understand the structure of subordination in syntax?",
      "answers": [
        "To simplify writing styles for early grade students",
        "To enhance sentence clarity and cohesiveness",
        "To reduce the length of sentences",
        "To eliminate the need for punctuation, making the sentence f low more smoothly"
      ],
      "correct": "To enhance sentence clarity and cohesiveness"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "\"Sara gives Bongbong a flying kiss.\" What syntactic structure is demonstrated?",
      "answers": [
        "Subordination",
        "Coordination",
        "Predication",
        "Correlation"
      ],
      "correct": "Predication"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "A teacher asks students to choose a sentence with a verb phrase in the passive voice. Which option is correct?",
      "answers": [
        "The cake was being decorated.",
        "The chef decorated the cake.",
        "The cake smells delicious.",
        "The baker is decorating the cake."
      ],
      "correct": "The cake was being decorated."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Which sentence uses a period incorrectly?",
      "answers": [
        "She enjoyed the concert although it was expensive.",
        "I will meet my sister-in-law at the park tomorrow.",
        "Lisa said, \"Get the hell out of here!\"",
        "It was in the 90's when everything was fun."
      ],
      "correct": "It was in the 90's when everything was fun."
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Which of the following pairs contains coordinating conjunctions?",
      "answers": [
        "Neither...nor, either...or",
        "But, and",
        "Although, because",
        "If, then"
      ],
      "correct": "But, and"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Which of the following correctly demonstrates the use of a correlative conjunction?",
      "answers": [
        "He is tired but nevertheless determined to finish.",
        "I will either visit the museum or the park.",
        "She was happy because she won.",
        "I love both cats and dogs."
      ],
      "correct": "I will either visit the museum or the park."
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct conjugation of the verb \"to sing\" in the present perfect tense?",
      "answers": [
        "I have sung the song already.",
        "I have sang the song already.",
        "I have been singing the song since yesterday.",
        "I am singing the song."
      ],
      "correct": "I have sung the song already."
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Choose the sentence that correctly uses a preposition of time.",
      "answers": [
        "She will arrive on Friday morning.",
        "He walked towards the rocky beach.",
        "The cat is under the table in the corner.",
        "They arrived at the station from the airport."
      ],
      "correct": "She will arrive on Friday morning."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Which sentence uses an adverb of frequency correctly?",
      "answers": [
        "He always forgets to call me.",
        "She eats hardly vegetables.",
        "They have sometimes meetings at noon.",
        "We are seeing rarely the sun these days."
      ],
      "correct": "He always forgets to call me."
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Which sentence uses an adverb of time correctly?",
      "answers": [
        "I have already completed the assignment.",
        "She is singing beautifully every night.",
        "The children played loudly in the park.",
        "The event will take place before the meeting."
      ],
      "correct": "I have already completed the assignment."
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Where is split structure commonly found in negation?",
      "answers": [
        "In simple, single-clause sentences that indicate disappointment",
        "In sentences using multiple negation markers",
        "In subordinate clauses with subjects of ill repute",
        "In sentences devoid of auxiliary verbs"
      ],
      "correct": "In sentences using multiple negation markers"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "When is the use of infinitive complement clauses particularly common?",
      "answers": [
        "In casual spoken language",
        "In formal academic writing",
        "In legal documents",
        "In poetic expressions"
      ],
      "correct": "In formal academic writing"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences best represents an unreal conditional?",
      "answers": [
        "If he trains hard, he will win the championship.",
        "If she were taller, she could be a model.",
        "If they finish early, they can watch the movie.",
        "If the weather improves, we might go hiking."
      ],
      "correct": "If she were taller, she could be a model."
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "A writer wants to add an adjective phrase to modify \"a woman\" in the sentence: \"I saw a woman ______.\" Which option correctly completes the sentence?",
      "answers": [
        "running through the park",
        "with long, flowing hair",
        "who sings beautifully",
        "in the morning"
      ],
      "correct": "with long, flowing hair"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "How does the use of an interjection change the tone of the sentence?",
      "answers": [
        "It adds a formal tone.",
        "It emphasizes the speaker's emotions or reactions.",
        "It makes the sentence more neutral.",
        "It clarifies the meaning of the sentence."
      ],
      "correct": "It emphasizes the speaker's emotions or reactions."
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "\"I can't believe you're here!\" What type of sentence is this?",
      "answers": [
        "Exclamatory",
        "Exclamation",
        "Surprising",
        "Disbelief"
      ],
      "correct": "Exclamatory"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Which sentence is an example of a complex sentence?",
      "answers": [
        "She opened the door and left the room.",
        "After the rain stopped, we went for a walk.",
        "He enjoys playing basketball.",
        "The teacher spoke loudly in the classroom."
      ],
      "correct": "After the rain stopped, we went for a walk."
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "What is the difference between a clause and a phrase?",
      "answers": [
        "A clause is a group of words without a subject-verb component, while a phrase is a group of words containing a subject and verb.",
        "A clause is a group of words containing a subject and verb, while a phrase is a group of words without a subject-verb component.",
        "A clause and a phrase both do not have a subject and predicate.",
        "A clause and a phrase both contain a subject and verb."
      ],
      "correct": "A clause is a group of words containing a subject and verb, while a phrase is a group of words without a subject-verb component."
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a collective noun?",
      "answers": [
        "Team",
        "Flock",
        "Quickly",
        "Bunch"
      ],
      "correct": "Quickly"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "Troupe : Performers ; _______ : Fleas",
      "answers": [
        "Troop",
        "Swarm",
        "Band",
        "Loveliness"
      ],
      "correct": "Swarm"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "\"It's nice to finally meet you.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Negation",
        "Modification",
        "Parallelism",
        "Complementation"
      ],
      "correct": "Complementation"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "How does adjectival modification affect the syntactic structure of a noun phrase?",
      "answers": [
        "It changes the number of the noun and its modifiers.",
        "It limits the noun's role in the sentence.",
        "It adds descriptive information about the noun.",
        "It alters the case of the noun, expanding its scope."
      ],
      "correct": "It adds descriptive information about the noun."
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences is a compound-complex sentence?",
      "answers": [
        "Although she was tired, she stayed up late, and she finished the project.",
        "Thinking about his next lunch, Adrian finished his homework before going out.",
        "The sun sets in the west, and the stars appear, shining like diamonds.",
        "The children played in the park all afternoon."
      ],
      "correct": "Although she was tired, she stayed up late, and she finished the project."
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "A student is asked to identify the adjective phrase in the sentence: \"The house with the red door is my favorite.\" What should the student answer?",
      "answers": [
        "\"The house is my favorite\"",
        "\"With the red door\"",
        "\"My favorite\"",
        "\"The house\""
      ],
      "correct": "\"With the red door\""
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "In which sentence is the verb used as a linking verb?",
      "answers": [
        "She feels tired after the workout.",
        "He runs every morning to keep a healthy lifestyle.",
        "I will cook dinner tonight for my baby.",
        "They have completed the project."
      ],
      "correct": "She feels tired after the workout."
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences uses the correct conjugation of the verb \"to have\" in the future perfect tense?",
      "answers": [
        "I will have finished my homework by tomorrow.",
        "I have finished my homework by tomorrow.",
        "I had finished my homework by tomorrow.",
        "I will finish my homework by tomorrow."
      ],
      "correct": "I will have finished my homework by tomorrow."
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "A student needs to choose the correct noun phrase in the sentence: \"The small red ball bounced across the floor.\" Which option is correct?",
      "answers": [
        "\"The small red\"",
        "\"The ball bounced\"",
        "\"The small red ball\"",
        "\"Bounced across the floor\""
      ],
      "correct": "\"The small red ball\""
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "I. chair II. child III. criterion IV. crisis Which is different?",
      "answers": [
        "II",
        "I",
        "IV",
        "III"
      ],
      "correct": "I"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "Which sentence uses a noun in the genitive case?",
      "answers": [
        "I walked to the park.",
        "The girl's bicycle is missing.",
        "He went to the bank yesterday.",
        "The teacher gave us homework."
      ],
      "correct": "The girl's bicycle is missing."
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "Which type of sentence would you use to express your opinion about a movie you watched?",
      "answers": [
        "Declarative Sentence",
        "Interrogative Sentence",
        "Imperative Sentence",
        "Exclamatory Sentence"
      ],
      "correct": "Declarative Sentence"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "Which sentence uses a demonstrative pronoun correctly?",
      "answers": [
        "This is the book I borrowed from the library.",
        "She gave me this book yesterday.",
        "He has those ideas in his notebook.",
        "That were my favorite shoes."
      ],
      "correct": "This is the book I borrowed from the library."
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "A student wants to add a noun phrase to complete the sentence \"She bought ______.\" Which option is correct?",
      "answers": [
        "a beautiful new dress",
        "very quickly that cute puppy",
        "at the store without her wallet",
        "with a smile"
      ],
      "correct": "a beautiful new dress"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "Which sentence demonstrates the correct use of a noun in the vocative case?",
      "answers": [
        "Hey, John, can you help me with this?",
        "I saw Sarah yesterday vocalizing before her performance.",
        "The teacher gave us instructions.",
        "He voiced out his thoughts passionately."
      ],
      "correct": "Hey, John, can you help me with this?"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences contains a noun of direct address?",
      "answers": [
        "John, could you please close the door?",
        "John closes the door every time you leave.",
        "John is closing the door, but Joe is opening it.",
        "John can close the door, can he?"
      ],
      "correct": "John, could you please close the door?"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "Which sentence correctly follows the grammatical pattern of a second conditional?",
      "answers": [
        "If he studied harder, he will pass the test.",
        "If she had known the answer, she would have told me.",
        "If I were you, I would take the opportunity.",
        "If they call us, we would answer immediately."
      ],
      "correct": "If I were you, I would take the opportunity."
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "A teacher wants to test students on prepositional phrases by asking which sentence contains one. Which option is correct?",
      "answers": [
        "She quickly walked away.",
        "They arrived late last night.",
        "We met at the park.",
        "He sings beautifully."
      ],
      "correct": "We met at the park."
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "Which sentence contains a compound sentence structure?",
      "answers": [
        "I wanted to go swimming, but the pool was closed.",
        "Because I missed the train, I was late to the meeting.",
        "She read a book while waiting for the bus.",
        "If it rains, we will stay inside."
      ],
      "correct": "I wanted to go swimming, but the pool was closed."
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "What does the relative pronoun 'whose' indicate?",
      "answers": [
        "It refers to a person (as the verb's object).",
        "It refers to an animal or thing.",
        "It shows possession.",
        "It applies universally to a number of people or things."
      ],
      "correct": "It shows possession."
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "Adrian responds by saying \"Yes\" or \"No\" to the teacher. What do you call Adrian's response?",
      "answers": [
        "Nonchalance",
        "Holophrase",
        "Uniresponsum",
        "Simple sentence"
      ],
      "correct": "Holophrase"
    }
  ],
  "INTRODUCTION TO LINGUISTICS": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "During a business meeting, someone says, \"Let's not beat around the bush.\" What does this idiomatic expression mean in this context?",
      "answers": [
        "To avoid discussing the main issue.",
        "To take a leisurely walk.",
        "To engage in small talk.",
        "To address the issue directly."
      ],
      "correct": "To address the issue directly."
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "In a political speech, the word \"revolution\" is used to inspire the audience. What is the connotative meaning of the word \"revolution\" in this context?",
      "answers": [
        "A sudden and significant change.",
        "The act of revolving around the town square.",
        "A period of political upheaval.",
        "A sudden scientific breakthrough."
      ],
      "correct": "A sudden and significant change."
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "During a conversation, a speaker is able to repair misunderstanding by rephrasing their statement. Which aspect of communicative competence is being utilized? ",
      "answers": [
        "Grammatical Competence",
        "Discourse Competence",
        "Sociolinguistic Competence",
        "Strategic Competence"
      ],
      "correct": "Strategic Competence"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "It emphasizes the importance of mental development in language acquisition, suggesting that cerebral processes influence language learning.",
      "answers": [
        "Nativist Theory",
        "Behaviorist Theory",
        "Social Interactionist Theory",
        "Cognitive Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Social Interactionist Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Who defined language as \"a system of signs that express ideas\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Ferdinand de Saussure",
        "Roman Jakobson",
        "Michael Halliday",
        "Charles Hocket"
      ],
      "correct": "Ferdinand de Saussure"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "In the sentence \"The professor's lecture was so esoteric that only a few students could understand it,\" which context clue best helps to determine the meaning of \"esoteric\"?",
      "answers": [
        "\"professor's lecture\"",
        "\"so\"",
        "\"only a few students could understand it\"",
        "\"that\""
      ],
      "correct": "\"only a few students could understand it\""
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Who proposed the theory of X-bar syntax, which provides a framework for understanding the hierarchical structure of phrases?",
      "answers": [
        "Ferdinand de Saussure",
        "Edward Sapir",
        "Noam Chomsky",
        "Leonard Bloomfield"
      ],
      "correct": "Noam Chomsky"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "How does a compound sentence differ from a complex sentence in terms of structure?",
      "answers": [
        "A compound sentence contains a main clause and a subordinate clause, while a complex sentence contains two main clauses.",
        "A compound sentence contains two main clauses joined by a correlative conjunction, while a complex sentence contains a main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
        "A compound sentence contains a main clause and a relative clause, while a complex sentence contains two main clauses joined by a subordinating conjunction.",
        "A compound sentence contains two main clauses joined by a coordinating conjunction, while a complex sentence contains a main clause and one or more subordinate clauses."
      ],
      "correct": "A compound sentence contains two main clauses joined by a coordinating conjunction, while a complex sentence contains a main clause and one or more subordinate clauses."
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "In a business meeting in Singapore, a participant uses a mix of English and local expressions. Which variety of English is this an example of?",
      "answers": [
        "American English",
        "Singlish",
        "Konglish",
        "British English"
      ],
      "correct": "Konglish"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "______ is the practice of alternating between two or more languages or language varieties within a conversation or discourse while ______ is the blending elements of two or more languages within a single utterance or sentence.",
      "answers": [
        "Language borrowing and code-blending",
        "Code-mixing and language shif",
        "Language shift and language borrowing",
        "Code-switching and code-mixing"
      ],
      "correct": "Code-switching and code-mixing"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "A teacher is able to explain complex grammar rules in the students' first language, making it easier for them to understand. Which type of teacher is this?",
      "answers": [
        "NEST",
        "Language Assistant",
        "Non-NEST",
        "Monolingual Teacher"
      ],
      "correct": "Non-NEST"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Which term describes the physical movement of the speech organs to produce specific speech sounds?",
      "answers": [
        "Phonetics",
        "Phonology",
        "Pronunciation",
        "Articulation"
      ],
      "correct": "Articulation"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Which of the following is true about the classification of vowel sounds?",
      "answers": [
        "Classified based on place of articulation",
        "Classified based on manner of articulation",
        "Classified based on tongue height and tongue position",
        "Classified based on voicing"
      ],
      "correct": "Classified based on tongue height and tongue position"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "This is not a question. I just wanted to tell you that I love you very very much.",
      "answers": [
        "Show me your ass",
        "I love you too",
        "Thanks",
        "Okay"
      ],
      "correct": "I love you too"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Which of the following consonant sounds is produced by obstructing the airflow at the alveolar ridge?",
      "answers": [
        "/p/",
        "/t/",
        "/k/",
        "/f/"
      ],
      "correct": "/t/"
    }
  ],
  "STA/LET/SDA": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "In a short story, the author writes, \"The old house stood silent, its windows like eyes watching the world pass by, while a sense of melancholy lingered in the air.\" Which aspect of stylistics is being balanced in this sentence?",
      "answers": [
        "Expressiveness, by focusing solely on visual details",
        "Emotiveness, by focusing solely on the character's feelings",
        "Both expressiveness and emotiveness",
        "Neither expressiveness nor emotiveness"
      ],
      "correct": "Both expressiveness and emotiveness"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "How can power dynamics be analyzed in a conversation between a manager and an employee?",
      "answers": [
        "By counting the number of words spoken by each participant",
        "By examining the use of directives and interruptions by the manager",
        "By analyzing the grammatical correctness of each participant's speech",
        "By focusing on the topic of conversation with nominal consideration of the participants' roles"
      ],
      "correct": "By examining the use of directives and interruptions by the manager"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the principle of informed consent in research?",
      "answers": [
        "Participants are required to participate in the study without any information about the research since it is either highly technical or confidential.",
        "Participants are informed about the study's purpose, procedures, risks, and benefits, and voluntarily agree to participate.",
        "Participants are only informed about the benefits of the study and not the risks to avoid jeopardizing the researcher's goal.",
        "Participants are informed about the study after it has been completed."
      ],
      "correct": "Participants are informed about the study's purpose, procedures, risks, and benefits, and voluntarily agree to participate."
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "During a puppetry performance, a puppeteer uses a marionette to depict a character walking through a forest. What technique should the puppeteer use to make the movement appear realistic?",
      "answers": [
        "Move the marionette's legs in a stiff, robotic manner",
        "Swing the marionette's arms wildly while walking",
        "Keep the marionette's body completely still while moving the legs",
        "Synchronize the marionette's leg movements with a gentle sway of the body"
      ],
      "correct": "Synchronize the marionette's leg movements with a gentle sway of the body"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Which method is most appropriate for assessing the construct validity of a research instrument?",
      "answers": [
        "Factor analysis",
        "Content analysis",
        "Test-retest reliability",
        "Inter-rater reliability"
      ],
      "correct": "Factor analysis"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "What is the primary responsibility of a stage manager during a theatrical production?",
      "answers": [
        "Designing the set and costumes together with the tailors and seamstresses",
        "Directing the actors' performances",
        "Coordinating all aspects of the production and ensuring smooth execution",
        "Writing the script in consultation with the actors and directors"
      ],
      "correct": "Coordinating all aspects of the production and ensuring smooth execution"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Which architectural feature is most effective in enhancing the acoustics of a theater space by reflecting sound towards the audience?",
      "answers": [
        "Fly lof",
        "Orchestra pit",
        "Catwalk",
        "Acoustic panels"
      ],
      "correct": "Acoustic panels"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "You are tasked with conducting a discourse analysis on a political speech. Which of the following steps is most appropriate for selecting a representative sample of the speech for analysis?",
      "answers": [
        "Analyzing the introduction and conclusion of the speech as they reflect each other",
        "Selecting random excerpts from different parts of the speech to avoid bias",
        "Focusing uniquely on the most controversial statements made in the speech",
        "Analyzing the entire speech to capture the full context and nuances"
      ],
      "correct": "Analyzing the entire speech to capture the full context and nuances"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "While analyzing a written discourse, Mary notice recurring references to economic inequality. Which of the following is the best approach to identify and analyze this theme?",
      "answers": [
        "Ignoring the references and focusing on other themes",
        "Examining how economic inequality is discussed and its impact on the overall discourse",
        "Counting the number of times economic inequality is mentioned",
        "Summarizing the main points without analyzing the theme in detail"
      ],
      "correct": "Examining how economic inequality is discussed and its impact on the overall discourse"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Which method is most appropriate for evaluating the sensitivity of a research instrument to detect changes over time?",
      "answers": [
        "Responsiveness analysis",
        "Predictive validity",
        "Split-half reliability",
        "Face validity"
      ],
      "correct": "Responsiveness analysis"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Which of the following strategies is most effective for refuting an opponent's argument in a debate?",
      "answers": [
        "Ignoring the opponent's points and presenting new arguments",
        "Attacking the opponent's character instead of their argument",
        "Providing evidence that directly contradicts the opponent's claims",
        "Eating the opponent's ass"
      ],
      "correct": "Providing evidence that directly contradicts the opponent's claims"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Which of the following is a key strategy for managing public speaking anxiety?",
      "answers": [
        "Avoiding eye contact with the audience",
        "Practicing deep breathing techniques",
        "Speaking as quickly as possible to finish sooner",
        "Focusing on potential mistakes during the speech"
      ],
      "correct": "Practicing deep breathing techniques"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "In a speech therapy session, a therapist asks a child to produce the sounds /s/ and /z/. What is the primary difference between these two sounds?",
      "answers": [
        "/s/ is voiceless, and /z/ is voiced",
        "/s/ is voiced, and /z/ is voiceless",
        "/s/ is a vowel, and /z/ is a consonant",
        "/s/ is a nasal sound, and /z/ is a fricative sound"
      ],
      "correct": "/s/ is voiceless, and /z/ is voiced"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "A student wants to ensure their research topic makes a significant contribution to their field. Which approach should they take to identify an original and impactful research topic?",
      "answers": [
        "Replicating a well-known study to confirm its findings",
        "Choosing a topic that has been frequently discussed in recent conferences, indicating its great impact",
        "Selecting a topic based on the recommendations of their advisor",
        "Conducting a thorough literature review to identify gaps and unexplored areas"
      ],
      "correct": "Conducting a thorough literature review to identify gaps and unexplored areas"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "How can the effectiveness of the \"Literature Review\" section in a rationale be evaluated?",
      "answers": [
        "It summarizes the research findings with marginal critical analysis.",
        "It critically analyzes and synthesizes relevant research to highlight gaps.",
        "It provides a chronological list of all relevant studies.",
        "It includes personal opinions and anecdotal evidence."
      ],
      "correct": "It critically analyzes and synthesizes relevant research to highlight gaps."
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the process of breaking down a script to understand its structure, themes, and character motivations?",
      "answers": [
        "Blocking",
        "Table read",
        "Script analysis",
        "Tech rehearsal"
      ],
      "correct": "Script analysis"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "A researcher finds that some data points are missing in their dataset. Which method is most appropriate for handling missing data to maintain the integrity of the analysis?",
      "answers": [
        "Deleting all cases with missing data",
        "Replacing missing data with the mean value of the variable",
        "Using multiple imputation to estimate and replace missing data",
        "Discounting the missing data and proceeding with the analysis right away"
      ],
      "correct": "Using multiple imputation to estimate and replace missing data"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "During the analysis of discourse data, you notice a recurring pattern in the way participants discuss their experiences. What is the best approach to further investigate this pattern?",
      "answers": [
        "Paying no mind to the pattern and focusing on other aspects of the data",
        "Quantifying the frequency of the pattern across different participants",
        "Summarizing the pattern extensively and providing interpretation as an afterthought",
        "Analyzing the context and variations of the pattern to understand its significance"
      ],
      "correct": "Analyzing the context and variations of the pattern to understand its significance"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Manny is analyzing a poem that uses vivid imagery to describe a storm. Which of the following best captures the effect of this imagery on the reader?",
      "answers": [
        "It creates a sense of calm and tranquility.",
        "It evokes a feeling of chaos and intensity.",
        "It highlights the poet's use of formal structure.",
        "It emphasizes the poem's rhyme scheme."
      ],
      "correct": "It evokes a feeling of chaos and intensity."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "You are analyzing a novel with a first-person narrative. Which of the following best captures the effect of this narrative voice on the reader?",
      "answers": [
        "It creates a sense of distance and objectivity.",
        "It allows for an intimate and personal connection with the narrator.",
        "It provides multiple perspectives on the events of the story.",
        "It emphasizes the formal structure of the prose."
      ],
      "correct": "It allows for an intimate and personal connection with the narrator."
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "In Chamber Theater, how does the use of minimal props and set design affect the audience's experience?",
      "answers": [
        "It distracts the audience from the narrative.",
        "It enhances the focus on the actors' performances and the story.",
        "It makes the performance less engaging and dynamic.",
        "It complicates the understanding of the plot."
      ],
      "correct": "It enhances the focus on the actors' performances and the story."
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "During a theater performance, the director decides to use abstract set designs and symbolic costumes. What is the primary purpose of these artistic choices?",
      "answers": [
        "To save on production costs and encourage creative thinking among the audience",
        "To create a realistic depiction of the setting",
        "To ensure the actors' comfort on stage",
        "To enhance the audience's emotional and intellectual engagement"
      ],
      "correct": "To enhance the audience's emotional and intellectual engagement"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "What is the primary advantage of using a mixed-methods research design?",
      "answers": [
        "It combines qualitative and quantitative approaches to provide a comprehensive understanding of the research problem.",
        "It eliminates the need for a literature review.",
        "It allows for the collection of only quantitative data.",
        "It simplifies the data analysis process."
      ],
      "correct": "It combines qualitative and quantitative approaches to provide a comprehensive understanding of the research problem."
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which statistical test is most appropriate for comparing the means of two independent groups?",
      "answers": [
        "Chi-square test",
        "Paired t-test",
        "ANOVA",
        "Independent samples t-test"
      ],
      "correct": "Independent samples t-test"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "Which aspect of a poem's rhythm is most influenced by the arrangement of stressed and unstressed syllables?",
      "answers": [
        "The meter",
        "The rhyme scheme",
        "The enjambment",
        "The imagery"
      ],
      "correct": "The meter"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Which type of meter is characterized by a pattern of one stressed syllable followed by two unstressed syllables?",
      "answers": [
        "Iambic",
        "Trochaic",
        "Anapestic",
        "Dactylic"
      ],
      "correct": "Dactylic"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "Which factor most likely enhances the external validity of a research study?",
      "answers": [
        "Using a homogeneous sample that is easy to control",
        "Conducting the study in a highly controlled laboratory setting",
        "Using complex statistical analyses to interpret the data",
        "Including a diverse and representative sample of the population"
      ],
      "correct": "Including a diverse and representative sample of the population"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Which of the following best evaluates the meter of the following line of poetry: \"Shall I compare thee to a summer's day?\"",
      "answers": [
        "Trochaic tetrameter",
        "Iambic pentameter",
        "Anapestic trimeter",
        "Dactylic hexameter"
      ],
      "correct": "Iambic pentameter"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "A researcher is studying the effects of a new medication on blood pressure. Which data collection procedure would best ensure the accuracy and reliability of the measurements?",
      "answers": [
        "Self-reported questionnaires",
        "Blood pressure measurements taken by trained medical professionals",
        "Telephone interviews with participants",
        "Online surveys"
      ],
      "correct": "Blood pressure measurements taken by trained medical professionals"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the technique of \"affective memory\" in Method Acting?",
      "answers": [
        "Using physical actions to recall past experiences",
        "Recalling personal emotional experiences to inform a character's emotions",
        "Mimicking the physical behavior of others to develop a character",
        "Using external stimuli to trigger a character's emotional response"
      ],
      "correct": "Recalling personal emotional experiences to inform a character's emotions"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "Which of the following techniques is most closely associated with the physical acting method developed by Jacques Lecoq?",
      "answers": [
        "Stanislavski's System",
        "Viewpoints",
        "Commedia dell'arte",
        "Neutral Mask"
      ],
      "correct": "Neutral Mask"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "A researcher is conducting a study on the dietary habits of college students. Which sampling method would best ensure a representative sample of the entire student population?",
      "answers": [
        "Convenience sampling",
        "Snowball sampling",
        "Stratified random sampling",
        "Quota sampling"
      ],
      "correct": "Stratified random sampling"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "How does a director's vision influence the overall production of a stage play?",
      "answers": [
        "It guides the creative decisions, including casting, design, and interpretation of the script.",
        "It determines the budget and financial aspects of the production.",
        "It ensures the technical elements, such as lighting and sound, are executed correctly.",
        "It widens the audience's ass."
      ],
      "correct": "It guides the creative decisions, including casting, design, and interpretation of the script."
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "In a study examining global communication trends, which aspect best represents the megacontext?",
      "answers": [
        "The specific language used in individual emails",
        "The cultural norms and values of different countries",
        "The organizational structure of a multinational corporation",
        "The personal relationships between employees"
      ],
      "correct": "The cultural norms and values of different countries"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes a characteristic feature of Charles Dickens' writing style?",
      "answers": [
        "Use of stream-of-consciousness narrative",
        "Focus on the psychological depth of characters including their antihero traits",
        "Minimalist prose with sparse descriptions",
        "Detailed descriptions of social settings and vivid characterizations"
      ],
      "correct": "Detailed descriptions of social settings and vivid characterizations"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "What is a defining characteristic of Henrik Ibsen's dramatic style?",
      "answers": [
        "Use of elaborate poetic language and symbolism",
        "Preference for historical and mythological themes",
        "Emphasis on supernatural elements and fantasy",
        "Focus on social issues and realistic dialogue"
      ],
      "correct": "Focus on social issues and realistic dialogue"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "How can the relevance and significance of the \"Rationale\" section be effectively evaluated?",
      "answers": [
        "It includes a detailed budget and timeline for the research.",
        "It highlights the theoretical framework and its application to the study.",
        "It demonstrates how the research addresses a gap in the existing literature.",
        "It provides a summary of the research findings and conclusions."
      ],
      "correct": "It demonstrates how the research addresses a gap in the existing literature."
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "A passage describes a setting with \"dark, looming clouds and a chilling wind that cut through the air.\" What can be inferred about the mood of the scene?",
      "answers": [
        "The mood is cheerful and uplifting.",
        "The mood is tense and foreboding.",
        "The mood is calm and serene.",
        "The mood is indifferent and neutral."
      ],
      "correct": "The mood is tense and foreboding."
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the role of a rebuttal in a debate?",
      "answers": [
        "To respond to and refute the opponent's arguments",
        "To summarize the main points of the debate",
        "To introduce new arguments and evidence",
        "To provide a closing statement"
      ],
      "correct": "To respond to and refute the opponent's arguments"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "How can the thematic organization of synthesized literature be evaluated for its effectiveness?",
      "answers": [
        "It categorizes studies based on common themes and research questions.",
        "It organizes studies by the researcher's last name.",
        "It groups studies based on the year of publication.",
        "It lists studies alphabetically by title."
      ],
      "correct": "It categorizes studies based on common themes and research questions."
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "Which criterion best evaluates the accuracy of citations in a research paper?",
      "answers": [
        "The citations are placed at the end of each paragraph.",
        "The citations include the author's name, publication year, and page number.",
        "The citations are formatted in a consistent style throughout the paper.",
        "The citations are listed alphabetically in the bibliography for easy referencing."
      ],
      "correct": "The citations include the author's name, publication year, and page number."
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes a key characteristic of a true experimental design?",
      "answers": [
        "It involves the manipulation of an independent variable and random assignment of participants.",
        "It relies on observational data without manipulating any variables.",
        "It uses a single group of participants without a control group.",
        "It focuses on qualitative data collection methods such as interviews and focus groups."
      ],
      "correct": "It involves the manipulation of an independent variable and random assignment of participants."
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "During an improvisation exercise, an actor is given the prompt \"You just found a mysterious box in your attic.\" What is the most effective way for the actor to respond to this prompt?",
      "answers": [
        "Ignore the prompt and talk about something unrelated then talk about the box",
        "Stand still and wait for further instructions",
        "Ask the audience what they think is inside the box and pretend to be carrying it",
        "Describe the box in detail and speculate about its contents"
      ],
      "correct": "Describe the box in detail and speculate about its contents"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "In a poem where the speaker reflects on lost love, which stylistic element is most likely to contribute to a melancholic tone?",
      "answers": [
        "The use of bright and cheerful diction",
        "The use of short, abrupt sentences",
        "The use of somber and reflective language",
        "The use of complex and technical jargon"
      ],
      "correct": "The use of somber and reflective language"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "In a piece of prose where dialogue is used extensively, what is the primary effect of this stylistic choice?",
      "answers": [
        "It slows down the pacing of the narrative.",
        "It provides direct insight into characters' thoughts and personalities.",
        "It minimizes the importance of the setting.",
        "It focuses solely on the plot development."
      ],
      "correct": "It provides direct insight into characters' thoughts and personalities."
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "Which citation style is commonly used in the social sciences for writing research reports?",
      "answers": [
        "APA",
        "MLA",
        "Chicago/Turabian",
        "IEEE"
      ],
      "correct": "APA"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "In regression analysis, which method is most effective for dealing with heteroscedasticity in the residuals?",
      "answers": [
        "Using ordinary least squares (OLS) regression",
        "Overlooking the heteroscedasticity and proceeding with the analysis",
        "Increasing the number of predictors in the model",
        "Applying weighted least squares (WLS) regression"
      ],
      "correct": "Applying weighted least squares (WLS) regression"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "In a story, a character is described as \"clenching his fists and gritting his teeth\" during a conversation. What can be inferred about his feelings towards the conversation?",
      "answers": [
        "He is feeling relaxed and at ease.",
        "He is feeling confused and puzzled.",
        "He is feeling amused and entertained.",
        "He is feeling angry and frustrated."
      ],
      "correct": "He is feeling angry and frustrated."
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "In an educational setting, students participate in a theater workshop where they perform scenes from historical events. What is the primary educational benefit of this activity?",
      "answers": [
        "To improve students' memorization skills",
        "To provide entertainment for the school community",
        "To prepare students for professional acting careers",
        "To enhance students' understanding of historical contexts and perspectives"
      ],
      "correct": "To enhance students' understanding of historical contexts and perspectives"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "In a descriptive passage that vividly portrays a bustling city, which of the following best describes the effect of this language on the reader?",
      "answers": [
        "It evokes a lively and energetic atmosphere.",
        "It creates a sense of isolation and solitude.",
        "It emphasizes the simplicity and tranquility of rural life.",
        "It focuses on the internal thoughts of a single character."
      ],
      "correct": "It evokes a lively and energetic atmosphere."
    }
  ],
  "TRANSLATION & EDITING": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "What is the term for the ethical principle that requires translators to respect the privacy of their clients and sources?",
      "answers": [
        "Fidelity",
        "Impartiality",
        "Transparency",
        "Confidentiality"
      ],
      "correct": "Confidentiality"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Simon is translating a website from English to Filipino for his school project. He encounters a cultural reference in the source text that has no direct equivalent in the target culture. Which translation technique should he use to convey the meaning and context of the cultural reference?",
      "answers": [
        "Borrowing",
        "Calque",
        "Equivalence",
        "Adaptation"
      ],
      "correct": "Adaptation"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "What is the term for the difference between the meaning of a word or phrase in the source language and the meaning of the same word or phrase in the target language?",
      "answers": [
        "Equivalence",
        "Discrepancy",
        "Gap",
        "Mismatch"
      ],
      "correct": "Gap"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "What is the name of the American linguist who coined the term \"dynamic equivalence\" and introduced the concept of \"functional equivalence\" in translation?",
      "answers": [
        "Eugene Nida",
        "Noam Chomsky",
        "Roman Jakobson",
        "Peter Newmark"
      ],
      "correct": "Eugene Nida"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "What is the principle of editing and translation that is about suiting the purpose, context, and expectations of the client and the readers?",
      "answers": [
        "Clarity",
        "Coherence",
        "Consistency",
        "Appropriateness"
      ],
      "correct": "Appropriateness"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "What is the main reason for maintaining the author's voice in translation and editing?",
      "answers": [
        "To preserve the authenticity and identity of the text",
        "To preserve the accuracy and relevance of the text",
        "To preserve the communication and persuasion strategies of the text",
        "To preserve the nuances and subtleties of the text"
      ],
      "correct": "To preserve the authenticity and identity of the text"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "What is one of the types of human translation that involves translating a text by using the same grammatical structures and word order as the source text, as much as possible?",
      "answers": [
        "Literal translation",
        "Free translation",
        "Dynamic translation",
        "Functional translation"
      ],
      "correct": "Literal translation"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "What is the term for the social phenomenon that occurs when a language or a culture dominates and influences other languages or cultures through translation?",
      "answers": [
        "Translation shift",
        "Translation loss",
        "Translation gap",
        "Translation power"
      ],
      "correct": "Translation power"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "What is the term for the process of checking and correcting the spelling, punctuation, grammar, and formatting of a text?",
      "answers": [
        "Editing",
        "Revising",
        "Proofreading",
        "Translating"
      ],
      "correct": "Proofreading"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "What is the term for the original text that is being edited or translated?",
      "answers": [
        "Source text",
        "Target text",
        "Input text",
        "Output text"
      ],
      "correct": "Source text"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Bea is translating a scientific paper from English to Filipino for your school project. She encounters a term in the source text that has no direct equivalent in the target language. Which translation technique should she use to convey the meaning and concept of the term?",
      "answers": [
        "Borrowing",
        "Calque",
        "Equivalence",
        "Adaptation"
      ],
      "correct": "Borrowing"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "What is one of the benefits of using translation materials for bilingual classrooms?",
      "answers": [
        "They can suit the linguistic and cultural needs of the students.",
        "They can nominally enhance the language skills and intercultural competence of the students.",
        "They can measure the learning outcomes and evaluate the performance of the students.",
        "They can motivate the interest and engagement of the students in the learning process."
      ],
      "correct": "They can suit the linguistic and cultural needs of the students."
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "What is the term for the professional practice that involves providing oral translation between two or more parties who speak different languages?",
      "answers": [
        "Interpretation",
        "Transcription",
        "Subtitling",
        "Dubbing"
      ],
      "correct": "Interpretation"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "What is one of the purposes of using translation as a method of assessment in the language classroom?",
      "answers": [
        "To monitor students' progress and identify their strengths and weaknesses.",
        "To motivate students' interest and engagement in the language learning process.",
        "To expose students to authentic and diverse texts and contexts in the target language.",
        "To measure students' learning outcomes and evaluate their performance."
      ],
      "correct": "To monitor students' progress and identify their strengths and weaknesses."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Kathy is translating a poem from English to French for a class assignment. The poem contains a metaphor that compares love to a rose. How should she handle this figurative language in your translation?",
      "answers": [
        "Substitute it",
        "Preserve it",
        "Explain it",
        "Omit it"
      ],
      "correct": "Preserve it"
    }
  ],
  "ENGLISH": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Aaron is analyzing how words are formed, focusing on prefixes, suffixes, and roots. Which area of linguistics is he most concerned with?",
      "answers": [
        "Syntax",
        "Morphology",
        "Phonology",
        "Pragmatics"
      ],
      "correct": "Morphology"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Which term describes a word that has the same pronunciation but different meanings and spellings?",
      "answers": [
        "Homograph",
        "Synonym",
        "Antonym",
        "Homophone"
      ],
      "correct": "Homophone"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "A student asks about the function of the word \"Oh\" in the sentence:  \"Oh, I forgot to lock the door!\"",
      "answers": [
        "Interjection",
        "Conjunction",
        "Adverb",
        "Pronoun"
      ],
      "correct": "Interjection"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "What role does etymology play in a dictionary's handling of words formed through word formation processes?",
      "answers": [
        "It helps the dictionary define words based only on their original meanings.",
        "",
        "It lists the word's linguistic origin without including its current meaning.",
        "It is only mentioned for words that have changed meanings over time."
      ],
      "correct": ""
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "How would you classify the sentence, \"She skated through the hardest part of the exam\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Synoeciosis",
        "Procatalepsis",
        "Anthimeria",
        "Epanalepsis"
      ],
      "correct": "Anthimeria"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "What is the primary difference between phonemes and allophones?",
      "answers": [
        "Phonemes are individual sounds, while allophones are stress patterns.",
        "Phonemes are abstract sound units, while allophones are contextual variations of those phonemes.",
        "Phonemes only occur in written language, while allophones occur in spoken language.",
        "Phonemes are always voiced, while allophones are always voiceless."
      ],
      "correct": "Phonemes are abstract sound units, while allophones are contextual variations of those phonemes."
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Which pair of words is an example of a minimal pair?",
      "answers": [
        "Cat and Dog",
        "Ship and Sheep",
        "Book and Library",
        "Sky and Fly"
      ],
      "correct": "Cat and Dog"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "How can you differentiate between voiced and voiceless phonemes?",
      "answers": [
        "Voiced phonemes are louder than voiceless phonemes.",
        "Voiced phonemes involve vocal cord vibration; voiceless phonemes do not.",
        "Voiceless phonemes are longer in duration than voiced phonemes.",
        "Voiceless phonemes can only occur at the beginning of words."
      ],
      "correct": "Voiced phonemes involve vocal cord vibration; voiceless phonemes do not."
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "In English, how do tense and lax vowels differ?",
      "answers": [
        "Tense vowels are pronounced with a raised tongue, while lax vowels are pronounced with a lowered tongue.",
        "Tense vowels are always nasalized, while lax vowels are not.",
        "Tense vowels have a longer duration and are produced with more muscular tension than lax vowels.",
        "Tense vowels are only found in unstressed syllables, while lax vowels are found in stressed syllables."
      ],
      "correct": "Tense vowels have a longer duration and are produced with more muscular tension than lax vowels."
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "What is the main difference between inflection and derivation in morphology?",
      "answers": [
        "Inflection changes the word's meaning, while derivation maintains the same meaning.",
        "Inflection adds new words to the language, while derivation modifies existing words' grammatical forms.",
        "Inflection modifies grammatical features like tense or number, while derivation creates new words by adding prefixes or suffixes.",
        "Inflection always involves adding prefixes, while derivation involves adding suffixes."
      ],
      "correct": "Inflection modifies grammatical features like tense or number, while derivation creates new words by adding prefixes or suffixes."
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "How does the concept of \"morpheme\" differ from \"word\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Morphemes are larger than words.",
        "Morphemes can be the smallest units of meaning or grammatical function, while words are complete units that can stand alone.",
        "Morphemes are always derived from other words, while words are original units of language.",
        "Morphemes cannot stand alone, while words can."
      ],
      "correct": "Morphemes can be the smallest units of meaning or grammatical function, while words are complete units that can stand alone."
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Identify the morphemic structure of the word \"unhappiness.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Root: happiness, Prefix: un, Suffix: ness",
        "Root: happy, Prefix: un, Suffix: ness",
        "Root: happy, Prefix: un, Suffix: ing",
        "Root: happiness, Prefix: un, Suffix: ing"
      ],
      "correct": "Root: happy, Prefix: un, Suffix: ness"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "What is an example of morpheme alternation (allomorphy)?",
      "answers": [
        "The suffix -ed in \"played\" vs. \"skipped\"",
        "The prefix un- in \"unhappy\" vs. \"undone\"",
        "The vowel change in \"foot\" vs. \"feet\"",
        "The consonant cluster in \"strength\" vs. \"strengths\""
      ],
      "correct": "The vowel change in \"foot\" vs. \"feet\""
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "How do phonological rules affect morpheme realization in different linguistic contexts?",
      "answers": [
        "Phonological rules do not impact morpheme realization.",
        "Phonological rules only affect inflectional morphemes.",
        "Phonological rules can cause morphemes to be pronounced differently depending on their phonetic environment.",
        "Phonological rules are only applicable to vowel sounds."
      ],
      "correct": "Phonological rules can cause morphemes to be pronounced differently depending on their phonetic environment."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "What is the main theme of George Orwell's novel \"1984\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Romantic love",
        "The struggle for power",
        "The dangers of totalitarianism",
        "The beauty of nature"
      ],
      "correct": "The dangers of totalitarianism"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Which of the following is a correct example of parallel structure?",
      "answers": [
        "She likes running, to swim, and biking.",
        "She likes running, swimming, and biking.",
        "She likes to run, swimming, and bike.",
        "She likes running, to swim, and to bike."
      ],
      "correct": "She likes running, swimming, and biking."
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "In poetry, what is a \"meter\"?",
      "answers": [
        "The central theme of the poem",
        "The pattern of stressed and unstressed syllables",
        "The use of vivid imagery",
        "The length of each line"
      ],
      "correct": "The pattern of stressed and unstressed syllables"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "What is the effect of using enjambment in poetry?",
      "answers": [
        "To create a pause at the end of each line",
        "To continue a sentence without a pause beyond the end of a line",
        "To rhyme the last words of each line",
        "To emphasize a specific word or phrase"
      ],
      "correct": "To continue a sentence without a pause beyond the end of a line"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Which literary device involves a direct address to an absent or imaginary person?",
      "answers": [
        "Allusion",
        "Apostrophe",
        "Metonymy",
        "Synecdoche"
      ],
      "correct": "Apostrophe"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following best describes a Bildungsroman?",
      "answers": [
        "A novel focused on the growth and development of the protagonist",
        "A novel with a complex and intricate plot",
        "A novel set in a dystopian future",
        "A novel that includes elements of fantasy and magic"
      ],
      "correct": "A novel focused on the growth and development of the protagonist"
    }
  ],
  "AFRO-ASIAN LITERATURE": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "In Chinua Achebe's \"Things Fall Apart,\" Okonkwo's fear of failure and weakness is largely driven by his desire to avoid being like his father. What motivates Okonkwo to reject his father's way of life?",
      "answers": [
        "His father's extreme wealth and success",
        "His father's reputation as a brave warrior",
        "His father's laziness and lack of achievement",
        "His father's harsh treatment of his family"
      ],
      "correct": "His father's laziness and lack of achievement"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "In \"The God of Small Things\" by Arundhati Roy, the relationship between the twins Rahel and Estha is central to the story. How does their bond affect their ability to cope with family trauma?",
      "answers": [
        "It makes them more dependent on each other",
        "It isolates them from the rest of their family",
        "It weakens their resolve to overcome challenges",
        "It strengthens their resilience and sense of identity"
      ],
      "correct": "It strengthens their resilience and sense of identity"
    }
  ],
  "ASSESSMENT OF GRAMMAR": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "The students are encouraged to explore language through creative writing and reading, using correct grammar along the way.",
      "answers": [
        "Learning Through Writing",
        "Deductive Teaching",
        "Inductive Teaching",
        "Structuralism"
      ],
      "correct": "Inductive Teaching"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "A type of fossilization in which different languages have their own syntactic rules",
      "answers": [
        "Phonological Fossilization",
        "Syntactic Fossilization",
        "Morphological Fossilization",
        "Semantic"
      ],
      "correct": "Syntactic Fossilization"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "An approach that focuses on instruction before practice.",
      "answers": [
        "Learning Through Writing",
        "Deductive Teaching ",
        "Inductive Teaching",
        "Structuralism"
      ],
      "correct": "Deductive Teaching "
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "The input to the semantic component which describes the meaning.",
      "answers": [
        "Surface Structure",
        "Deep Structure",
        "Langue",
        "Parole"
      ],
      "correct": "Deep Structure"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Model of the pedagogy study in which the learning process is carried out in a continuous active cooperation of all students. Students and teachers are equal subjects of study.",
      "answers": [
        "Active",
        "Interactive",
        "Passive",
        "Inductive"
      ],
      "correct": "Interactive"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "A method of teaching grammar involves presenting several examples that illustrate a specific concept and expecting students to notice how the concept works.",
      "answers": [
        "Learning Through Writing",
        "Deductive Teaching",
        "Inductive Teaching",
        "Structuralism"
      ],
      "correct": "Inductive Teaching"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "It is anchored to behavior or manner of speech production.",
      "answers": [
        "Grammar",
        "Langue",
        "Language",
        "Parole"
      ],
      "correct": "Parole"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "It links the subject of the sentence to its subject complement: therefore, this pattern only works with linking verbs.",
      "answers": [
        "Sensory Verbs",
        "Linking Verb",
        "Action Verb",
        "Verb Phrase"
      ],
      "correct": "Linking Verb"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "It always indicates the ignorance of rule restrictions, including semantic restrictions of lexis or other linguistic items.",
      "answers": [
        "Communication Strategy",
        "Overgeneralization",
        "Learning Strategy",
        "Language Transfer"
      ],
      "correct": "Overgeneralization"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "We need these skills to talk about something that logically happened in the past so others can follow the story.",
      "answers": [
        "Grammaring",
        "Training Transfer",
        "Fossilizing",
        "Sequencing"
      ],
      "correct": "Sequencing"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Which refers to the instructional strategies that make up the art or science of knowledge?",
      "answers": [
        "Psychology",
        "Methodology",
        "Pedagogy",
        "Andragogy"
      ],
      "correct": "Pedagogy"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "It is a word or phrase whose meaning depends on their context of use i.e. you, there.",
      "answers": [
        "Entailment",
        "Deixis",
        "Presupposition",
        "Pronoun"
      ],
      "correct": "Deixis"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "The poet can be satirical, expressing himself with wit and force. Interpret: \"Which is the basest creature, man or beast? Birds feed on birds, birds on each other's prey; but savage man alone does man betray.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Man is just like animals",
        "Man's inhumanity to his kind",
        "Man is the most beastly of animals",
        "Man is proven by his actions"
      ],
      "correct": "Man's inhumanity to his kind"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which synonym will you choose for the given sentences? \"One of his ambition is to make a fortune,\"",
      "answers": [
        "Shape",
        "Earn",
        "Explore",
        "Receive"
      ],
      "correct": "Earn"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "What communicative competence is shown by Alex when in his speech he wanted to use the word 'rummage', but he could not think of it so he used 'thorough search' instead?",
      "answers": [
        "Linguistic",
        "Discourse",
        "Strategic",
        "Sociolinguistic"
      ],
      "correct": "Strategic"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Which word is closest in meaning to the CAPITALIZED word in the given sentence? \"I got my courage back and wonderful sense of expectation of the IMMINENT arrival of the liberation.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Unexpected",
        "Eminent",
        " Approaching",
        "Delayed"
      ],
      "correct": " Approaching"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Which sentence has an adjective clause?",
      "answers": [
        "The victim who was allegedly salvage",
        "The victim who was allegedly salvage is a freshman.",
        "They found the salvaged victim in an abandoned building.",
        "They were called to identify the salvaged victim."
      ],
      "correct": "The victim who was allegedly salvage is a freshman."
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "When children start to explore their environment and intend to learn more about the world around them, they usually become very inquisitive and always throw questions. Which language function is described?",
      "answers": [
        "Expressive",
        "Imaginative",
        "Personal",
        "Heuristic"
      ],
      "correct": "Heuristic"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Identify the incorrect example of Past Perfect Tense from the given options:",
      "answers": [
        "I had gone to the gymnasium by the time you arrived.",
        "I had retired to bed when the guests arrived.",
        " I had many opportunities to swim in the past.",
        "I had just stepped into my office when the phone rang."
      ],
      "correct": " I had many opportunities to swim in the past."
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences uses the tag question correctly?",
      "answers": [
        "Alice usually brings her lunch from home, doesn't she?",
        "Nobody has called for me, haven't they?",
        "You won't tell anyone, would you?",
        "None of those customers were happy, weren't they?"
      ],
      "correct": "Alice usually brings her lunch from home, doesn't she?"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Determine the sentence pattern for the following sentence: The people elected the young candidate for governor.",
      "answers": [
        "S-IV",
        "S-TV-DO",
        "S-LV-C",
        "S-TV-DO-OC"
      ],
      "correct": "S-TV-DO-OC"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Identify the sentence that uses the correct third conditional sentence structure.",
      "answers": [
        "If Immanuel had enough money to buy the car, he would have gone to the party with you.",
        "If I had known you were coming, I will have prepared dinner.",
        "If he had taken the train, he would save time.",
        "If she had been invited, she would come to the party."
      ],
      "correct": "If Immanuel had enough money to buy the car, he would have gone to the party with you."
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Which statement is correct in structure and form?",
      "answers": [
        "Of the areas that produce lanzones, the Camiguin Island is sweeter.",
        "Of the areas that produce lanzones, the Camiguin Island is the sweetest.",
        "Of the areas that produce lanzones, the Camiguin Island, is the sweetest.",
        "Of the areas, that produce lanzones, the Camiguin Island is the sweeter."
      ],
      "correct": "Of the areas that produce lanzones, the Camiguin Island is the sweetest."
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "How many years does learners take to develop CALP?",
      "answers": [
        "3 years",
        "4 years",
        "5 years",
        "6 years"
      ],
      "correct": "5 years"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "In applying passive voice, which should you use on an official sign?",
      "answers": [
        "Beyond this point, do not permit pedestrian.",
        "Do not permit pedestrian beyond this point.",
        "Beyond this point, pedestrian should permit to go.",
        "Pedestrians are not permitted beyond this point."
      ],
      "correct": "Pedestrians are not permitted beyond this point."
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "EVERYONE met at the contest venue. The capitalized pronoun is an example of a/an ________ .",
      "answers": [
        "Indefinite pronoun",
        "Relative pronoun",
        "Demonstrative pronoun",
        "Interrogative pronoun"
      ],
      "correct": "Indefinite pronoun"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "The adjective that expresses the supreme value of the noun like the capitalized phrase in the sentence, \"English is the MOST INTERESTING subject for Ryza,\" is called __________ .",
      "answers": [
        "Superlative adjective",
        "Relative pronoun",
        "Demonstrative pronoun",
        "Interrogative pronoun"
      ],
      "correct": "Superlative adjective"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Which is NOT a variable of functional grammar?",
      "answers": [
        "Term which represents the role of the interlocutors",
        "Tenor is concerned with the nature of the relationship among the people involved.",
        "Field which represents the content or topic of the social activity.",
        "Mode is the medium and role of language in the situation"
      ],
      "correct": "Term which represents the role of the interlocutors"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "It refers to a group of two or more words that usually go together, for example, \"make sense,\" \"pay attention,\" and \"give a hand.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Co-reference",
        "Collocation",
        "Denotation",
        "Connotation"
      ],
      "correct": "Collocation"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "In which sentence does the adverb tell HOW the action is done?",
      "answers": [
        "Christy had ice cream after she was done.",
        "Then Christy came home to wrap the present",
        "Christy went to the store to buy a present.",
        "Christy wrapped the present carefully."
      ],
      "correct": "Christy wrapped the present carefully."
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "It _________ unfair that she should stay on the stage longer.",
      "answers": [
        "Has to",
        "Needs",
        "Tends to",
        "Seems"
      ],
      "correct": "Seems"
    },
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Which of the following concepts in grammar is shown in the following definition of noun? \"Noun in a sentence occurs before the verb phrase; after a transitive verb; after a linking verb; after a preposition; and after another noun or noun phrase.",
      "answers": [
        "Noun placement",
        "Distribution",
        "Grammatical pattern",
        "Syntax"
      ],
      "correct": "Distribution"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Which type of error is committed in the sentence below: The President together with his department secretaries is in Central distributing relief goods.",
      "answers": [
        "Dangling modifier",
        "Misplaced modifier",
        "Squinting modifier",
        "Run-on sentence"
      ],
      "correct": "Misplaced modifier"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "What issue is pointed out in the following sentence? \"The movie ends with two scenes that contains clue of the real cause of the main character's failure to amass great wealth.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Subject-verb agreement",
        "Determiner-noun agreement",
        "Pronoun-antecedent agreement",
        "Predeterminer-noun agreement"
      ],
      "correct": "Subject-verb agreement"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which word is not an adjective in the statement below? \"It is an interesting, but a difficult question. I am not sure if I have done it right.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Interesting",
        "Difficult",
        "Sure",
        "Right"
      ],
      "correct": "Right"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "The following sentences show \"syntactic ambiguity\" EXCEPT:",
      "answers": [
        "I talked to my English literature teacher.",
        "Nicole saw the people with binoculars.",
        "They are the wealthy men and women in our society.",
        "We challenge his beliefs about religion."
      ],
      "correct": "We challenge his beliefs about religion."
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "The underlined word in the following sentence functions as _____ . \"For an essay to be unified, it must maintain a consistent level of language and attitude toward the subject and the reader.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Direct object",
        "Indirect object",
        "Object complement",
        "Predicate nominative"
      ],
      "correct": "Object complement"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "How many phrases are there in the given sentence? Villagers in the mining area were prohibited to go back to their homes covered by sticky mud.",
      "answers": [
        "4",
        "5",
        "2",
        "3"
      ],
      "correct": "5"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Which of the following statements has a direct object?",
      "answers": [
        "Please dedicate yourself to the improvement of your soft skills.",
        "What matters most is your unwavering commitment.",
        "Yours class president is my nephew's basketball coach.",
        "How our varsity team won was unimaginable."
      ],
      "correct": "Please dedicate yourself to the improvement of your soft skills."
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Which linguist proposed the theory of Universal Grammar, suggesting an innate human capacity for language acquisition?",
      "answers": [
        "Ferdinand de Saussure",
        "Noam Chomsky",
        "Steven Pinker",
        "Benjamin Whorf"
      ],
      "correct": "Noam Chomsky"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Which of the following statements has a noun clause?",
      "answers": [
        "My mother told me that you knew where to find the best caterer in town.",
        "The much-awaited performance which was postponed several times finally came.",
        "Mrs. Romero is the speech trainer who first taught me how to give a good impromptu speech.",
        "When do you expect to meet the new members of our dance troupe?"
      ],
      "correct": "My mother told me that you knew where to find the best caterer in town."
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "What term is used to suggest that concepts have internal structure, with the best examples (for instance Tom Cruise in the case of 'film stars', Robin in the case of 'birds') close to the core and less typical members arranged in successively more peripheral regions?",
      "answers": [
        "Stereotype",
        "Idiotype",
        "Prototype",
        "Archetype"
      ],
      "correct": "Prototype"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Three kinds of complements come after verbs. Which sentence has an indirect object?",
      "answers": [
        "Many business owners sold their shares.",
        "The farmers consider natural fertilizers as a better option.",
        "The loving mother gave her daughter a big hug.",
        "The pharmacist sold unexpired drugs."
      ],
      "correct": "The loving mother gave her daughter a big hug."
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "What is shown in the following? \"The man saw the cow.\" 1. the man (subject) 1.1. the (article) 1.2. man (noun) 2. saw the cow (predicate) 2.1. saw (verb) 2.2. the cow (object) 2.2.1. the (article) 2.2.2. cow (noun)",
      "answers": [
        "Parsing",
        "Inflecting",
        "Diagramming",
        "Conjugating"
      ],
      "correct": "Parsing"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "All of the following contain operator verbs EXCEPT:",
      "answers": [
        "Your father approved my marriage proposal, won't he?",
        "Will your father approve my marriage proposal?",
        "My father won't approve your marriage proposal.",
        "My father approves your marriage proposal."
      ],
      "correct": "My father approves your marriage proposal."
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Which of the following is the true description of an auxiliary verb?",
      "answers": [
        "It is followed by noun or noun phrase functioning as its direct object.",
        "It is used to complete the verb phrase in certain constructions such as the emphatic, the negative, the passive, or the perfect and progressive aspects.",
        "It occurs before the main verb, and denotes modification of the basic meaning of the main verb.",
        "It belongs to several classifications of verbs. It may take an impersonal it as a subject."
      ],
      "correct": "It is used to complete the verb phrase in certain constructions such as the emphatic, the negative, the passive, or the perfect and progressive aspects."
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "What type of mood is indicated in this sentence: \"How did you come to know about that tragic event?\"",
      "answers": [
        "Subjunctive",
        "Imperative",
        "Directive",
        "Indicative"
      ],
      "correct": "Indicative"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences does NOT observe correct subject-verb agreement?",
      "answers": [
        "The mayor as well as his brothers is going to prison.",
        "Neither of the two traffic lights is working.",
        "My assets were wiped out in the depression.",
        "Neither the plates nor the serving bowl go on that shelf."
      ],
      "correct": "Neither the plates nor the serving bowl go on that shelf."
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "The pronoun in this sentence \"When she arrived, Suad was surprised to find her apartment door open\" is ______ .",
      "answers": [
        "Cataphoric",
        "Anaphoric",
        "Deitic",
        "Coreferential"
      ],
      "correct": "Cataphoric"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "For two weeks now, our professor in World Literature has untiringly _______ about the importance of submitting subject requirements on time.",
      "answers": [
        "Spoken",
        "Spoke",
        "Have been speaking",
        "Did speak"
      ],
      "correct": "Spoken"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "Which sentence is grammatically incorrect?",
      "answers": [
        "I have watched it the other day.",
        "The students had gathered at the quadrangle with their placard when the principal entered.",
        "By the time he graduated, his parents will already have left for New Zealand.",
        "He lived in his ancestral home in the countryside during his last year."
      ],
      "correct": "By the time he graduated, his parents will already have left for New Zealand."
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Which sentence shows the correct combination of tenses of verbs?",
      "answers": [
        "I had just put the washing out when it starts to rain.",
        "The train had left when I arrived at the station.",
        "Arch had gone out when I had arrived in the office.",
        "I had saved my document before the computer crashes."
      ],
      "correct": "The train had left when I arrived at the station."
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "It is most versatile verbal as it could be used as noun, adjectives, or adverbs.",
      "answers": [
        "Subject",
        "Gerund",
        "Progressive tense",
        "Infinitive"
      ],
      "correct": "Infinitive"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Which sentence has a wrong verb form?",
      "answers": [
        "The office staff notices that the crowd has not been dispersed when they arrived.",
        "Lilia have drove all night to get to the conference on time.",
        "Robert knew yesterday that you have not received your email.",
        "Marilyn was correct when she said she would fail the exam."
      ],
      "correct": "Lilia have drove all night to get to the conference on time."
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which is TRUE among the options below as you refer to the two given statements? He may leave tomorrow if he finishes his term paper. He will leave tomorrow if he finishes his term paper. (I. The sentence with may denotes permission or possibility. II. The sentence with will simply describes a future event. III. The two sentences convey the same meaning. IV. Action in sentences I is conditional as stressed by the word \"if\")",
      "answers": [
        "II and IV",
        "II, III and IV",
        "I and III",
        "I and II"
      ],
      "correct": "I and II"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "What lexical process is exemplified by the following? Get as to procure, to become, or to understand.",
      "answers": [
        "Compounding",
        "Conversion",
        "Polysemy",
        "Derivational Affixation"
      ],
      "correct": "Polysemy"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Mr. Cornejo gave the students examples of phrases and clauses that intervene between the subject and verb in a sentence. Which sentence below demonstrates a correct verb agreement regardless of the prepositional phrases that intervene between the subject and verb?",
      "answers": [
        "The group of students, as well as their teacher, were pleased with the exam results.",
        "In addition to the dogs, the cats are also included in the pet adoption program.",
        "The committee, consisting of ten members, has/have decided to postpone the meeting.",
        "The parents of the bride, along with her sisters, was/were busy preparing for the wedding."
      ],
      "correct": "The group of students, as well as their teacher, were pleased with the exam results."
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "A student wants to know why adjectives such as unique, possible, impossible, etc. cannot be compared in degree, unlike other gradable adjectives. Which of the following is the most appropriate response to the student's question?",
      "answers": [
        "Comparatives and superlatives apply to absolutes such as unique, possible, impossible.",
        "These adjectives are ungradable and cannot be used in the comparative or superlative forms.",
        "The degree of uniqueness, possibility, or impossibility can be determined based on context.",
        "These adjectives can be compared using comparative forms only."
      ],
      "correct": "These adjectives are ungradable and cannot be used in the comparative or superlative forms."
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "Teacher Marites reminded the students to identify the subject and verb agreement in a sentence. Which sentence below demonstrates a correct verb agreement between the subject 'number' and the verb?",
      "answers": [
        "The number of people attending the concert were more than expected.",
        "A number of attendees was not happy with the performance.",
        "The number of books in the library is decreasing.",
        "A number of students are passing the exam with flying colors."
      ],
      "correct": "The number of books in the library is decreasing."
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Mrs. Ampon is discussing tense-aspect combinations with her class, and she needs to give an example of the present perfect tense. Which of the following sentences is an example of the present perfect tense?",
      "answers": [
        "I ate sushi for lunch.",
        "She will sing at the concert tomorrow.",
        "They are running a marathon this weekend.",
        "Employees have gathered information."
      ],
      "correct": "Employees have gathered information."
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "The following are linguistic mechanisms that Halliday and Hassan (1976) point in order for texts to have cohesion except:",
      "answers": [
        "Reference",
        "Ellipsis",
        "Substitution",
        "Genre"
      ],
      "correct": "Genre"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "Enrique wants to know when to use adverbs of frequency in a sentence. Which of the following is the most appropriate response to the student's question?",
      "answers": [
        "Adverbs of frequency can be placed anywhere in the sentence.",
        "Adverbs of frequency should be placed before the main verb of a sentence.",
        "Adverbs of frequency should be placed at the beginning or end of a sentence.",
        "Adverbs of frequency should be placed after the object of the sentence."
      ],
      "correct": "Adverbs of frequency should be placed before the main verb of a sentence."
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "Marisol wants to know how to teach the order of adjectives in a noun group to her students. Which of the following is the most appropriate response to the teacher's question?",
      "answers": [
        "Adjectives can be placed in any order in a noun group, depending on personal preference.",
        "Adjectives in a noun group must be placed in a specific order: determiner, opinion, size, shape, condition, age, color, origin, and noun.",
        "The order of adjectives in a noun group is not important in English.",
        "The order of adjectives in a noun group depends on the length of the adjectives used."
      ],
      "correct": "Adjectives in a noun group must be placed in a specific order: determiner, opinion, size, shape, condition, age, color, origin, and noun."
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "A teacher assigned a writing task to her students and provided them with a rubric that includes the criteria for evaluation. One of the criteria states that \"Writing should be free from subject verb agreement errors\". One of the students submitted a paragraph that contains the following sentence: \"Neither of my siblings is interested in English, but I was inspired by the books that I read.\" Which of the following statements is true regarding the subject-verb agreement in the sentence above?",
      "answers": [
        "The subject-verb agreement is incorrect because \"neither\" is singular and \"siblings\" is plural.",
        "The subject-verb agreement is incorrect because \"books\" is plural and \"was\" is singular.",
        "The subject-verb agreement is correct.",
        "The subject-verb agreement is incorrect because \"my\" is singular and \"siblings\" is plural."
      ],
      "correct": "The subject-verb agreement is incorrect because \"neither\" is singular and \"siblings\" is plural."
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "Which of the following can be a function of gerunds? (I. Subject of the verb II. Object of a verb III. Object of a preposition IV. Subject complement)",
      "answers": [
        "I and II",
        "I, II, and III",
        "I, II, and IV",
        "I, II, III, and IV"
      ],
      "correct": "I, II, III, and IV"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences contains an infinitive that functions as an adjective?",
      "answers": [
        "To dream requires incredible courage.",
        "The teacher assigned several exercises to complete.",
        "To do well in college, one must study diligently.",
        "We tell stories to teach lessons."
      ],
      "correct": "The teacher assigned several exercises to complete."
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "Which of the following are the characteristics of a finite verb? (I. Finite verbs agree with their subjects in person and number. II. They carry tense information, telling us whether the action occurs in the past, present, or future. III. Finite verbs can function as the main verb in the predicate of a sentence. IV. Finite verbs include infinitives, gerunds, and participles. V. Finite verbs can be combined with auxiliaries and modals.)",
      "answers": [
        "I, II, III, and IV",
        "I, II, III, and V",
        "I, III, IV, and V",
        "I, II, III, IV, and V"
      ],
      "correct": "I, II, III, and V"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "It refers to a type of mood that expresses a wish, obligation, possibility, or suggestion. Usually, it describes a hypothetical situation that has not yet occurred and is not certain to occur. For example, \"If I were rich, I would travel the world.\"",
      "answers": [
        "Indicative",
        "Subjunctive",
        "Imperative",
        "Interrogative"
      ],
      "correct": "Subjunctive"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "Which of the following sentences shows an error in subject-verb agreement?",
      "answers": [
        "Measles is contagious.",
        "The committee works hard even on holidays.",
        "One hundred pesos are hard to earn in one day.",
        "My pajamas are still wet."
      ],
      "correct": "One hundred pesos are hard to earn in one day."
    }
  ],
  "LITERARY CRITICISM": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "What analysis method would be best suited to investigating the depiction of gender roles and power relations in Charlotte Bronte's work \"Jane Eyre\"?",
      "answers": [
        "Psychoanalysis",
        "Marxism",
        "Feminism",
        "Formalism"
      ],
      "correct": "Feminism"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Which historical approach places the text as parallel to the relevant experiences of the author when the text was written?",
      "answers": [
        "Sociological criticism",
        "Biographical criticism",
        "Psychological criticism",
        "New Criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Biographical criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Which is known as the science of interpretation?",
      "answers": [
        "Hermeneutics",
        "Textual exegesis",
        "Literary Appreciation",
        "Literary criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Hermeneutics"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which literary movement in the 19th century celebrated imagination, nature, and emotion, with poets like William Wordsworth and Samuel Taylor Coleridge as key figures?",
      "answers": [
        "Romanticism",
        "Realism",
        "Classicism",
        "Naturalism"
      ],
      "correct": "Romanticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Which of the following is the sole concern of a New Critic?",
      "answers": [
        "the work itself",
        "the reader's response",
        "the author's life",
        "the archetypes in the text"
      ],
      "correct": "the work itself"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Which of the following approaches shows that there is a dynamic interaction between the text and the reader?",
      "answers": [
        "Gender criticism",
        "Reader-response criticism",
        "Psychological criticism",
        "Biographical criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Reader-response criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "What did Renaissance criticism grow directly from?",
      "answers": [
        "The recovery of classic texts",
        "The invention of the printing press",
        "The exploration of new lands",
        "The rise of humanism"
      ],
      "correct": "The recovery of classic texts"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "These are motifs and images found among many different myths of people widely separated in time and place but tend to have common meaning or elicit comparable responses.",
      "answers": [
        "symbolism",
        "figurative language",
        "imagery",
        "archetypes"
      ],
      "correct": "archetypes"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "The fact that Young Goodman Brown \"changed\" from being a faithful and loving husband to a skeptic, gruesome, and lonesome being betrays everything he once stood for. Adopting a formalist standpoint, this shows that he is a _____ .",
      "answers": [
        "Dynamic character",
        "Flat character",
        "Static character",
        "Round character"
      ],
      "correct": "Dynamic character"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "For Psychoanalytic critics, dreams are powerful catalysts for great ideas. Among the following, this is illustrated by ______ .",
      "answers": [
        "John Milton",
        "Nathaniel Hawthorne",
        "Robert Browning",
        "Edgar Allan Poe"
      ],
      "correct": "Edgar Allan Poe"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Formalism and Structuralism are literary theories that both lead to:",
      "answers": [
        "a subjective textual interpretation",
        "a scientific textual interpretation",
        "an artistic textual interpretation",
        "an intertextual interpretation"
      ],
      "correct": "a scientific textual interpretation"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Which historical approach places the text as parallel to the relevant experiences of the author when the text was written?",
      "answers": [
        "Sociological criticism",
        "Biographical criticism",
        "Psychological criticism",
        "New Criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Biographical criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "In analyzing poetry, one must first understand context. Which among the following is NOT included in a poem's context?",
      "answers": [
        "Does the poem belong to a particular period or literary movement? Does the poem relate to imagism, confessional verse, beat movement, the Harlem Renaissance, the Civil Rights Era etc.?",
        "How long is the poem? The longer the poem is, the more focus is demanded of the readers.",
        "Who wrote the poem? Does the poet's life suggest any special point of view, such as political affiliation, religious sect, career interest, musical talent, family or personal problems, travel etc.?",
        "When was the poem written and in what country? Such information will help readers understand what's in a poem and why?"
      ],
      "correct": "How long is the poem? The longer the poem is, the more focus is demanded of the readers."
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which term is borrowed from art criticism and applied to a kind of fiction that mixes realism with flights of myths and fantasy? It is associated with Latin American writers such as Gabriel Garcia Marquez.",
      "answers": [
        "metaphor",
        "masque",
        "magical realism",
        "adonitology"
      ],
      "correct": "magical realism"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Which of the following does not allow intertextual reading of literature?",
      "answers": [
        "Marxism criticism",
        "Postcolonial Criticism",
        "New criticism",
        "Feminism Criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "New criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "How can the new criticism school in poetry be characterized?",
      "answers": [
        "Intellectual and metaphysical",
        "Sentimental and didactic",
        "Impressionistic and symbolical",
        "Emphasis on craft over content"
      ],
      "correct": "Emphasis on craft over content"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Which characterized hermeneutics during the middle ages?",
      "answers": [
        "Meaning became terribly difficult in literature",
        "Interpretation became significantly important in the field of religion",
        "Invention of literary forms gave rise to the science of interpretation in secular texts",
        "Philosophical ideas were so abstract that people had to check the science of interpretation"
      ],
      "correct": "Interpretation became significantly important in the field of religion"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "What is the primary focus of Reader-Response Criticism in literary analysis?",
      "answers": [
        "Analyzing the historical context of a text",
        "Investigating the author's biography",
        "Examining readers' interpretations and reactions",
        "Deconstructing the language in a text"
      ],
      "correct": "Examining readers' interpretations and reactions"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Leroy is using Psychoanalytic literary criticism to analyze a poem. What would be a key focus of his analysis?",
      "answers": [
        "The poet's use of rhyme and meter",
        "The historical events that inspired the poem",
        "The unconscious desires and anxieties expressed in the poem",
        "The cultural and societal norms challenged by the poem"
      ],
      "correct": "The unconscious desires and anxieties expressed in the poem"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "What literary theory or approach is shown in the following passage?",
      "answers": [
        "Feminist Criticism",
        "Psychoanalytic Theory",
        "Reader-Response Criticism",
        "Romantic Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Feminist Criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Which of the following aspects of a nineteenth-century novel would most likely be examined in a work of feminist literary criticism?",
      "answers": [
        "the tone of the female omniscient narrator",
        "the dialogue spoken by male and female characters",
        "the descriptions of objects used for domestic chores",
        "the nonlinear structure of the plot"
      ],
      "correct": "the dialogue spoken by male and female characters"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "According to the Greek writer, certain gods were originally great people venerated because of their benefactions to mankind. What philosophy in the study of myths, tells us this?",
      "answers": [
        "Romanticism",
        "Rationalism",
        "Euhemerism",
        "Structuralism"
      ],
      "correct": "Euhemerism"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Which emphasizes the hereditary psychological component of the characters and experimenting with the connections between human psychology and the external environment?",
      "answers": [
        "Realism",
        "Neoclassicism",
        "Naturalism",
        "Romanticism"
      ],
      "correct": "Naturalism"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which of the following does not allow intertextual reading of literature?",
      "answers": [
        "Marxism criticism",
        "Postcolonial criticism",
        "New criticism",
        "Feminism criticism"
      ],
      "correct": "New criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "What literary theory or approach is shown in the following passage? Not only James's governess fit the classic profile of the female sexual hysteric, she also experiences the \"hysterical fit\" observed by turn-of-the-century clinicians. That her first hallucination precipitates a \"nervous explosion\" of some intensity is clear from her own account.Like that of the classic hysteric, her \"mental activity...is split up, and only a part of it is conscious.\" Her initial fantasy of her handsome employer is conscious, but his transformation into a figure embodying her fear of sexuality is generated by deep-rooted unconscious inhibitions.",
      "answers": [
        "Marxist Literary theory",
        "Psychoanalytic Theory",
        "Postmodern Literary Theory",
        "Deconstruction"
      ],
      "correct": "Psychoanalytic Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "What literary theory or approach is shown in the following passage? What is even more troublesome is disagreement among critics about just what standards are to be applied. Two \"straight\" readers, seeing the ghosts as real and the story as an attempt to \"turn the screws\" of horror as thrillingly as possible, might flatly disagree with each other about whether the literary experience of thrilling horror is good or bad for \"us,\" or for a given immature reader, or for a former governess now incarcerated in a mental institution. Because of all this variety, we have to ask our questions as if we were dealing not with one TheTurn of the Screw but many different ones. What is even more troublesome is disagreement among critics about just what standards are to be applied. Two \"straight\" readers, seeing the ghosts as real and the story as an attempt to \"turn the screws\" of horror as thrillingly as possible, might flatly disagree with each other about whetherthe literary experience of thrilling horror is good or bad for \"us,\" or for a given immature reader, or for a former governess now incarcerated in a mental institution. Because of all this variety, we have to ask our questions as if we were dealing not with one TheTurn of the Screw but many different ones.",
      "answers": [
        "Deconstruction",
        "Psychoanalytic Theory",
        "Reader-Response Criticism",
        "Marxist Literary Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Reader-Response Criticism"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "Which of the following methods of analyzing a literary work would be most appropriate to use with a psychoanalytic approach to literary criticism?",
      "answers": [
        "comparing the author's treatment of a theme with that of the author's contemporaries",
        "identifying and classifying syntactic patterns employed in the work",
        "interpreting symbolic representations of emotional repression in the work",
        "examining the work for evidence of the author's creative process"
      ],
      "correct": "interpreting symbolic representations of emotional repression in the work"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "This theory or approach involves analysis of nationality, ethnicity, and politics.",
      "answers": [
        "Postcolonial Literary Theory",
        "Marxist Literary Theory",
        "New Historicism",
        "Deconstruction Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Postcolonial Literary Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Using the feminist perspective in Alice Walker's Beauty: When the Other Dancer is the Self, the critic will consider the ________ .",
      "answers": [
        "the time when the story was written",
        "who the other dancer is",
        "the author's perception of 'beauty' and the world she lives in",
        "the figure of speech used in the title."
      ],
      "correct": "the author's perception of 'beauty' and the world she lives in"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "Not only James's governess fit the classic profile of the female sexual hysteric, she also experiences the \"hysterical fit\" observed by turn-of-the-century clinicians. That her first hallucination precipitates a \"nervous explosion\" of some intensity is clear from her own account. Like that of the classic hysteric, her \"mental activity...is split up, and only a part of it is conscious.\" Her initial fantasy of her handsome employer is conscious, but his transformation into a figure embodying her fear of sexuality is generated by deep-rooted unconscious inhibitions.What literary theory or approach is shown in the passage above?",
      "answers": [
        "Marxist Literary Theory",
        "Postmodern Literary Theory",
        "Psychoanalytical Theory",
        "Deconstruction Theory"
      ],
      "correct": "Psychoanalytical Theory"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "Which of the following methods of analyzing a literary work would be most appropriate to use with a psychoanalytic approach to literary criticism?",
      "answers": [
        "comparing the author's treatment of a theme with that of the author's contemporaries",
        "identifying and classifying syntactic patterns employed in the work",
        "interpreting symbolic representations of emotional repression in the work",
        "examining the work for evidence of the author's creative process"
      ],
      "correct": "interpreting symbolic representations of emotional repression in the work"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "Which of the following aspects of a nineteenth-century novel would most likely be examined in a work of feminist literary criticism?",
      "answers": [
        "the tone of the female omniscient narrator",
        "the dialogue spoken by male and female characters",
        "the descriptions of objects used for domestic chores",
        "the nonlinear structure of the plot"
      ],
      "correct": "the dialogue spoken by male and female characters"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "The father of dramatic criticism is _____ .",
      "answers": [
        "Sophocles",
        "Plato",
        "Socrates",
        "Aristotle"
      ],
      "correct": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "These are motifs and images found among many different myths of people widely separated in time and place but tend to have common meaning or elicit comparable responses.",
      "answers": [
        "symbolism",
        "figurative language",
        "imagery",
        "archetypes"
      ],
      "correct": "archetypes"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "Mimetic criticism of literature can be approached through:",
      "answers": [
        "language",
        "rhyme",
        "meaning",
        "archetypes"
      ],
      "correct": "meaning"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "Give the archetypal meaning of the image serpent.",
      "answers": [
        "luck",
        "nihilism",
        "evil",
        "danger"
      ],
      "correct": "evil"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "Expressive theory analyzes a literary piece by looking into",
      "answers": [
        "relationship between author and work",
        "the author and his creativity",
        "the text and inner expression",
        "the text and his audience"
      ],
      "correct": "relationship between author and work"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "A psychologist who has influenced the interpretation of certain images in literary works as an expression of the authors sexuality.",
      "answers": [
        "Skinner",
        "Freud",
        "Mackery",
        "Lucack"
      ],
      "correct": "Freud"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "A theory of criticism which sees a literary work in relation to other works.",
      "answers": [
        "archetypal",
        "intertextuality",
        "objective correlative",
        "formalistic"
      ],
      "correct": "intertextuality"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "A critical theory which believes that there is no elusive right interpretation of a text.",
      "answers": [
        "objective",
        "affective",
        "expressive",
        "mimetic"
      ],
      "correct": "objective"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "This movement initiated by Andre Breton adheres to the imagination, dreams, the fantastic and the irrational.",
      "answers": [
        "Impressionism",
        "Surrealism",
        "Postcolonialism",
        "Magical Realism"
      ],
      "correct": "Surrealism"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "A writer of the Greek classics who regarded poetry as a means to give instruction.",
      "answers": [
        "Virgil",
        "Homer",
        "Hesiod",
        "Horace"
      ],
      "correct": "Hesiod"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "One of the Greeks earliest epic writer who claimed that the function of poetry is for pleasure.",
      "answers": [
        "Virgil",
        "Homer",
        "Hesiod",
        "Horace"
      ],
      "correct": "Homer"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "The Greek who introduced satire as literary genre.",
      "answers": [
        "Aristophanes",
        "Euripides",
        "Archilochus",
        "Aeschylus"
      ],
      "correct": "Aristophanes"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "The literary judgments of Plato are published in a work entitled",
      "answers": [
        "Poetics",
        "The Republic",
        "Ars Poetica",
        "Poesie"
      ],
      "correct": "The Republic"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "The author of \"Ars Poetica\".",
      "answers": [
        "Aristophanes",
        "Archilochus",
        "Euripides",
        "Horace"
      ],
      "correct": "Horace"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "One of Plato's mockery on poetry is that ___.",
      "answers": [
        "it is too sophisticated",
        "it is too simple",
        "it conceals reality",
        "it is an imitation of an imitation"
      ],
      "correct": "it is an imitation of an imitation"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "In analyzing poetry, one must first understand context. Which among the following is NOT included in a poem's context?",
      "answers": [
        "Does the poem belong to a particular period or literary movement?",
        "Does the poem relate to imagism, confessional verse, beat movement, the Harlem Renaissance, the Civil Rights Era etc.?",
        "How long is the poem? The longer the poem is, the more focus is demanded of the readers. affiliation, religious sect, career interest, musical talent, family or personal problems, travel etc.?",
        "When was the poem written and in what country? Such information will help readers understand what's in a poem and why?"
      ],
      "correct": "How long is the poem? The longer the poem is, the more focus is demanded of the readers. affiliation, religious sect, career interest, musical talent, family or personal problems, travel etc.?"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a process or principle of formalist criticism?",
      "answers": [
        "Meaning is the essence of literature",
        "Defamiliarization crates the literary experience",
        "The dominant quality and literary device shape the nature and form of literature",
        "Close reading and non-intertextual interpretation are approaches in the literary texts"
      ],
      "correct": "Meaning is the essence of literature"
    }
  ]
};